Mars pictures
WY produced
timeline&proofreading:
Zcc911@any Douban
Hello
Please sign to my niece m Lotus
She adores you, I also is
Your novel touched me.
Your words are so sincere
Thank you for everything you do
Thank you
Hello - Hello
To see you so excited, I love your
book
Please sign to my daughter.
What's her name
Ruth Ding
Is to give her birthday gift, she's
37 years old.
I dare say she will like
The book is too great.
Thank you
Hello - want to sign to who?
Please sign to my mother
To help her birthday
She's big book fans.
She called? - Natalie
She was at home opening and closing
the mouth are you
Crazy
Thank you - thank you very much
Please sign to Jenna
I'm in and out of the hospital
several times
Your book gives me tremendous hope
Although my body is not good,
though...
I make them subject to a lot of pain
Perhaps someday, the kids will love me
Thank you - thank you.
To the end here.
End? Didn't notice the shouting stop?
- The end of the bar
Guys, sorry, the book signing
concluded.
From 8 a.m. she had been in this
To, and then sign a book.
To me this big book fan
Crowds will gather, I'm afraid also
have to sign
Quietly sign, no one will see
Then sign a copy of my will collapse
Really
Really disappointed that I can from
afar
I have to go? I'm tired.
The exposed surface can go.
But I'm tired - very soon.
All for you Oh, I'm not going to be a
long time
Okay, they are here to see you.
Who?
Large booksellers, the international
press...
Karina
I'll be 5 minutes
Delphine...
Thank you, Europe Carrie Ann
You're already here! - Karina
Not.
Hello
Hello - Hello?
De Wigan, so glad to see you again.
Don't you remember me? - Huh?
Brown multi Fellini, your Italian
Publisher
Thanks for letting me publishing this
book, a giant!
Thrilling you!
See I'm all cried out
But I think the sales results will
not make us cry
I would like to ask you...
Just I'm sorry.
I don't blame you
This book is for me very difficult
I know
Glad to meet you
I really appreciate your work
Sometimes I have a
You are special to me and writing feel
Like you see my thoughts
You have the book?
Of course there are
To sign to who?
Ella - she
Yeah, like the market name, My name
is Ella
Thank you
Would you like a Cup of vodka?
Why not?
I want to know how you work
You are writing notes or recording?
Write notes
I have several Notebook
Ready to take on the body
've been with?
Yeah, so I'm more at ease
I can look at?
See?
Don't worry, I won't steal the turn
A total of 4 present
1 of the present recording...is
writing the book
2 This is used to...remember the
title, ideas
This is it, write more intimate things
Now you are probably not easy?
Achievements, reviews, family reaction
Like a sudden lay of the spotlight
I think you almost can't go on.
Can't go?
A bit of an exaggeration.
However, you occasionally will feel
very alone.
Feed - ready?
No, like I've been hollowed out.
The country can make you a good rest
Banquet?
You didn't come to the
You over there?
I spoke to sue Miller co-chaired the
Europe hereby will meet
After the meeting there is a queue,
do not go open
Later find the opportunity to first
slip.
I met a woman, very interesting
Ah, change for a woman interested?
Don't be ridiculous.
We talked all night, great
Her ability to listen first class
Listen attentively
Willing to listen to not many people.
What's her name?
Ella
Yeah, is she, what's her name?
I tell you La, El Le
Her name is Ella on? - The
Just like the vegetable market in the
name
Excuse me
How is it, Raymond
I saw your car
You want some coffee?
No thanks...just take two bottles of
cider over
Really
You really are too kind!
Awesome
I bought a Delphine wrote the book
If you can please her signature.
Sorry, I should sent a present to you
Take
A few years ago...
My wife also spent a period of hard
times
She is also fed into
It's a bit like talking about her
story
She didn't commit suicide?
No, thankfully
Now she is completely well
Thank you
Then...leave.
Not much to be?
Not
Wish smoothly - Thank you.
Now the kids are gone...
I want them
Of course you will want them, but...
More unencumbered.
More unencumbered to come here?
To, is also.
But I mean the writing, a few months.
What you even read didn't do, the
light"gathering information"
Is the start of work, isn't it?
The collection of information does
not work?
I know you
How much of this will take some time
But this time you have been hesitant
not before
This is a big challenge, a new
adventure
Those roles, I have to tell them to
get along...
I don't know...maybe two years
This is normal
What is normal?
Is the thinking, questioning.
I really want to write? They really
so funny?
In the unlikely event I'm wrong?
This kind of thing, you know?
Do you think that you're mistaken?
Not, not so
I'm ready
Also very happy to be once again
buried the first work
"You think just say it's a novel."
"Then change a few names will be able
to get away with it"
"You can continue to live your
apathetic day?"
"Too late."
"You betrayed your mother earn a lot
of money"
"The home idea show, the reward is
very high."
"Purse full Oh"
"To continue to make big money."
Hello - Hello, I'm Ella
Such a hit to some venture
I don't know if the so fast to call
you
I gave you my phone number?
Yes, but you maybe just out of
courtesy
You have...out for a Cup of coffee?
Yeah, why not?
Sorry, you must have better things to
do
On the contrary, I am glad that you
about me
Hello - Hello
Stil, a glass of white wine for?
Yes, Thank you.
That day both I in speaking, didn't
talk to you
I have nothing to say.
I'm interested in
But don't want to say it doesn't
matter
Thank you
I help others to write autobiography
Write someone else's life in exchange
for remuneration
Actress, female politicians...
Is written by you, the author, but
hang their name
I belong to the circle of unseen kind
of person
Stars beneath the shadow of the
So you pick the...customer.
You refers to my patients.
Well, now your patient is who?
A TV presenter
Summer in her home, recorded 30 hours
of interviews
Now trying to write a book
You've never thought about writing
yourself?
Yourself?
Of your own life.
My life nothing to say
My husband has long since passed
away, left me alone
Also no children
Is you choose not to?
Anyway, I also don't feel sorry
We do not live together, each have
their own life
Between us is like that
I probably scared rigid, a compromise.
Afraid of people in love live
together for a few years after
Into the kind of relationship
Everyone for your comments kind of
relationship?
You meat search me?
Without the meat of the search, we
all know
We all know that? - Yes
Know you with a bit of TV Arts
reporter rapport
He invited you on the program is
batch miserably
What, am I not allowed on his show?
Not, but would provoke jealousy, it's
normal.
How is this considered normal
A lot of writers want to get invited
Even I was also
Damn, I forgot...I gotta go.
I talked to Editors about
Checkout, Thank you - good
You about where?
The 6th district
I just happened to stop by, and go
together.
Your children have left home, right?
The
They leave me.
Son admitted to the Belgian Academy
of Arts
Daughter wanted to test the National
Civil Aviation school
Now in Lyon, a star of pre-school
Your daughter wanted to be a pilot?
Not
I at this station
Prayer
Damn, my notebook
Hello?
Of course I'm at home
Can you see me?
Really?
But where are you?
I didn't see you.
Incredible
When?
Saturday
I see I have no available
Anyway, Thank you
Good night - good night
Hello beautiful
I was the first one to?
I thought I was late.
No
By the way, Happy Birthday
I said what all don't take, don't the
gifts and flowers
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Forgive you.
I'll talk to the other open together
I can't believe
It took you two days to get these?
Really outrageous
Are you a family man?
He wanted me to think so, but I don't
know.
You should have vaguely thought about
who or suspect who?
No
Maybe this is your theme:"follow-up"
What follow-up do?
You on a book"follow-up"
The book revealed the story of the
subsequent development
For several months I'm all in favor
of a present
Completely fictional novel
Delphine...
Completely fictional novel, really?
Now, you have gone beyond these.
You should accept the reality.
They won't come, we two people to eat.
Wait a little longer - no.
Call and ask
No, hit is white hit
You exactly say to them?
No, my annual Unified e-mail
notification
They followed in previous years did
not come
The minimum to split a gift.
Glad you came
You don't know this about me more
meaningful
Since my husband died.
His friends will no longer bother me.
Every year I invite, but they never
did.
You know the reason?
I don't want to say, I'm not ready
Someday, I will tell you
This is my new book content summary
Look at
Also no one saw, I would like to hear
your thoughts
My God, a sea of people
De·Wigan lady, you can come really
good.
Thank you for inviting us - Hello
To, I have a surprise for you
Book on the photo is very small, and
no plus box
She deserve to have a life-size
portrait of
And is the body like
Sorry, I have to go and say Hello.
I'll be right back.
Hello
Here we go.
You don't mean Karina?
No, I have to go.
Hey - it's me
I Wake you up?
There is a little
I'm sorry it's so early to call fight
you
I run into a big problem.
You have Voice Recorder?
There, there is a
I now can past get? Urgent
Got to go, need to teach you?
No, I have the same recorder
Early in the morning can look so
perfect
What do you do? I just can't.
No, all women do
I don't think
How do you see with what others see
are two different things
Today what?
Coffee Olay and jam bread, please.
Thank you, believe me, I carefully
read the
It's just a background description,
character not stereotypes
Good
But the story outline with the
overall architecture of the forming
In short, some things need...
I was like - huh?
Really! - Thank you, this helps me a
lot
I think in my back into creation
before the
Will be successful
I really need an objective opinion -
you coffee
Thank you
Last night I talked to a man in a
hotel overnight
Early morning 5, 6, put on clothes
Take taxi home, to the downstairs.
Only to find forgot to take the key
Have a spare key?
There, but the maid 11 point only to
I talked to an official about a
morning at the Congress meet
I want to write her autobiography
Interesting?
Super exciting
Hey, just kidding
Get out of here, I want to smoke.
You know, Delphine
I have to honestly tell you
You might think
Some harsh...
I just lied to you.
I think your story is boring
Not bad, but just uninteresting
This story with you not the slightest
relationship
You're wrong, and shouldn't waste
time on this
Just because you don't dare to write
you the written
Of course...
If you get to edit the look, she
would say great.
They're not stupid.
Have to rely on you for them to make
money
Don't be fool, they only care about
this
Even if you lower the writing was
then rotten
They always have a way to get
thousands of readers to pay
I in the morning departure, you alone
I'm not too reassured
Are you sure you can?
I'm so much better
Ella helped me a lot busy
El?
Which aspect of it?
Can together to chat about work
Talk about important or relatively
private.
Sometimes I feel like she makes your
mind unstable
Not
Well
She is relatively persistent in some
ideas
Although I am not agree
But can always bring out the Spark
Let me get clear on their beliefs
You see
She bought a new notebook and send me
I still do not trust
You could have written?
Haven't
But soon.
When did you come back?
I go to Texas, see McKinsey
Then to Los Angeles to find Ellis.
There are di flute Weng
You are really lucky to be invited to
her, I love her work
Rest for a few days and then go to
New York to see Delhi lo
A total of...
Three weeks
And then it's gone?
Also Mike Ethan Wang, he's in London
They planned to let me continue to do
in the third quarter
But I rejected
I don't want to talk to you separate
too long
"Really heavy"
"As your loved ones, the crown with
the same last name"
"Today is particularly heavy"
"Are you for himself the surname of
Were you trippin"
"Yes, I'm the writer of the
relatives, I Bah"
"I heard that you get rid of your
kids."
"Smart"
"In front of the obstacles are in
addition to, right?"
"I know you're not a good mother."
Hey - I just got another e
Another seal?
Anonymous letter
Here again? Poor you!
You on Facebook? - Facebook for?
You don't see you on Facebook happen?
I can't book Ah, I don't know how on
This is very serious, to be with, I
immediately went to the
Well, I'm at home waiting for you
Facebook is going on? Maybe my page
But not my problem.
You didn't login, but there is one
with your name on the account
Who are in the above post
What is the password for?
louisepaul222, all lowercase
Why is 222 for?
I don't know, not my set
You a loved ones to leave a message
A day in the denigrate you
Take a look at this
"She's dangerous, and is destroying
everything the pervert."
"If you are like her family and
friends"
"Be sure to like her mom as being
locked up in the sanatorium"
Turn off it!
You are wrong, this is very serious
Anonymity is worse, on a social
networking site of the attack worse
Is?
Users more gullible defamatory, does
not consider the fact that
So the response is also useless
Your readers have for you defence.
Not all of it - not
And then they start to attack each
other
Take a look at this
"Why are you so vicious"
"Hate her to just go read someone
else's book!"
Another person a message
"All is shit, want to eat shit is her
home."
"In order to be on TV nothing to say
bitch."
"In order to be on the cover of a
magazine what are willing to do"
"Look at her take on that man"
"She only has eyes for money, family
can sell"
"Dare say, is literature"
Turn it off, please, don't say it
again.
I'm sorry, but...it's too much
I'm tired
I know
Don't worry
Let me handle it.
Eat it, you will feel relaxed many
What is this?
Anti-anxiety medicine
0.5 mg ingot
Thank you
Night and then eat a
Okay?
Call
Sleep?
With yesterday the same, very secure
The middle of the night 4 point Wake
Up very disturbed
Couldn't sleep
There and then eat a pill?
I swallowed two
8 point and a half to 9 points and
barely slept for half an hour
louisepaul222, right?
How often do you confiscate the
letter?
Well
From the reply begin
Uh...
For all of the planned solicitation,
a column about the draft
And manuscript review
I'll just say you're busy with the
new book creation
On offer you to feel pleasure
But at the moment you need to
concentrate on
This answer can also?
And then to sentence polite rhetoric,
like...
"Please keep in touch, the next time
you absolutely duty-bound"
What is this? Durga city High School?
You promised next week to the past?
They have 3 classes selected My Book
to do the report
Then?
I promised to go to lectures, talking
to writers stand
Speeches for?
I made a note...remember a few points
Remember a few key points...a 3 Letter
From the school librarians, serious
if the
She said:"the students are glad you
can be evacuated to"
"Can I send you take of the train
schedule"
"As stated in my previous letter, I
need it"
"To schedule the student's time and
book the venue"
Later, she began to hurry.
She said:"due to the delay did not
see your reply..."
"Remind you"
"Next Thursday there are 200 students
waiting"
"Listen to your speech the writing
stand to talk of"
"Thank you, they are poring over your
work"
Really hate this woman
I don't know...this is how back with
it, Delphine in?
Got a reply
I will go
Are you sure?
I have no choice
Your coffee
I find you as Durga city High School
notes
In fact, by the time you throw in the
trash.
Really?
No head no tail, I completely
rewritten.
Do you want to see it?
Also the line?
Anything
You saved me
Can help on the busy, I'm happy
If we can let you focus on the
important things just fine
You know I have troubles
In fact...
I rented the apartment
The landlord of the original
overseas, but suddenly coming back.
I have to move out
Can I live your home a week or two?
Until I find a new house
I want to say child's room empty...
Of course you can
These you all need?
No, but I can't find a place to put
There is also documentation
No, Don't move too heavy.
An Elevator would be nice
We asked, but the real estate
business is not Ken built
You can use these shelves, a closet,
also empty.
I come back later to pack
Hello, the cultural radio station for
an interview
Please on the 5 floor
Who is it? - Cultural Radio
journalists
You have to accept the interview, but
didn't tell me
I don't have anything to say to you?
You want to talk about what topic
My first book
On working hard
You also didn't talk about enough?
Hello - Hello, Thank you for
accepting the interview
Where, welcome
Damian, recording engineer - Hello
Jacket to me
Thank you
I can open the window?
Received a bit of city noise
Of course you can - will feel lively
some of the
You know the program of gist
Back view you a a novel
See how it affects now
Do you remember Emmanuel at first
glance now of the moment?
I remember very clearly
I'm on the D-line Express.
The weather was bad, raining
I'm on my way to work
At the time the work is very dull
Through the novel to portray the
workplace of the world
There are so easy?
The beginning theme is not in the
workplace
But city of Solitude
I think from day to day the angle cut
into the person's life
Broken, lonely life
There is nothing climax
Your work why is it dull?
I'm in the company responsible for
social PR
To understand social relationships
To exclude communication barriers and
conflict situations, to find solutions
I think you probably don't want to
hear anymore.
Thank you please let
The program Book Number 21 broadcast
I will send SMS to inform you
Thank you, goodbye - Thank you,
goodbye
Bye - bye
How?
You make new friends?
To engage in such a out know where
you go
"So you want to return to the fiction
of the embrace?"
Fuck her what's the matter?
She has what qualifications?
Are you serious?
You're jealous?
Sorry, to see you for this waste of
time I was angry
This woman will make you sink
Only I know you, know you can write
what
Only you?
Can't you see I'm scared to death
Have come to a dead end?
Don't say that was a good book,
listen to I'm sick of it
Said a non-stop, but even a shadow not
What contraindications, treasure,
ban, all did not
Nothing, that's all.
Look at me, I'm empty, can penetrate
the
This machine have ways of making you
talk
Dear Paul, what is it?
Don't you love mom anymore?
Occasionally call me, I miss you
There are sister links, then, called
her to also contact me
Love you
Take care of yourself, you know?
Mom?
Yes, mom.
Just remind your mom also in
Okay...
Before you call every day
I'm in school, mom.
I'm so excited
Just completed first solo flight
A single fly? What's that?
Is the instructor first to let go
Make your flying alone
At his command?
No, he's not on the plane
I am a man
This is what I've done the best thing.
You can't imagine, I'll tell you
Well...later then tell me
Then the next time you chat.
Love you
Back?
You have to go?
Yeah, I'm already late.
But still there is progress, then the
big mess
When did you start not moving the pen?
Don't know, but that's it.
Don't worry, we'll face it together.
But your offer also so many
Works translated around the world
I told everyone you are not in Paris
You didn't say I can't write?
No, can't let people know your status
"The first is to betray your mother."
"And then hooked up with the literary
program presenter promotions"
"Congratulations, admire"
"He dumped you, it can be expected a
present"
"You're the best at 淫书 to be
published."
"You hurt the people around you"
"Caused great damage"
"You know why?"
"Because people believe in the
printed text"
Must be on your rancor long-awaited
people
Your book Release This anger
This letter was recently received?
The
"People believe the printed word"
They are right
Why they're right?
"People"is who?
"People"might be wrong, might mess
want
Look around you
Each of the writers in the writing
community news events
Why is this?
Because that is the only reliable
source
You want to turn back to writing
fiction, there is only one reason
You refuse to write their own story
Don't take your sets to me.
Well, I apologize, but I insist to
say down
I reread the journal in the scholarly
world of that interview
Your Internet take a look at
Later I might write, but not now
I work with I went elsewhere
Go to where?
Take you away to where?
I see you're running in place
What Are you doing?
I heard you up
So?
If I make you uncomfortable, I can
leave immediately
Sorry
I shouldn't speak
Are you okay, Delphine is?
Okay
You should sleep, tomorrow to get up
early to go to Durga.
No, I can't.
I know the consequences very serious,
but I can't go
I have no strength
You let me on your behalf?
Are you kidding me?
Not
You want to pretend to be into me?
?
The network has more than two
thousand photo of me
Because of too many, each face are
not the same
Are you serious?
Very seriously
Etc.
To try this
I'm on the D-line Express.
The weather was bad, raining
I rush to work, when work is dull
I'm in the company responsible for
social and PR
To understand social relationships
To exclude communication barriers and
conflict situations, to find solutions
I think you probably don't want to
hear anymore.
Okay? I won't be too early to hit the
Not, okay
I woke up, just know a good news
What's the good news?
Al Roy for accepting our invitation
His French PR company also confirmed
Really happy for you.
What about you, okay?
I'm a little worried
Never got your message
I played two three times.
Also left a message for you
I'm okay.
Just?
Okay
I can understand your need to be
alone, work to be confidential
So certain things, you don't want to
tell me
But this time, you're a bit overdone
You push yourself to the danger.
Let me help you
Then come back
You know I can't.
We can't communicate, you tightly
closed your
We are not at War, I'm not your enemy
You know, sometimes
I can't help but to wonder if someone
took control of you
Delphine is?
Europe Carrie Ann
Are you okay?
I'm sorry, I'm just a little
attention has wandered just for
Well, I know
The hearts are placed in the
authoring on the
Do you live nearby? - No, I live in
Monte
We come here to the pediatric clinic
to see
I promised my daughter after watching
to sit on the carousel
Mom, you can go on the carousel? - Go
You go first, I'll be right over.
But can't sit alone Oh, the first
next to see
You look at me but obediently listen
to you.
Not visited, do not sign the book
Do not travel, activities all block
off
Thank you, but I...
Don't say, but I have done it
Received your letter, I will not
bother you.
Now I can't wait to read your new book
I'm sorry, what letter?
You send a letter to us before you
finish the new book before the
Don't bother you.
Ah! I'm sorry, I...
Indeed, this time I retreat to
concentrate on writing
I need to be alone, but...
Don't worry, I will soon be out off.
Well, I gotta go, come on.
How?
Super miserable
Is the librarian found out.
I went to the police station to
forgery offences sent to the Office
Is currently on bail waiting pass
Okay, I talk nonsense.
Everything is going well
They simply have no doubt
You see, we can swap identities
I at any time pending disposal
Even if there is someone you know in,
it will not goof
I can't wait to give it a try.
This is what you told me of a diary
You went through my stuff?
I didn't turn it in here
You record every thing, Super lucky
12-year-old started writing, has been
to the children born
15 years of memories, events
Character sketches... - and
adolescent gibberish
This is your memories
Note The not my best years
There are these, why are you looking
everywhere for footage
I'm not looking for material
You have to face is this fact
Don't say, I've had enough.
Don't want to shake me, no one cares
about this fact
Your readers care about
These things only made sense to me
There is no idea, say to listen to
the point is boring
Bad words will lead to anxiety
If the hard construction of the idea,
it would turn into a novel.
So what are you waiting for, start
writing.
Write what?
You just say those.
Please forgive me for yesterday's
behavior
I got a bad news
I had planned to get de Palma Dieu to
write autobiography
To?
With men I always feel uncomfortable
But de Palma Dieu is not the same, I
am very interested
Yeah, he has another for
Contract threatens to, he actually
found someone else.
A man, of course
Cooked duck so fly
I kind of betrayed feeling
However, I also not don't understand.
The so-called men of
understanding...this kind of stuff
Who is it?
Is the flange the cable watts
He can't come back soon.
He was next in the third quarter of
the program
Perhaps, you need this
Need?
Keep a little distance
You are very vulnerable
He is your boyfriend
But he was always invited to, praise
other writers
I'm not jealous.
In this regard does not
This man across the sea to visit
He thought than the French writers of
the more interesting writers
Am I wrong?
No, but it is not full so, I want
to...
I just want to say this can't help
you to get back confidence
It is honored that you actually for
me to make an exception
Don't be kidding, What Are you
talking about?
You sent the letter.
You meet European Lianne.
Really, I don't remember writing this
letter
I can not talk nonsense Oh
"Dear gentlemen."
"You know, I encountered a bottleneck"
"Can't concentrate on writing, so
this months"
"Please don't contact me, invite me"
"Write a book, I temporarily broke
off all contact"
"Thanks for understanding"
Is you wrote?
At that time, my mind some Chaos
Thank you
I began to worry.
My bubble tea, and bought Bourbon,
red wine
There are macarons to you
I have something important to tell you
I know you sent a letter to my friends
They please do not contact me
Yeah
I'm trying to help you, not distract
you
But don't you think you overdo it?
You should first ask me.
With me in yeah, this is not enough?
I can't believe you would do this.
You need quiet and solitude to write
that book.
Which book?
Your own story, you owe the public
this book
You better listen up
My writing is never to please who
Now more did not intend to do so
Whether you want to or don't want to
The reader love you, you're
responsible for them
This off you what happened?
What right Have you to meddle with it?
How dare you presume to help me
decide what to write
You think you are?
I'm in a nearby hotel booked a room
Luggage received well, a little later
someone will come and get
Don't do this.
Don't argue.
I see I make you very uncomfortable
I thought I could help you get back
self-confidence
I was wrong, sorry
Are you okay?
Hurts - don't move, don't move.
I'll be right back, don't move
Delphine is!
"Knee fractures"
Didn't white throw...
The situation may be even worse
When I saw you being carried away...
I really good afraid
To be so over the four weeks...
Impossible.
To flange cable watts family lived,
it would be more convenient
Others in a foreign country, I A
person can't go.
Wait a minute, take a break
I can't.
If you want, I'll go with you.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I also want to write something,
just
I have to go get some necessities
Clothes, toiletries...
To be, I got it.
Give me the keys.
See you can stand up, I'm really happy
Barely OK...
You buy something, I receive up, you
have to?
No, Thank you.
Say of is also, strawberries are
pressed rotten.
Have the need for help...
No, I'm fine, Thank you very much
You're welcome, come on - Thank you
This damn weather
My husband and I met that night, is
also such
Big traffic jam, I was stuck in the
car.
Suddenly someone knocked on my car
window
A handsome man, wearing a leather
jacket
I opened the door, he got into the
car.
He long?
Tall and rugged, a face of Hu slag
Manly
I immediately fell in love with him
the taste of
Mix the wet leather and tobacco taste
If it was me, there may be wariness
Sean a car, I would want him.
We parked in a cul-de-SAC on the edge
of the
Looking for a small hotel
Spend the passion of a night
You how old was it?
19-year-old
He is 28 years old
I know him, he is a mountain guide
He also climbed the K2 peak.
Just...
Had an accident...
Forced to give up everything
Later he did Express, bartender
Even wanted to open a antique shop,
just messing around.
It seems like everything understand.
We encounter
Quickly in my life made a place
So obvious, but I didn't see
Ella is My the write theme
She know, you talked to her?
Of course not, if let her know.
She would immediately close my mouth,
and closed with the clam as tight
Gotta make her automatically leaned
over
This...请君入瓮 the trick
Be sure to handle with care
Of course I will be very careful, it
is also used to say?
I think the photo of the real life
story
Her life was like a novel, I don't
like
First of all she was willing to open
Atrium
You said her mouth was tight
The
I'll let her speak as long as I'm
able.
I'll get back to you
You can buy a Cup of coffee for me? -
Good
There is also chocolate
Are you Delphine de·Wigan? - Yes, I
was
I'm Balzac high school librarian
Located in Durga city
Ah, Yes...
In order to invite you, we had by
letter
Yeah, I think of it, I've seen you
I think I have not the pleasure to
meet you
However, I go to school...
You also really dare say!
Don't you remember?
I don't remember what you had coming.
Because you didn't show up
Let me remind you, de Wigan Mrs.
You even the most basic courtesy are
not
No notification, not even a cry of
apology.
Please be assured that we never
encourage students
Read your masterpiece.
Wish you have a pleasant evening
She want to?
Nothing, just a book fan
We agreed to the Alps Chalet stay for
1 month
But he back out.
I insisted to go, I was wrong.
Your fault?
At the time he accepted the
treatment, I the down his
I'm very self-blame
No one that is someone else's life is
responsible for
Is?
I don't know.
One day a sudden storm
Wooden house for only you?
Only we
We are bored as hell, and can only be
read...
We have not had sex.
All day listen to the wind blow, the
head almost blow up
A day in the morning the wind
stopped, I go out breathable
Are you a man?
He didn't want to come out
I'm heading for the woods to go...then
I heard a gunshot
I look back to the Chalet to run...
Saw his body.
Skull burst
Blood everywhere.
Terrible!
It was a long time ago.
My mom died, I was alone...
Subsequently, the occurrence of fire
Really?
Yeah, the house burned, everything
burned.
Fortunately, I have a friend
My best friend, Kiki
Kiki is? You never told me about her
Oh, no?
You even said You have no friends
In fact...
Kiki is not a real person
Is my imaginary friend
Very pretty little girl, red hair.
I want to talk to her to run away
together, just the two of us
No one to bother us
What's the matter?
You get up to?
I didn't hear you get up
I'm up for a long time
Are you okay? - Okay
That I let you concentrate on work.
Get
Things such as what I think
She took the bait.
What does that mean?
She thinks I'm in Recalling their own
past
So remove the heart of Defense, to me
your heart.
Great!
I can't let her according to the time
order of speaking
So are intermittent small story
I have to think of a way to connect
The simplest method is recording, but
the risk is too high
I have to hang up.
Noon to eat what?
Don't know, whatever.
Tell you now a bit early, but...
I started as a new book intended to
outline the
Really?
Very intimate content
From a personal perspective to
re-examine their
You mean the autobiography?
Yes!
I can't say too much, the story of
architecture is also very weak
Similar to the confessions of the like
Now I can't boot
Or on paper to write notes, but
I can be recording, so slowly there
is progress
Talk to you before that the
follow-up? - Of course
Will be very painful
But you're right.
This is to face the time
I never told you
My mom also committed suicide.
I found her lying in the hallway on
the floor
Wearing my favorite yellow floral
dress.
I was 4 years old
I firmly against her.
So spent...several hours
Today is 2 months 7 days
I re-start writing
If necessary, loudly say.
Yesterday she finally remove the
heart of Defense
That a few pieces of the past
This is just a beginning
The point is, to win her trust
I know how to do
She created a fantasy friend, Kiki
She wants to talk to Kiki run away
together
Kiki tells her that they will have
new life
The house burned down, everything up
in smoke
Tall and rugged, a face full of Hu
residue, Manly
Wooden house only they
She found his body.
Skull burst, blood everywhere.
Can't you just wait?
Don't follow me around the turn
Or you'll break the other knee
(Ella)
Tell me, what the hell you're writing!
No, the confidentiality provisions of
provision than the contract length
I won't tell.
You might slip out.
Who is it?
Actress? Female politicians are?
The answer is not very close?
Female singer? Athletes?
Catherine Deneuve is? Kim Kardashian
for?
Los can be·Hever God is!
(Imaginary friends Kiki)
To close the window.
Rats
I'm telling you, the house has rats!
You see the mice?
I saw two only got into the cellar
Calm down, calm down, it's okay.
Sit down...alone.
We went to buy the rat trap to
destroy it
Don't worry, it's okay.
You can go off the cellar door?
I didn't have time to watch
Please help me to get crutches
The supermarket didn't sell, so I
went to town.
Rat trap, the exterminator, I have
bought
Be sure to fully wipe them out
The clerk was just...
Just what? He's not a sorcerer.
Just to give you go to put, I don't
go down
Just very sorry...
I'm really afraid of
I'm also not baipaoyitang the
supermarket, you see!
I can't see!
I generally love to eat plain, just
add a little lemon
But you get the sauce very successful
It's not difficult, is the most
common cooking method
I cook not out
Come again?
No, I'm good support
I already eat two disc a
I open a bottle of wine
Also good...
My dad he...
Every day can drink 3 bottles of
My mother passed away after me and
him had each other
I'm afraid of him, he has violent
tendencies
He...
My body hurt is his masterpiece
He locked me in the house
He died in that fire
I'm finally free.
How did things happen?
Is arson
Who put the fire?
Have not been found to
You have to wonder who?
I think is Kiki
I cooked a fish soup for dinner.
Soup? Fantastic
Didn't you say you love to drink soup?
Your body is hot, gotta think of a
way to bring the fever down
Hello?
No, I'm not Delphine, I'm her friend
Ella
We haven't met
Where you are from?
I can't hear you
From Wyoming it?
Delphine sleep, and food poisoning
No, not serious, etc. her up and then
call back
I re-start writing
If necessary, loudly say.
Yesterday she finally remove the
heart of Defense
That a few pieces of the past
This is just a beginning
The point is, to win her trust
I know how to do
She mentioned a fire
But unwilling to say more
But I will make her come clean
She also mentioned the suicide of the
Mother
I made you soup
I'm not hungry, my stomach
uncomfortable
So you should not an empty stomach.
I can't eat
Try again - please.
Come, come on
I beg you...please
Don't, don't
First aside
I'll eat again
I'm busy for half a day to get you
soup...
I soak a Cup of hot cocoa to you
I contact not on Francois
Never mind, something he would call
again.
Help me with the kids.
Has been notified
You should drink a little
You didn't eat
Come, obediently obedient
Barely drink a little
Don't cheat.
Drink!
! Drink!
Delphine is!
Delphine is! - ?
I'm Raymond -?
?
Here I am - Delphine is!
Hey, you guys, look here!
You scared me to death.
I don't understand, is because of me?
Because I always not around?
I jumped on the first plane.
You're lucky
Luckily someone found in a timely
manner you
Why do you want to die for?
I did not want to die.
Test report test out sleeping pills
mixed sulfate thallium
That was the rodenticide of the main
ingredients
You still no clue?
You should remember that you talk to
her by phone?
She for me to answer the phone, don't
you feel strange?
You have to believe me.
I didn't tell Ella spoken to - know.
Not just that night, no, never
Good
I don't call you, you're shut down
Off, you know?
So I'm calling Raymond
Raymond is?
Our neighbor, Raymond.
The Windows were tightly closed, he
knocks on the door and shake the
window
Ah, the original is Raymond?
Why don't you open the door?
Because Ella gave me Poison.
You don't believe me even if the
I believe you
Sorry to keep you waiting
Come in
Come in, sit down, please
I very like
Suspenseful and exciting
This is probably you have written the
best book.
Karina, this 3 years I didn't write
anything
I have not sent what document to you
But I really receive the presentation.
This is someone else to write, Ella
(Delphine de Wigan, the true
adaptation of)
(A present to make you shudder
endless novel)
(True story)
To see you so happy, really...
I was very touched
Your book every day I see, I love
The new book is really...
True...
To sign to who?
Me, myself, and Delphine...
We have the same name
Very much looking forward to your
next work
Hello, de Wigan Mrs.
Please sign to Ella
true adaptation
Director: Roman
Polanski
the
timeline&proofreading: Zcc911@any
Douban
Automatic Translation By:
www.elsubtitle.com
Visit Our Website For Free Translation