Just going to drop
her on the couch.
Okay. I'll pick her up tomorrow.
You're not driving home until
you have another cup of coffee.
Hey, don't worry about whispering.
She slept through everything.
Jet engines, turbulence,
bipolar flight attendants.
I hate her so much. I hate you!
No, I don't. I love you.
I resent her youth.
Coffee may not be the answer.
How long has it been
since you've slept?
Ah, Let's see, uh, I didn't
get any sleep at your parents',
both our flights were delayed,
somebody phoned in a bomb
threat to the Taco Bell Express,
they shut down the airport so...
Four hundred eighty-seven hours?
You need to lie down. Come on.
Okay.
Go away, balls.
No, no, no.
We don't sleep on pool tables
anymore. We're parents now.
Nothing fun or weird.
Your mother's a bitch.
Woah, woah!
Woah, where'd that come
from? I thought you liked her.
Never did. Your dad, on
the other hand, he's a flirt.
Has he ever flirted with you?
No, he only flirts with
people he likes. Come on.
Oh, my God. Oh, this is heaven.
What are you doing in heaven?
Part of an exchange program. Gandhi's
down there at a strip club with Mussolini.
Just sleep.
Mmm. Okay.
Hey, remember that time when I tried
to trick you into getting me pregnant
to save our marriage?
What? No!
Yeah. Sam was eight and I stopped
taking the pill and started sleeping naked.
You don't remember?
I remember the naked thing. I
didn't think you wanted a baby.
I thought you wanted a new car.
Mmm.
But it's all right. We have the
greatest kid ever and you're a good dad.
Good night.
Wait, wait. Before
you fall asleep,
the time we went to Vegas and
you told me that you got robbed.
Did that really happen?
No, I lost it all on
blackjack. Remember?
This is like a truth serum.
Is it hard for you to find another
guy because I set the bar too high?
No.
What do you know?
You're half asleep.
Nolan?
Nolan!
What?
What do you think about the fact
that Ed just called you a pussy?
I didn't hear that.
Ed? Pussy.
He's probably right.
Now, hold on. Before
everybody leaves,
I want to invite you all to take part in
something that I am very excited about.
Oh, I knew this day was coming.
It's either real estate or vitamins.
No, Ed. A few nights ago, I had
an experience that led me to believe
that we could advance the
frontiers of psychological study.
I'm talking about stripping
away your defenses to a point
where inhibitions come
down and truths come out.
So, what? We're all
going to get drunk?
No. I'm talking about
sleep deprivation therapy.
Can I be drunk for that?
No. Because sometimes
when people get drunk,
they grab a gun and shoot
their boyfriends in the testicles.
You're talking about
me, aren't you?
I thought that was
abundantly clear.
Now, I've done a lot
of research on this.
I think if we stay up long enough, we
can get to a whole new level of honesty.
That's the way my old
associate in Nam used to do it.
You ought to bring
Pho Than Kwon in here.
That old boy kept me awake 70
hours straight at the Hanoi Hilton,
getting intel out of me.
Seriously, you can get him. He's got a
noodle shop down at the Music Center.
He gives me 10% off
because he tortured me.
A real sweetheart.
It's your mistake for
staying at a Hilton.
I want you all here on Friday
for a weekend workshop.
Some of us might have
plans this weekend.
And what were
you planning to do?
Call my friends and ask them why they
never invite me anywhere on the weekends.
I guess I could reschedule
it for next weekend.
How are we going
to stay up that long?
The way Pho Than kept us awake, he'd
take a car battery and some jumper cables
and clamp them onto our nipples.
I think we'll start with coffee.
Pho Than used coffee, too. He'd boil up
a big pot and then make us bend over...
We're just going to drink it.
We drank it.
Anyway, so they make me empty my
pockets with all my good-luck charms
in front of everybody,
including Jake Slater.
It's midterms. I had
all my good luck stuff.
My silver dollar,
my dreamcatcher,
my Monopoly dog...
Hey, at least you didn't have the
pouch full of your baby teeth. Right?
Oh, crap. You
had the baby teeth.
Well, I had to. I
had an algebra test.
I'm a freak.
No, you're not. I know tons of people
who carry good-luck charms. Here.
My dad made this penny for me
when we went to Carlsbad Caverns.
It was the best day we ever had.
Do you always
carry this with you?
Yeah. So I guess
I'm a freak, too.
And if Jake Slater
doesn't like you,
because you carry a pouch
full of baby teeth, then...
Well, you understand why, right?
It's open.
Hey, Charlie. Hey, Sam.
Hi. Hey, Kate. I'm
going to go pack.
Why doesn't she like me? Do you
think she knows we're sleeping together?
Nobody knows. Maybe
she's just intimidated by you.
That's cool. So, why am I here?
Because I want to ask you to help
me with my sleep deprivation project.
I need another psychologist there
to supervise the group for a few hours
while I rest so I can
be fresh for the session.
Well, I would, but you're not still
going through with that, are you?
Kate, Kate. This is
breakthrough research
and really positive
for my patients.
Breakthrough research?
Somebody wants to get into
the Journal of Applied Psychology.
But my primary
concern is my patients.
Come on, Charlie. You're
desperate for recognition.
You can't play baseball anymore, so
you're trying to get it in psychotherapy.
So? What's wrong with wanting to be
known as the best in your profession?
Because you're experimenting on
human beings and sleep deprivation
is not a recognized therapeutic
tool. God, you can be so stubborn.
I am not being stubborn. I'm laying
the foundation for a new methodology.
And, for the record,
you're a therapeutic tool.
Drat. Outwitted.
Hey, Charlie. Hey,
Kate. Sam ready to go?
She's upstairs grabbing her bag, and
thanks again for taking her on my weekend.
Oh, well, it's probably a
good idea she's not here
for your crazy people
stay-up-all-night party.
I mean, I'm not a professional,
but seems to me that unstable
people need as much sleep as possible.
Right. Get some rest.
You know, there's something I've
been wanting to say to you for a long time.
Yeah?
It's really stupid, but
for the longest time
I thought you and Charlie
had the hots for each other.
You're kidding.
I know. It's crazy. I
mean, you're gay, right?
I mean, I'm not "gay" gay. I
mean, I like to live in the moment.
You're so cool. We
should hang out.
Patrick, you're early.
Didn't realize traffic
was going to be so light,
but since I'm the
first person here
for our "no sleepover,"
I'll just take the couch.
Patrick, if you want the couch, just
say you got here early to take the couch.
Nobody is going to be petty enough
to compete with you for the couch.
Damn it! I wanted the couch.
Oh, crap! The couch is gone.
I told you if I let you pick
me up, you had to be on time.
I'm sorry. I've never
been to your house before.
Please. I've seen you parked
outside my house for hours.
Well, not in daytime.
Okay, guys. As you can see,
I've set up a few cameras around
to document the workshop.
Woah, woah, woah, woah.
Whoa. I did not
agree to be filmed.
Okay, then I will make sure that no
footage of you winds up in my presentation.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I did not agree not to be filmed.
Okay. We've all been up for about 12
hours, but most sleep deprivation symptoms
don't kick in until after 36. So we'll
start the session tomorrow night.
Until then, the only
rule is to stay awake.
Ed, wake up.
Ed? Ed!
Oh, my God. He's not breathing.
You hit your feet,
you lose your seat.
I think I can trace a lot of
my anger back to the moment
I found out my mother died.
I was in the back of
a cab with my brother.
He hung up the phone, he turned
to me and he said, "Mom's dead."
There was nothing in his eyes.
It was like he didn't even care.
I said, "What's the matter
with you? Our mother is dead!"
You know what?
That sucked. Okay.
Patrick, we're 24 hours in. You've been
in front of the camera for half of that.
So far your mother has died in a
cab, on a train, in a plane, in a boat.
The only place she hasn't
died is in a box with a fox.
Stop rehearsing
your breakthrough.
Ed, what was that?
I was playing the
video bowling game
and the controller
slipped out of my hand.
I think I'm losing
my muscle control.
That's great! That's the
third sign of sleep deprivation.
What's the first one?
Unsubstantiated euphoria. Yes!
Kate should be here any
minute to cover for me.
I'm cold. Nolan,
give me your blanket.
Sure. Here you go.
Hey, Patrick? What do you
think about me and Lacey?
Yeah, not a big fan.
I mean, could you
see us together?
The only way that happens
is if she's robbing a gas station
and using you as a human shield.
But you do see
us together. Cool.
Thank God you're here.
I'm leaving.
What do you mean you're leaving? I
have to get some sleep before the session.
I have a client who's having a
breakdown. She's at the hospital.
Okay. This may
sound a little harsh,
but can't they just strap her to
a gurney, pump her full of drugs,
and let her ride it out? You
know, kicking it old-school?
I have to sign her in.
So you'll be gone,
what, a couple of hours?
The family is committing her.
The paperwork takes forever. That's
why we never did it with my mom.
It was easier to just let her run
around the house naked, covered in jam.
Okay. I really can't
process that right now.
But if you're not back in time,
I'll have to do the session
on 36 hours of no sleep.
I'm sorry, but your muscle coordination
seems fine, your pupils are responsive,
and you're showing no signs
of unsubstantiated euphoria.
Look, let me just go and I
will get back as fast as I can.
You will? You will? Yeah!
Hey.
Yeah?
So it's been almost 36
hours. How you doing?
Not good. I think I just texted a
picture of my boobs to my dentist.
Oh.
What a coincidence. He wants me
to come in tomorrow for a cleaning.
So, anyway, uh...
I was thinking, if you're
not doing anything,
I hear there's
pizza in the kitchen.
Do you want to go? Or I
could just bring you a piece.
I don't want you touching
my food. I'll get it myself.
Great. It's a date.
We got a great table. Only
problem is it's so close to the kitchen.
Give me a Coke.
Okay.
This will be fine.
That was funny.
Thanks. When I'm
tired, I'm really funny.
Fork.
Hey, guys. I'm going to make
some more coffee. What's so funny?
This fork was being hilarious.
All right. Giddy and
mildly delusional.
I think we're getting
real close to a session.
Really? Already?
I must have completely lost
track of time. This was great.
I hope we can do this again. I'm
going to go splash some pee on my face.
Face on my pee.
I will see you later.
And I meant water.
It's a crazy night, huh?
You holding up okay?
Oh, yeah. Mmm-hmm. You've
got something right there.
Did I get it?
Uh, no. Here, let me.
Lacey, you can't do that!
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. I meant to do this.
That's the same
thing! Lacey. Lacey.
You have to stop
this. You're exhausted.
What's going on right
now is called transference.
I'm going to get a tattoo
of you somewhere special,
and if you grow a little
beard, it will look perfect.
You're having these emotions because
you feel like I'm the only man in your life
who listens to you and
cares about you right now.
Oh, my God. You're right. What
am I doing? This is so embarrassing.
It's okay. Sorry. Nobody
will know. You're tired.
You don't know
what you're doing.
Yes, I do.
Okay, you do a little bit.
You've clearly lost all your
inhibitions. It's time to get started.
Great.
With the session.
Okay, everyone. Time for
the session. Let's do this.
Ed, please turn off
the bowling game.
All right. Fine.
Okay. I think we're at a point
now where we have the opportunity
to get beneath the surface of some
issues we've all been wrestling with.
Please, Ed. Tell me
you're still bowling.
Who would like
to start? I would.
Two years ago, I was in New York. I
was in the back of the cab and my brother
got a phone call.
Does anybody
have something real?
I would like to talk
about something real.
Okay, but remember, even
though we're in therapy,
there are some things that
nobody wants to hear about.
Oh, you'll want to hear this. I've had
a lot of boyfriends break up with me
because they say I'm too sexual.
Well, stuff happens.
Nolan, you've been quiet.
Actually, I really want to
hear what Lacey has to say.
Me, too. Sing it.
When I want someone,
I just have to have them.
And I tell them
nothing's off-limits.
You can't hurt me. Is
that unusual, Charlie?
Is there something
wrong with me?
You seeing what I'm seeing?
That is an unusual way to sit, right?
Okay. Lacey,
let's get into this.
Your sexually provocative
behavior is probably just you
trying to fill an emotional void
left behind from your childhood.
Wow. Void. Someone likes to
talk dirty with people watching.
She's a complete slut.
I could have told you
that from the shoes.
I'm going to go get some
pizza. You remember pizza?
Looks like your ship is
taking on water, captain.
Not helping, Ed. People are just
getting into some more difficult truths.
Lacey is this close to realizing that
she doesn't need to use sex to get love.
I use love to get sex.
Love is empty and meaningless,
and sex lasts forever.
Two down, two to go.
Time to call in a Mayday.
Ed, please.
Everyone is experiencing
emotions but me.
Why can't I feel anything real?
This isn't even real.
You just hit the iceberg, boy.
This whole thing is going down.
If I were you, I
would call it a day.
I know what I'm doing.
The hell you do. Shut up, Dad!
I apologize for "shut up."
I'm going to need a few minutes
in the kitchen to figure out "Dad."
You okay?
I tried to be objective and I
wind up yelling at a patient.
Oh, come on, Charlie. Wake
up. Look what happened here.
You called one of your patients Dad. Freud
would be creaming his jeans over that.
Freud wouldn't wear
jeans. He wore a slip.
A Freudian slip. I'm so tired.
But your hypothesis was correct.
The inhibitions came
down and the truth came out.
Yeah, for me.
Nobody else had a breakthrough?
Lacey cried, Nolan yelled, and Patrick
realized he's avoiding his real emotions.
That is huge! And what did
you realize about your dad?
I don't know.
What did I realize?
Wake up!
Ed, he's on my ass just like
my dad's been my whole life.
I've never been
good enough for him.
And?
Wake up!
Now it's just about
hitting me, isn't it?
Why did you do this study? Who
do you want recognition from?
Have you asked yourself
even one of these questions?
Well, not yet. Someone has
been slapping the crap out of me.
Okay. I'm still trying
to make my dad proud.
That's what this
whole thing was about.
Why can't I be a normal person and
just want to have sex with my mom?
Wakey, wakey, eggs and bakey.
Except it's eggables
and tofacon.
Ed, I'm very sorry about
last night. I was really burnt.
Good, because I was afraid
you were going to come over here
and ask me to take
you fishing or something.
If you want to go to a
strip club, I'd be up for that.
No, no.
Here's your blanket.
Keep it. Someday when you're lying
in your bed with it wrapped around you,
I want you to think about
what could have been.
Just take your stupid blanket.
You okay?
Yeah. Whatever I did last night,
don't take it seriously. I was crazy.
We all got a little
crazy last night.
I was thinking
about what you said,
and I may have some anger
stuff from when I was a kid,
stuff from my dad
leaving or whatever.
Welcome to the
club. This is a penny
my dad made for me
at Carlsbad Caverns.
It's actually the last great time I
remember us ever having together.
I keep it for good luck.
So it reminds you that, even though
you have issues with your parents,
you can move past them?
Exactly.
Thanks. Hope it works.
Isn't that the coin you have
been carrying around for 35 years?
Yeah.
Did you mean to give it to her?
No.
How are you feeling?
Sad.
Do you want me to take
you to Carlsbad Caverns?
Is that a euphemism
for something else?
Yes.
Then, yes.