In your estimate, how many prisoners
have passed through the camp,
while you were there?
About...
twenty-five to thirty thousand.
Do you remember somebody?
All the names are listed in the camp's registers.
You can check them.
All the archives of your camp
were burned by the Nazis before liberation.
Where did they catch you?
On my way to Switzerland.
You should've gone through Italy.
Maybe.
Where are you from?
Antwerp.
Your father was a jeweler, right?
Rabbi.
Do you practice?
Not really.
Hey friend, do you have something to eat?
Only a sandwich.
You're kidding?! Here, let me show you something.
I'll give you this for your sandwich.
Thanks, but I don't need it.
Are you crazy?!
It's a rarity. A first edition.
It's priceless, worth a thousand sandwiches!
I'll exchange it for half of yours.
Please...
Do it!
Take it.
Thank you!
Where did you get this book?
My landlords left it
when they fled.
I went in and took it.
Who is Reza?
Their son.
And "Bawbaw"?
It means 'father' in Persian.
"Thou shalt not steal" -
it's one of our Commandments.
The Eighth Commandment –
"Thou shall not steal."
I think we can forget all of them now.
Get out! Off there!
Over there!
- Get out!
- Off you go! Bags there!
- Come on! Come on!
- Get out!
- Get out! Now!
- Move it!
Go!
Move!
That's your group.
Go!
All right! Next ones!
Let's go! Get out! Bags there!
Let's go! Move it! Quickly!
Move it! Quickly!
Put your bags here!
Get out!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Bags here!
Thank you kindly!
Come on!
Walk!
Didn't just I say to come?!
Quickly!
Go! Now!
Come on, a little faster here!
Form a line!
Turn away! Don't stare at me like that!
Ready!
Fire!
Did you see that? He fell on purpose.
Hey!
You thought you could fool us, huh?
I know what I saw – you fell on purpose.
No... No, please!
You think you're smarter than me?
I'm not a Jew!
- Get on your knees!
- I'm a Persian!
On your knees!!
I'm a Persian!
- Yeah, right!
- What's he saying?!
He says he's Persian.
Don't shoot, don't shoot him, Max!
Why the hell not?
Officer Koch is looking for a Persian.
There is even a reward.
And if this one's bullshitting us?
How could he know Koch was looking for a Persian?
Come on! He said the first thing that came into his mind.
He's lying.
- Huh?! Are you lying?!
- No! I swear!
I'm not a Jew!
I'm Persian!
Here!
- Give it here.
- Please...!
- Is this yours?
- Yes!
Come with me!
Paul, it's your ass, if he turns out not to be Persian.
Yeah, yeah.
So what's the reward?
Ten cans of meat.
Six for me!
Bullshit! I found him.
"TO EACH WHAT HE DESERVES"
This is very sloppy!
I'm sorry, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer,
I tried my best!
No! You did not try your best.
Had you tried your best,
the letters would be the same size
and the lines would be parallel to each other.
Commandant authorized me
to keep the prisoner registers
And you're making a fool of me.
Tell me then - what's this letter?
It's an 'r', Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
It's anything but an 'r'!
It could be an "n" or it could be a "v"!
It could even be an "x"!
That's how I always write my 'r's...
Don't talk back to me!!
Do I look like an idiot to you?!
Or do you think I am blind?!
You will write it again!!
Un-until I am satisfied with it!
Get out!
Heil Hitler!
Come in!
May we enter, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer?
No, why don't you stand there
with your head in the door!
I already told you to come in!
What do you want?
We've found a Persian.
Bring him in!
How do you know he's a Persian?
He told us.
Of course he did. And what if he's lying?
I also said that.
Does he speak German?
Seems to.
You're Persian?
Half.
My father is Persian and...
my mother is Belgian.
Wait in the hallway.
Your name is Reza?
Joon - is your last name?
What is this, "Bawbaw"?
Bawbaw...
it means "father" in our language.
What's the capital of Persia?
Teheran.
What language do they speak there?
Farsi.
How do you say 'mother'?
Mother?
Mother. Yes, how do you say 'mother'?
It's the first word a child learns!
Answer right now
or I'll have you shot!
"Anta".
Read me something from this.
I can't read or write Farsi.
We only spoke it at home.
Then speak it right now!
What does it mean?
'You...
see the sun slowly setting,
yet you're surprised,
when it's suddenly dark.'
More than anything in this world,
I hate liars...
and thieves.
If you're lying to me, you will regret it.
But if you're telling the truth,
consider yourself lucky.
Starting tomorrow, you'll work in the kitchen
and help feed the prisoners.
Then after work every day, you'll come
and teach me your language.
- Understood?
- Absolutely!
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
Get in here!
Take him to the barracks. For now.
Only two?
He first wants to make sure
this guy is a real Persian.
If you don't want it,
I'll send it to my family in Hamburg.
Fuck your Hamburg! You, come!
Move!
Go, go!
Go! Go!
Get in line!
Throw your things here.
Go! Go!
Get in line!
Everyone must take a number
and sew it on their chest!
You'll be working here –
in the kitchen that serves officers.
Follow all orders, internal regulations
and rules of hygiene.
All knives and cutting implements
are strictly inventoried
They have to be returned to us
and counted every night.
If you breach these rules, you'll be punished.
In case of laziness and poor hygiene,
the offender gets 15 lashes.
In the event of sabotage, theft,
or an attempt to spoil the food - you'll be shot.
Is that clear?
And you must wash your hands every time,
as you enter and leave the kitchen.
Get to work!
I heard there is a dance tonight.
Will you go with me?
Sorry Max. I have other plans.
What plans are those?
What does it matter to you?
Not a lot...
I'm just curious.
Anyway, I thought you were after Jana?
Listen, that was just one time.
I... was drunk,
and I was standing next to her.
And suddenly she was standing next to me.
She still waits for you, you know?
Curls her hair for you.
Says Max likes girls with curls.
Who knows what I said that night.
See that one?
Koch wants him brought to him
after every shift.
Why is that?
He thinks he's a Persian.
So? Koch is sweet on Persians?
Koch is not sweet on anyone.
And anyway, this one is no Persian.
'Father' – "bawbaw".
"Anta" –
'mother'
'Father' – "bawbaw"
"Anta" – 'mother'
I need more.
'Plate' –
"rut"
'Fork' –
"kars"
'Bread' –
"radʒ"
'Spoon' –
"bala"
'Meat' –
"gank"
'Fish' –
"ʧim"
'Plate' –
"rut"
'Fork' –
"kars"
'Meat'...
Shit!
"gank... gank"
After the war, I want to go to Teheran.
I want to open a German restaurant there.
They don't eat pork in Iran.
I don't need pork.
I can cook anything – lamb, veal, fish.
I started as a kitchen boy
when I was twelve.
Ten years later, I was a master chef.
Master chef.
In a restaurant that served
150 guests a night.
Farsi is a complex language,
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
I have no doubt.
Which is why I've devised a plan.
4 words a day amounts to 24 words a week,
96 words a month, and...
1,152 words a year.
The war will last...
a minimum of two more years.
That means that by the end of the war,
I should know over 2000 words.
I'm not concerned
with reading or writing.
I just need to speak.
Understood?
Yes, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
One more thing...
As you can see,
I'm a very kind man,
but I'm not anybody's fool.
If you're not who you claim to be,
I will find out and kill you.
Is that understood?
Understood, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
And stop saying 'Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer'
after every sentence.
Yes, sir.
Good.
Let's start with the basics.
I need the words
that have to do with food.
For example, how do you say...
'restaurant'?
'Restaurant'?
is...
"onordan".
"O-nor-dan".
- "Onor-dan"?
- "dan".
Yes. Close enough.
'Bread' –
"rаdʒ".
- "Rаdʒ?"
- "Rаdʒ". Yes.
'Spoon' –
"bala".
"Bala"?
'Fork' –
"kars".
'Fish' –
- 'Fish'...
- "ʧim".
- "ʧim"?
- Yeah.
Nice.
Then what is... 'pig'?
'Pig'?
'Pig'.
"Tsvajn", yes.
"Tsvajn", Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
Odd as that may sound...
"Rut, ʧim, palʲi, gank, anta, bawbaw,
onordan, tsvajn, rаdʒ, bala, kars,
rut, ʧim, palʲi, gank,
anta, bawbaw, onordan, tsvajn,
rаdʒ, bala, kars, rut, ʧim,
gank, anta, bawbaw, onordan, tsvajn,
rаdʒ, bala, kars, rut, ʧim, bala,
rаdʒ, bala, kars, rut, ʧim,
onordan, tsvajn,
palʲi, gank, anta, rаdʒ, gank..."
What are you doing?!
Praying.
Pray quieter!
"rаdʒ, bala, kars, rut, ʧim, bala, gank,
anta, bawbaw, onordan, tsvajn,
rаdʒ, anta, bala, kars, rut, ʧim..."
"Onordan"
"Rut"
"Bala"
"Rаdʒ"
"Tsvajn"
Yes!
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer,
I'm Rottenfuhrer Max Beyer.
May I report?
Report.
That prisoner, who claims to be Reza Joon,
is lying to you.
He's not a Persian.
Is that so?
Yes.
And what led you to this assumption, Beyer?
Well, I checked him again.
And...
Not only does the man look like a Jew,
his hands are of a Jew, his nose is of a Jew,
the back of his head is of a Jew,
he even stinks like a Jew.
You imagine you're smarter than me?
No, of course not.
I just wanted to warn you...
About something you're incapable
to comprehend yourself.
I may not yet know, if he's telling the truth,
but I doubt that you know any better.
With all due respect, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer,
I know that pack of Zionists all too well.
There were a few of them in my town –
and they're crafty like rats.
He'll pretend to be Chinese,
if he has to.
Just to make a fool of you.
To make a fool of me?
Listen you, Jew-expert.
You took my canned meat,
and now you come
and tell me he is not Persian.
Where's the logic?
Let the Persian be my concern, Rottenfuhrer.
Dismissed.
I decided to remove you from your duties,
Helferin Strumpf.
Your handwriting leaves much to be desired.
The Persian will keep
the logs now.
- But...
- But what?!
Dismissed!
Show me your hands.
They're dirty.
You know that they must always be clean!
Go and wash them!
What are you staring at?
Get to work!
Persian!
Translate these forty words into Farsi.
Forty?
I thought – four words a day...
No, forty.
I need to make up for lost time.
Is there a problem?
There are only thirty-nine words.
Is that important?
Add another one.
Which one?
Any one.
How about 'truth'?
I don't have a pencil.
I want you in my office after your shift.
Have them translated by then.
Absolutely, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
May I take a pencil?
No.
You'll say the words, and I'll write them down.
Thank you.
Is this place free?
I see you're in a bad mood.
Leave me alone.
Why? Maybe I can help.
You can't.
Let me guess, you're unhappy in love.
I don't give a damn about love!
Then why are you so upset?
Koch dismissed me from writing the prisoner logs,
and replaced me with the Persian.
Are you sure it's the only reason?
Yes, goddamnit!
I happen to like writing lists in a quiet office
more than watching over those dirty Jews in the kitchen!
Including your Persian!
He's not a Persian, and he's not mine.
And I'm working on getting rid of him.
How?
I could kill him,
but if Koch found out...
What if he escapes?
Then he'll die for sure.
That's what I mean.
You go back to your post.
Go on!
Hey, shorty!
Come here!
Put your hands down.
Where do you think you're going?
There is a minefield there
and a swamp over there.
So, if you don't blow up,
you'll sink.
Anyway, they'll track you with dogs.
Here, sit down.
Sit down.
If I were you, I'd go back.
I can't, I'll die there too.
That's true.
I'm supposed to invent forty words
in a language I don't know.
Which one?
Farsi.
F-farsi?
Persian.
Inventing them is not a problem,
but to remember them all...
it's impossible.
And there will always be more.
Many more.
Here you are.
Go get him.
I would hurry. It won't take them long.
To your health!
I was sure
that bastard would be hiding here!
Stop!
On the ground!
Don't move!
I was taking out the garbage.
I was just taking out the garbage.
Where is the Persian?
He went to take out the slop,
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
He's been gone a long time.
Where have you been?
Come on.
Heil Hitler!
How's your penmanship?
Adequate, I think.
Sit down.
These are the lists of the new arrivals.
They need to be written into this register.
But, neatly and orderly.
Can you do that?
And the crossed out ones?
Those died en route.
Don't write them in.
No! Wait!
First the margin lines,
place of birth, their number,
then their name and date of birth.
You have...
three quarters of an hour.
But take your time
and make sure it's done properly.
And don't forget the 40 words.
We'll get to them
after you finish the lists.
'I' – Gilles – "Ilʲ"
'You' – Klaus – "au"
'Brother' –
Hillel...
"khilʲ"
'East' –
Fabio...
"fab"
'No' –
Mark...
"ma"
'Shit' –
"ard"
"ar... d, ard"
'Death' –
Max...
"ax"
How goes the work?
Good.
May I go then?
Have you forgotten something?
No.
Here are the words.
'I'?
"Il"
- "Ilʲ".
'You'?
- "Au".
"Ilʲ, au."
'Brother'?
"Shil"?
"Khilʲ"
- "Khilʲ"?
- "Khilʲ".
Say all of these aloud.
I need to know how
to pronounce them.
'East' –
- "Fab".
'No' –
"Ma".
- 'Shit'.
- "Ard".
"Ard".
'Death'?
- "Ax".
– "Ax".
"Ax".
- 'Small'.
- "Ri".
"Ri..." Rolled "r"?
Yes.
- Rrr.
- "Rr...".
- "Ri".
'Big'?
"Tus".
Good. That's enough for now.
Now I have a lot to learn.
You may go.
"Ilʲ"
Jean.
Patrice.
Claude.
Andre.
Pierre.
Olivier.
Michel.
"on"
"is"
"lod"
"drэ"
"er"
"liv"
"ʃelʲ"
"ari, nar, na,
ælʲ, isi,
sent, selʲ,
ofi, lʲeri, li,
ʃelʲ,
dje, ri"
Heil Hitler!
The Commandant wanted to speak with me.
Yes, he is waiting for you.
Enter!
Heil Hitler!
I wanted to ask you...
How's your Persian language coming along?
Good.
I've learned 570 words in the past six months.
Extremely impressive!
Why, may I ask, did you choose
such an exotic language?
I hope to move to Persia
after the war.
Do you believe Europe under The Reich
won't suit you after our victory?
No, not at all.
My brother lives in Teheran.
I've read your file, Koch.
There isn't a single word there
about your brother in Teheran.
That's right.
I only learned of it about a year ago.
He lived in Greece up until 1939.
Too many coincidences, don't you think?
We come to power
and your brother moves to Greece.
War begins,
and he drifts off to Teheran.
Not much of a patriot.
And now you here with this Moslem.
I assure you, Herr Standartenfuhrer,
I'm not doing anything wrong.
I'm just studying the language.
Let's change the subject.
This weekend, I've organized
a nature outing for the troop.
A picnic.
Prepare food and drink for thirty people.
But it has to be the finest.
Make sure it's the best we can provide.
Nothing French. Something from the homeland.
Understand?
Will do, Herr Standartenfuhrer.
- Heil Hitler!
Do you know why they called this dish "Eisbein"?
Long ago, they used shin bones of pigs
for making gliders of skates.
I think we've learned enough
food words.
Let's change the subject.
How do you say 'love' in Farsi?
"Onaj".
"Onaj"?
Then 'I love you' is... "Ilʲ..."
"... onaj au."
And what does a girl say in return?
If she loves him back, she says the same.
"Ilʲ onaj au."
"Ilʲ bar onaj au."
"Ilʲ... bar..."
It means 'also'.
Are you in love with someone, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer?
No. Not yet.
But...
maybe, someday...
Why do you ask? Is that so hard to imagine?
Do you think I'm not capable of love?
No.
We're all capable of it.
In the grass there grows a tiny flower...
It is called...
Erika.
Hundreds of thousands pretty bees...
buzz around her – Erika.
Just because there's sweetness in her heart.
An enchanting scent comes
from her flowered dress.
In the grass grows a tiny flower...
It is called...
Erika.
Bravo!
Comrades, ladies and gentlemen,
you sang so beautifully.
It touched my heart.
I suggest we have some refreshments.
Hauptsturmfuhrer Koch has prepared
a small menu for us.
Tomato soup with roasted butter-croutons.
Soup!
Soup!!
I hope you're all as hungry as I am!
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
we got lucky with the weather!
Koch organized all of it!
Come on!
Nothing but the best, is what I told him.
Get lost!
I didn't know you played the accordion.
There's a lot you don't know about me.
Why would you bother, I'm not an officer.
Don't be an ass, Max.
Call me a fool if you want,
I kept telling myself that he loves me.
But he used me and then threw me away.
And, are you still in love?
Why do you need to know?
I don't need to.
Cut more bread.
Reza, what is 'tree' in Farsi?
"Radʒ"
What did you say?
In Farsi 'tree' is "radʒ".
Oh, you filthy Jew!
I thought you said that "radʒ" means 'bread'.
You lying swine!
It means both 'tree' and 'bread'!
Like 'castle' in German!
Stop lying to me!
I trusted you and you betrayed me!
What for? So you can laugh at me
with the other Jews?
I warned you not to play me for a fool!
He is really worked up!
The Persian must've stolen something.
I'm glad I only took one piece of bread.
Let's leave our man to his protocols!
That sure is hard-earned bread!
So... gentlemen, you wanted bread?
Bread?
Such great company...
is a rare thing nowadays.
Believe me, years shall pass
and you'll remember this day
as one of the happiest in your life.
Let's capture this moment
before it gets really dark.
Where is my camera?
Herr Commandant.
I'll do it myself.
Everyone should stand in a semi-circle.
Let's all look happy!
Thank you very much!
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen!
Pity we have to go back to work tomorrow.
It's so lovely in the fresh air, you can forget the smell...
The Persian is of no use to me anymore.
Send him to the quarry tomorrow.
Of course, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
I'll request that you be assigned to work supervision.
Make sure his time there is hard.
I can promise you that.
Oh, I can promise you that!
Stand up!
I said, stand up!
Get up! Move it!
Let's go!
Here!
Your new workplace.
You'll work until I say you're done.
Is that understood?
Come on!
Hit harder!
Go on!
No rest for you, is that clear?! Go on!!
We'll continue tomorrow.
We'll get a fresh start tomorrow, yes? What do you say?
We'll continue tomorrow! Get going!
What are you doing here?
I thought she was Commandant's for a minute.
That was before. She is mine now.
That's good.
You can have her.
I don't like redheads anyway.
Watch out!
Can you take my shift in the quarry tomorrow?
Why?
I'm going to take her to the soldiers' dance.
Yeah, yeah...
And break that Persian's back for me!
Finish him!
Fill it up!
I said, fill it up!
I can't anymore.
This is work sabotage.
You will be shot for this!
Fill it up!
I can't...
"Ilʲ ma lan."
(I no able.)
What did you just say?
Kapo, bring him back to the barracks!
He is of no use here.
I hate that perfume.
Why did you put so much on?
I didn't do it for you.
For who then?
Beyer.
Max?
He was so persistent, I finally gave in.
But I thought you said he liked...
He must've changed his mind.
Won't you wait for me?
It's too hot in here, my makeup is running.
But I always wait for you...
See you there, darling!
You look really nice all dressed.
Pardon me?
For you.
"Anta... anta... Ilʲ ora ahan anta."
What the hell is he saying?
It must be in his language.
He's been talking like this all night.
"Ilʲ ora ahan."
"Ilʲ ora ahan, anta!"
Well, what am I supposed to hear?
"Ilʲ ora ahan, anta."
Do you understand what he's saying?
"Anta..."
"Ilʲ ora ahan..."
"Anta, ilʲ ora ahan..."
He's talking to his mother. He wants to go home.
So he's a Persian after all.
Take him to the hospital. You come with me.
Here are the remaining eight.
A deal is a deal.
Many thanks, Herr Hauptshturmfuhrer.
They really did a number on you, didn't they?
You were screaming some crazy nonsense.
Where am I?
Soldiers' medical ward.
Koch ordered you brought here.
What language were you screaming in?
Farsi.
- But not real Farsi.
- What?
I made it up.
What do you mean...
made it up?
I don't know.
Even now... I don't know
what I'm saying even right now.
Oh yes, I told Koch you were crazy –
screaming nonsense like that.
I even offered to inject
some air into your veins...
...to put you out of your misery.
But he would have none of it.
He even sent you food a few times.
Strange man.
Test me.
"Radʒ".
I'm sorry, I overreacted.
Let's forget it ever happened.
As you wish,
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
Take these.
Yours are worn out.
Did they belong to the prisoners
that were sent East?
No, these are mine.
I've gained some weight here in the camp.
But they should fit you just fine.
Now let's get to work.
So, "radʒ" means 'bread'.
and 'tree'.
What if it's Jana?
Do you think he is fucking her now?
If he is...
she's definitely not enjoying it.
Why?
No.
The Commandant's...?
Are you kidding?!
Oh that poor girl!
And you too!
Max!
Then, I just want to say...
that I promise
I will always do better,
be a bigger man
and stand firm, when the need arises.
Come in!
Come in!!
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer,
I'm here to make a report.
Can this wait until tomorrow,
when I'm on duty?
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer, it's about Herr Standartenfuhrer...
Close the door!
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer, it's a personal matter
about Herr Standartenfuhrer,
and as such, could not be reported
to the duty officer.
Report then.
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer, I'm here to report
personal information
which was inappropriately shared
by an officer on duty.
Which officer?
Helferin Elsa Strumpf shared
unethical information about the Commandant
with Rottenfuhrer Beyer.
She also happens to be his lover.
What did she say?
I can't repeat it.
Say it now, that's an order!
I don't feel comfortable...
Well, what the hell are you reporting then?!
For God's sake! Report now
and stop playing a virgin with me.
Just whisper it into my ear.
What a vindictive little bitch you are,
Helferin Krause.
Thank you for performing your duty.
Dismissed.
Heil Hitler!
As you are well aware, Herr Standartenfuhrer,
there is a total prisoner transport
scheduled for tomorrow.
Of course I am aware of it.
I gave the orders myself.
Of course, Herr Standartenfuhrer.
I'd like your permission to keep the Persian.
He is indispensable to me.
It's a delicate issue to show a preference
for a particular prisoner.
I know,
that's why I came to you with my request.
There is a problem.
There is a report about you and your Persian.
It's a good thing only I read it.
The next one might fall into wrong hands.
And so... to hell with him –
and your good reputation will remain intact.
Is it possible to find out what's in the report?
As you wish...
It says that you're harboring a Jew,
who pretends to be Persian.
That the Jew is likely your lover and boy-toy.
And that you removed a female guard
from important bookkeeping duties
and gave it to the parasite.
- Shall I go on?
- No, thank you.
That's enough.
All of this has no relation to the truth.
Except the bookkeeping matter.
I will reinstate the Helferin,
whom I'm sure is behind the report,
to resume her substandard work.
Well, since we are on the topic
of unsubstantiated gossip,
I can tell you a rumor
which relates directly to you.
I'm all ears.
It's...
...nothing big.
It's really a very small matter.
There is a rumor going around that...
that you have a very small penis.
Very small. Tiny.
Almost... invisible.
I assume that this rumor is baseless.
And you are in fact, quite amply endowed.
Nonetheless, I just wanted to enlighten you.
Thank you for your understanding,
Herr Standartenfuhrer.
How many words have you learned so far?
About... 1500 words.
Let's talk then.
Who are you?
"Ilʲ Klaus Koch."
(I Klaus Koch.)
Good.
Tell me more...
Where were you born?
Reza, I can't.
I memorized the words, but...
Try it.
You think I haven't tried?
"Ori lʲen rav au li?"
(How many years your age?)
I don't know numbers yet.
Right.
We'll learn them later.
"Ælʲ ʃur av au... anta?"
(What name is your... mother?)
Helena, but...
I don't remember her.
She died when I was three.
"Ilʲ ma ʃelʲ Alʲman."
(I no understand German.)
"Ælʲ dʲe isi kalʲavi?"
(What with she happened?)
"Isi ʒer ax."
(She have death. )
"Ilʲ ma selʲ isi."
(I no remember she.)
"Au ʃer gælʲ."
(You do good.)
"Rav ilʲ bawbaw mar..."
(My father disabled...)
"zeki jah..."
(legs and...)
"mad" - "mad"
(back) - (back)
"Ni ma ʒer gus."
(We no have money.)
"Ni alʲf..."
(We sell...)
How do you say "hot water"?
"Lʲest kan."
(Water hot.)
"Lʲest kan. Ni alʲf lʲest kan."
(Water hot. We sell water hot.)
"Vi ʒeravi gus lʲeri?"
(You have much money?)
"Ma."
(No.)
"Ni ʒer ril rav ɔnor."
(We have little for food.)
"Felʲ dri... jah..."
(Only cabbage and...)
"jah him."
(and potato.)
"Bet mat."
(This rarely.)
"Haraj au oskavi nar?"
(Of it you became cook?)
"Oj."
(Yes.)
"Has rem, ilʲ tar rav ɔnor lʲeri."
(When young, I dream of food much.)
Tomorrow, I'm sending you to work on a farm,
while we ship the rest of them.
Finished!
You don't need me in the kitchen?
It's just for a couple of days,
then you'll be back.
Will they all be killed?
They're being relocated to Poland.
- Where they will all be killed...
- Leave it!
I know nothing.
I'm just a cook.
You'll be picked up in the morning. Now go!
I heard they are shipping all Jews
to Madagascar.
They're relocating us
to a different labor camp.
You're both wrong. This is the end of us all!
I heard rumors that Poland is death.
We're French – they only kill Jews
from Poland or Russia.
Could you all shut up?!
Some of us are trying to sleep!
A Jew is a Jew. No matter where he's from.
Germans need a labor force.
Jew labor is free.
There is no profit in killing us.
You're all naive as children –
these transit camps are merely
the gates to hell.
One six three.
Five one eight!
175?!!
- One seven five!
- Too late!
Get the hell in there!
Shut up, already!
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
The register is almost finished.
Almost?
We managed to finish loading the whole camp,
and you can't finish crossing out their names?!
Get out, I'll do it myself.
That useless bitch!
Heil Hitler!
I see everything is in exceptional order.
Thank you, Herr Standartenfuhrer.
Good. I'm here for another reason.
Which one of you requested a transfer?
I did! I asked to be transfered to another camp,
Herr Standartenfuhrer.
You, Helferin Krause? Are you sure?
Yes, Herr Standartenfuhrer.
That's odd.
Those bureaucrats must have
messed things up as usual.
It seems instead of you, they've made
a transfer allocation for your friend here.
Congratulations!
You're on the next train to the front.
Aren't you happy to serve the Reich,
Miss Strumpf?
Yes.
I am, Herr Standartenfuhrer!
Excellent!
You will leave to the Eastern Front immediately.
Where I hope you will find plenty
of what you claimed to lack here.
You have seven lives like a cat, Persian.
A little Persian cat.
You know what?
I have a strong will.
And I'm determined to see you die.
Why don't we do it right now?
Here.
Ready?
Aviva –
"viva".
'madness'
Your name? - Angelo.
"ʒelɔ" –
'work'.
Your name? - Roberto.
"ærtɔ" –
'hunger'
Your name? - Paolo.
"olo" –
'arm'
Your name? - Domenico.
"iko" –
'understanding'
Your name?
Abramo.
"bramo" –
'hope'
Hurry up already!
Your name? - Franko.
"ankɔ" –
'patience'
"ærtɔ"
What?
Hunger.
"ærtɔ" means 'hunger'.
"ærtɔ"
"anko" –
'patience'.
"anko"
"iko" –
'understanding'.
"iko"
"bramo" –
'hope'.
"bramo"
"ʒelɔ" –
'work'.
What a wonderful language!
"ʒelɔ"
Don't worry! Stay strong
and everything will be fine.
Good evening.
My name is Marco.
This is my brother, Jacob.
He is mute.
I am Reza.
I don't speak Italian.
Aren't you a Jew?
Persian.
Why are you coming back so late?
I work in the kitchen.
And I thought only us Jews
knew how to get by.
But, apparently, Persians do too!
The Italians that work in the kitchen –
they say you see an officer after work.
Why?
I teach him Persian.
Hey you! Get up!
Get up!!
Get... up!!
Stand up!
Leave him alone!
He's my brother!
Stand up! You deadbeats, stand up!
Stand up!
Fakers! Cheaters! Get up!!
Enter!
Come in, sit down.
I've prepared something.
I would like to recite something.
- What do you want to recite?
- A poem.
I... I wrote a poem. In Farsi.
"Lom gat runleri ah fab,"
(Wind push clouds to east, )
"ah dan ufi... ʧen rav glo."
(to place soul yearns for peace.)
"Ilʲ vit ranaro talʲ sab,"
(I know I will be happy there, )
"æni runljeri san flo."
(where clouds now go.)
What do you say?
I like it very much, Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer.
Don't call me that. Call me Klaus.
I don't know if I can.
Try it. Come on!
Eat this!
Can I take this... to the barrack with me,
Klaus?
What happened?
Nothing.
Everything is fine.
We both know it isn't.
Who is it for?
Don't ask.
You just have to trust me.
I'll give you some canned meat and bread.
And I will walk you to the barrack.
Thank you.
You saved his life.
I'm in your debt now.
You don't owe me anything.
It's not that I like you so much...
It's just...
I promised my mother
I would bring my brother back home.
If you die – my brother dies too.
Get up!!
Get up!
Go!! Get going to work!!
To work! Quickly!
Quickly!
Get up!!
Go to work! Quickly!
Get up, Jacob!
Come on, little brother. Be strong!
Faster!!
Bunch of lazy bastards!
Faster!
Jew.
Are you Persian?
French.
French? That's what I thought.
Jew.
What nationality are you?
Who are you?
I'm talking to you!!
You hear me?!
He's an Englishman.
He doesn't speak a word in German.
An Englishman?
Look at his uniform –
British Air Force.
English plane – Englishman.
I thought the British were a fair race,
blonde or at least red-haired.
Ethnically, this one is Persian...
I believe.
Are you kidding me?
The British stick rabble
from all their colonies into their army.
Is he a real Persian?
Like I said – I believe so.
You are Persian and you say nothing?!
You're a real Persian?
I found a Persian!
You're mine!
You belong to me!
You know that soldiers are not allowed
in the kitchen.
I know, sweetheart.
But I found another Persian,
and I think they'll be happy to meet each other.
What do you think, Reza?
Are you coming with me?
We must wash our hands
before leaving the kitchen.
What?
Wash our hands?
That is the rule.
Fine, I understand.
After you.
I've waited so long, I can wait all night.
Go ahead. Wash them again.
The British pilot, is he here?
Over there.
You'll have a real family reunion, won't you?
Let's see how well you understand each other.
Hey, wake up!
Wake up!
How did you do this, huh?
He was alive twenty minutes ago!
- Who did this?
- I don't know!
Who did this?!
Did you do this?
You shit rat!
Tell me who did this!
Don't lie to me – who did this?!
I don't know!
Don't lie to me!!
Leave him alone!
I did it!
I did it.
Why are you howling?
You're howling, because you think it's unfair?
Do all of you think it's unfair?!
You are asking yourselves – why us?!
Why you?!
Because you are fucking traitors!
All of you!!
Everybody!!
The Allied Air Forces bombed our railway tracks,
but we must continue
the transfers of prisoners as planned.
We will march them
to the nearest working rail line tomorrow.
Can't tell, whether it's rain or snow out there.
Either way, it's shit.
Damn it!
Do not doubt the power of the Wehrmacht!
We are the SS.
And we will destroy all enemies of the Reich!
Farewell my lovely dear,
farewell, farewell, farewell.
We must, we must all part forever.
Farewell, farewell, farewell.
It's about Germany's glory, glory, glory.
All hail, all hail our victory,
All hail our victory.
Nasty weather.
I heard about what happened.
I understand why you're so sad.
I'm sorry about that Persian.
How great it would have been...
for us three to talk,
to practice Farsi.
He would have been like a brother to you.
Tomorrow, you'll go the farm again.
You know, my brother and I had a falling out.
Ever since I joined The Party,
he hasn't spoken a word to me.
Why did you do that?
What?
Join the Party.
I don't really know.
I was walking down the street
and they were standing there,
smoking,
in their brown shirts,
laughing and talking so cheerfully.
So I went and joined them.
And then?
That was in '32.
A year later my brother had troubles,
and had to escape.
Where to?
To Teheran...
I think.
Your brother is much smarter than you, Klaus.
Why are you so angry with me?
I didn't kill your countryman.
I'm just tired.
Tired?
Of what?
Of being afraid.
As long as you work for me,
you don't need to be afraid.
You know what?
I'll bet you 20 cans of meat
that nothing will happen to you.
Too bad, if I win, I won't get to eat them,
since I'll be dead.
Bloody cold.
I believe our continued presence here
is no longer necessary, Obersturmfuhrer Krupp.
Yes, of course.
It's all under control here.
Lunch, then?
Yes.
What's for lunch today?
Baked fish.
With potato puree and red cabbage.
I hate fish.
It's fabulous!
What is this beauty?
Sea trout. From the Rhine.
Mecklenburg, Western Pomerania.
Gentlemen.
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer, I see you decided
to part with your Persian.
Why do you say that?
Because I just saw him
at the prisoner transport.
Thank you.
Have you learned all the words you need?
You must have made a mistake, Herr Obersturmfuhrer.
To err is human.
Maybe you need glasses?
Well, I'm not blind yet.
Gentlemen,
I wish you bon appetit.
We will certainly have it. Thank you!
After all, I haven't eaten anything today.
Reza!
"Ǽlʲ au ʃer sav?"
(What you do here?)
"Ad istɔ tefleri ʃer."
(As they all do.)
Siemens, look back!
Herr Hauptsturmfuhrer!
Excuse me!
This man is coming with me!
It's impossible. The lists have been closed...
Damn your fucking lists!
This man goes with me! That's an order!
I need an order from the Commandant.
I'll shoot you right now,
and then get the order from Commandant.
As you wish.
Who left the camp instead of you?
Another prisoner.
Is it the same person you brought food to?
Yes.
Who is he to you?
He is no one to me.
Just a mute boy from Italy.
A mute boy from Italy!
And you would sacrifice your life for him?
For him you would die
with that nameless horde?
They're only nameless,
because you don't know their names.
But they are no worse than you!
At least they are not murderers.
I'm not a murderer.
No.
You just make sure the murderers eat well.
Gentlemen, the entire defensive front
has been placed on high alert.
The Americans, with support of their air forces,
are advancing faster than we expected.
To be precise, they are already here.
The High Command in Berlin
has ordered the camp to be evacuated.
All work must be stopped immediately.
All evidence and the remaining prisoners
must be disposed of.
You have orders to lock the prisoners
in the barracks
and turn off their lights.
You undestand what I mean?
Next barrack! Hurry up!
- Where is he?
- Who?
Joon! Prisoner Reza Joon!!
"Liv ilʲ!"
(Follow me!)
Max!
Max, let it be!
Leave it!
No, no, no!
Herr Obersturmfuhrer, I need
to speak with the Commandant.
Why are you not participating in the liquidation?
It's important! It's very important!
The Commandant is busy.
All right, then I'll wait.
Herr Standartenfuhrer, I am reporting
that Hauptsturmfuhrer Koch has left the camp.
Against your orders.
And he took one of the prisoners with him!
Who are you?
Beyer. Rottenfuhrer Beyer.
Von Dewitz, it seems Rottenfuhrer Beyer
has lost his purpose.
Where are you going?
Ten kilometers from here is a small airfield.
There is a plane waiting
to take me to Istanbul.
From there I fly to Teheran.
Then why did you bring me with you?
Remember our bet for twenty cans of meat?
I didn't want to lose.
"Ani gælʲ!"
(Good life!)
"Ilʲ salʲ au, gælʲ sid!"
(I greet you, good sir!)
"Vian rav ilʲ gælʲ."
(Document for me good.)
What language are you speaking?
Your passport says you're Belgian.
"Oj."
(Yes.)
"Ilʲ Marcel Gallant."
(I'm Marcel Gallant.)
"Rav ilʲ..."
(I have...)
"... lʲenleri."
(...years.)
"Au shelʲ?"
(You understand?)
Khiobi! - Yes?
I don't understand this man.
Come and try to talk to him.
"Oj."
(Yes.)
"Ilj jom Farsi ben gælj."
(I speak Farsi much good.)
He is speaking absolute gibberish.
Very suspicious.
And he looks like a German.
We are supposed to detain them for questioning.
"Ilʲ... Marcel Gallant."
(I... Marcel Gallant.)
"Ilʲ... flo ah hilʲ."
(I... go to brother.)
"Ilʲ... Ilʲ flɔ rav gas ɔnordan."
(I... I go to open restaurant.)
"Au ʃelʲ?"
(You understand?)
Akhbari! Come! Come!
"Ah ælj au ma ʃelʲ?!"
(Why you no understand?!)
Grab him!
Hold him! Hold him!
Stand still, you!
In your estimate, how many prisoners
have passed through the camp,
while you were there?
About...
twenty five to thirty thousand.
Do you remember anyone?
Could you give us a few names?
All the names are listed in the camp's registers.
You can check them.
They carefully recorded everyone
who entered or went out.
Unfortunately, there are no registers.
All the records of your camp
were burned by the Nazis before liberation.
Do you remember some of the names?
Yes.
I remember.
I can give you...
2840 names.
Of people?
Yes.
The first and last names of 2840 people.