Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
M_I_SForEver
Shh.
Shh, hey, it's okay.
Hey, hey, hey, it's okay, shh,
shh, shh.
It's just a nightmare.
Hey, hey.
Wanna tell me about it?
Oh, I knew you'd ask me that.
Oh, just go, you stink of
cigars.
Sometimes it's best to talk
about it.
You're weird.
Am I?
You sleep okay?
Sleepover.
Or is it tomorrow?
It's too thick, isn't it?
They don't even like me.
You mean you don't even like
them?
What's not to like?
They've only known you two
months.
You're the new girl on the
block.
On the block?
Queen of the Scottish castle.
Oh, don't say that, I hate
it when people say that.
Where are all your friends,
anyway?
Why is it just me who
has to make an effort?
One, I do make an effort.
And two, you're the one
finishing school today.
I don't want you moping
about in your room all day
not seeing anyone.
You seem to have made a
pretty good career out of that.
Yes, but I get paid for it.
You could pay me.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
It was the perfect blend!
Bee, wait.
- I'm late, Dad.
- Wait,
I wanna show you something.
Close your eyes.
- What?
- Please.
No tricks.
Ladies and gentlemen, behind
these boards
is the seed of what lies ahead,
a vision of what is yet to be.
Do not be afraid.
It may appear as magic,
but I can assure you, it's only
theatre.
The makeover.
Which is your favourite, two or
six?
Oh, I shouldn't have said that.
I prefer it as it is.
You're absolutely right,
- it's more...
- Ugly.
Yes.
Bee, can you at least show
some excitement about all this?
Forget the paint, I mean the
whole thing.
This place, our new life.
I didn't want a new life.
I'm trying to make things
better for us.
There's something here, I can
feel it.
I'm alive, I'm alive!
- The "Living Play."
- The "Living Play," Bee.
- A play that has to be...
- Has to be experienced,
not merely seen.
Hundreds of people exploring
multiple rooms all at once.
Yes.
Props, costumes, sound
design, special effects.
Yes.
Actors bring history alive
under one terrifying narrative.
- Yeah, a living...
- A living piece of shit.
See you later, dad.
Don't write anything I wouldn't
do.
My patience is thin, Mr.
Bremner.
What exactly are you asking?
One more week, sir.
My boys, they'll work in
the fields until I can pay.
They're fit, strong...
If I wanted labourers,
I'd employ labourers.
I have a daughter.
And what area of employment
would you presume upon your...
would you presume upon this
daughter?
She, uh, a maidservant, or...
Or?
Hi, you must be our new
neighbour.
I'm Jenny.
Bee.
It's nice to finally meet you,
- Is that short for...
- Beleth.
Beleth, oh, that's nice.
Well, we've been curious to know
who's moved into the castle.
So, your parents with you?
My dad.
Is he gonna fix the place up?
Guess you could say that,
yeah.
Gets awful lonely up here.
My dad's a writer,
that's kind of the point.
Be good to catch him sometime.
You sure about that?
Jack Travis, look him up.
Guessing the sheds are
cleared.
I see you got the TV working.
It's been working for ages.
Did you even hear what
I said?
Something about making tea or
something?
Where's that tea?
No, no!
You can get out there
and take down those sheds
like I've been asking for weeks.
Oh, yeah, 'cause no one's
gonna buy your granny's house
if there's some nasty sheds in
the garden.
Not if they're falling
apart, they won't.
Your family should've
sold this place ages ago,
your granny's been dead for
years.
- Callum!
- What?
I'm not being funny.
You've got to admit,
it's pretty awful timing.
Us having to come all the way
up here and sort it out now.
We're supposed to be taking a
year out.
Is it too cold and
windy in the far north
for poor wee Callum?
More like it's too boring and
shite.
Yeah, well, that's life.
Look, you'd only be sat on your
ass
watching TV somewhere else
anyway.
Oh, what was that?
Oh, oh, and what's that,
Callum?
Is that the sound of a big,
manly man
smashing sheds to pieces?
I'll smash you to pieces.
Fat chance.
After everything I've
done for you, Jenny?
Look, you'll get a tea
if you do some bloody work.
Oh, sorry, did I say tea?
I meant coffee.
Coffee helps me do manly things.
Jack Travis in the castle.
What was that?
What?
You said a name.
Um, Jack Travis.
The writer?
Two seconds.
Here he is, Jack Travis.
What?
Jack Travis is famous, man,
has to be.
Look, he's had this hit West End
play
that scared the shite out of
everyone.
Horrorpreneur, what is that?
I guess it's somebody that's
an expert in scaring people.
That is awesome.
Yeah, well, why has he moved
here?
Jack Travis in the frigging
castle.
Katie, truth or dare?
Dare.
Okay, I dare you to down
all of that drink in one go.
- I can't.
- Come on.
- No.
Yes.
♪ We like to dine with Katie ♪
♪ 'Cause Katie is our mate ♪
♪ We like ♪
Come on.
- Mm-mm, mm-mm.
- Yeah, come on.
That burns.
Okay, Alex, truth or dare?
Truth.
Okay.
What was the name of your first
ever
pet?
Lame.
You had a pet called Lame?
Ha ha, no.
Bee's turn.
Oh, queen of the castle,
do your worst.
Ticktock, ticktock.
Katie, truth or dare?
Um, truth.
Lame.
Everybody's frigging lame.
Why are you really friends
with Alex?
What sort of a shite question
is that?
Why am I friends with Alex?
'Cause we're friends?
I said, why are you really her
friend?
This is fricking stupid.
Uh, 'cause I like her and
she likes me.
Like, honest to god.
All right, Bee, truth.
Why do you think Katie's
friends with me, hmm?
I don't know.
Maybe because you make her
feel better about herself,
because she's secretly a
good girl and you're a slag.
What the fuck?
What game are you playing at,
woman?
We had an agreement.
I, I couldn't help it, Campbell.
He knew already.
Then a curse be on your
footsteps
as you bring service to this
household.
This comes from a girl who
sits at the back of the class
drawing dragons and
bats all over her work.
At least I can draw.
Oh, who gives a
shite?
That's just weird.
And how old is your dad,
anyway?
Must have been about 15 when he
had you.
Oh, touched a nerve.
At least I know who my dad is.
Uh, piss off, you arrogant
cow.
You think you're all so high and
mighty
in your frigging castle, don't
you?
I'd rather live here
than on some shitty
council estate in Wick.
And I'd rather live in
the back of a bin lorry
than this shitehole of
a haunted castle anyway.
Oh my god, a bin
lorry.
You do know why no one else
would come here for a sleepover?
I don't think she
knows.
This should be good.
It was a cold, dark
- and stormy night.
- Shut up.
The rain lashed at the
roof tiles like an old granny
pissing herself on the kitchen
floor.
Oh, that's nasty.
Okay, so there was this evil
baron who used to live here
called Laird Mackay or some
shite who everyone hated.
And the scandal was,
he was shagging his
housekeeping maid, Tabitha.
And obviously she got
up the duff, pregnant.
So they had this son, Alasdair,
who, when he was older one
night,
blurts out in front of all
of the Laird's dinner guests,
"My mother's not my real mother.
"My mother's the frigging
maid, you bunch of culls."
But that's the nice part.
Laird Mackay chased Alasdair
all the way down to the cellar
here he spent the whole night
building an entire wall around
him,
leaving him to thirst and starve
for days.
And night after night, Alasdair
would cry out for help,
and not even his mother, his
real mother, came to save him.
But there was one who did come.
The devil.
The devil made a pact with
Alasdair.
"You may have your revenge
in this place, Alasdair,
"but you will do my work
for eternity."
Next thing you know, Tabitha is
found dead
at the bottom of the
staircase, every bone broken.
Laird Mackay went insane,
threw himself out of the
highest window in the castle.
Or so they say.
Some say, if you put
your hands to the wall
where Alasdair was buried alive,
you can still hear his screams.
His screams to be set
free again.
That's ridiculous.
Then prove it.
Dare.
I dare you to put your hands on
the wall.
What's the point?
It's just a wall.
A pact with the devil?
Then what are you worried
about?
The only thing I'm worried
about
is looking completely stupid.
Well, you already
kinda are, so.
You two are doing it as well.
Aye.
You left me no choice,
Tabitha.
Please, Mackay, he's just a boy.
And a boy he shall remain.
Let him go, far from here.
You're his mother, Tabitha.
Would you wish him away so far
from home?
Oh my God, is this it?
It has to be.
Okay, who's first?
You's can frig off.
Bee?
Stupid question.
Hm.
Okay, Bee, your turn.
What about Katie?
It's your castle.
This is so stupid.
Hey.
Sorry if I acted like a bitch
yesterday.
I don't think that.
Why do you think you were?
I just hate school.
So did I.
So why the castle?
It's kind of a big old
place for just two people.
My dad's kind of...
He writes weird stuff.
What was his last one about?
Never watched it.
You never watched your dad's
play?
What's he working on how?
He has this crazy idea.
What?
I can't say.
I won't tell anyone.
It's immersive, um,
like a walkaround play.
In the castle?
What's it about?
Maybe you should come over
sometime.
Shit, I'm just making this
worse.
You're gonna have to
come and do this, love.
Since when did you ever iron a
shirt?
Exactly, that's exactly my
point.
Who are these people
anyway, the crease police?
You don't have to come.
Oh, yeah, yeah, no, uh,
wine and cheese in a castle?
No, I think I might just stay
home,
maybe iron the rest of my
clothes.
So this girl just invited us
over, then?
She's just being nice.
Yeah, well, let's hope they
are, eh?
You can always leave.
What do you mean, "You
can always leave"?
I'm beginning to think
you don't want me there.
I didn't mean...
Apparently her dad likes his own
company.
Okay, so why are you going,
then?
Look, Jenny, if I
had something better to do,
believe me, I would go and do
it.
Leave you with all the
socialising with famous writers.
I honestly don't know
how your family survived
growing up round here, I really
don't.
People are afraid of the
dark, aren't they?
It's as though we can just all
forget our deepest troubles
by sitting in a circle,
and stroke some kittens,
and do some mindfulness
exercises.
There's this idea that we're
like, um,
wheelie bins.
Here we go.
No, seriously.
This idea that we're all
just full of rubbish, okay,
and that all we need
to do is just empty it
and do some breathing, stroke an
iguana,
listen to some whale song
and bang, it's all
gone.
What would you do with all
this rubbish instead, then?
Well, uh,
if we are going for the
wheelie bin analogy,
which is mine, thank you,
what I would say
is that we need to, uh,
look closely at what's in
the rubbish, go through it
and find what's in there
that might be, uh...
Rubbish.
No, um, no, useful.
But isn't it so much easier
to just pay the council tax
and have someone take
it all away?
No self-examination needed.
Well, I suppose that's
the problem, isn't it?
It's always about what's
easiest.
Take Jack, okay?
Jack's got his own troubles,
his own rubbish, hm?
You're a writer, I imagine
you use it to write.
You can't write without
some serious reflection,
some self-examination, right?
Oh, you can.
Okay, okay, you can.
But I mean, it wouldn't
be any good, would it?
All you have to do is, you
have to go back to your life,
examine your rubbish, and in
some way turn it into fuel.
I mean, for example, uh, hm,
what was it that fueled
you to buy this place?
A witch.
Sorry, did I say witch?
I meant estate agent.
Oh, you got me.
That just sort of fitted,
didn't it?
See?
Jack's not afraid to go to dark
places.
That's where people find
themselves.
If we don't know what we're
afraid of,
then how can we know anything at
all?
We know ourselves from
the decisions we make.
Yeah, okay, to a degree,
but...
Why don't we ask Bee?
Bee, what's that short for
again?
I told you, Beleth.
Oh, isn't Beleth a demon?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's the, one of the gods
of hell, isn't he?
He had like 85 legions of
demons, of...
Why would a Cambridge student
decide to have a child
before he graduated?
Okay.
Or maybe it was because he
didn't decide to have a child.
- Maybe it just happened...
- That's enough.
And he thought, can't change
shit now.
That's enough.
Bee, Bee, wait.
What is all that shit in your
office?
What, this place is haunted?
Don't be ridiculous.
Well, what's with the
paranormal murder inquiry
pinned to your fucking wall?
It's nothing, it's
just folklore and rumours.
And you're all over it
like a fly around shit.
That's enough.
We wouldn't even have this
place if it wasn't for all that.
I never even wanted this
place.
God, Mum was right, it's all
about you.
You're messed up.
You listen here, Beleth.
I am this close to something
great.
Thousands of people will come
here
and experience something they
have never before imagined.
I don't care.
You need to start honouring
everything I've done for you,
you feckless waste of skin.
Dad, let go of me.
I'm not saying
don't do it.
Just think about it, Jack,
- it's a long way away.
- From where?
I don't want people just nipping
out from London at high tea
to pop in on Jack Travis's new
play thing.
This is a whole new level of
experience.
I know what
you're trying to do.
I'm sorry, I don't think you
do.
People will come for days.
Well, they'll have to.
Days?
Weeks, months.
They'll quit the rat race and
build houses on the beach.
Samantha?
I love your
passion, Jack, you know I do.
The whole thing does add
colour to your story.
Who's gonna back you?
I've got backing.
Really?
The whole thing's coming
together.
Well, I'm happy for
you,
because all I'm hearing
is that none of the major
players are interested.
It's too off the beaten track.
Aye, well, perhaps that's for
the best.
What?
Call me when you're back in
London.
We'll show them, won't we,
Alasdair?
Father and son.
Hey.
Pull up a seat.
How's the writing
going?
You know, there used to be
a whole village over there.
That what you're writing
about?
- Depends.
- Depends on what?
On whether I can
provide disabled access.
How's Bee?
Bee?
Bee.
Let me see.
You ever think maybe your
interest in darkness and evil...
No.
She's a teenager.
She seems troubled.
And she'll probably be very
successful like her father.
How much do you want for it?
Want for what?
I can help you.
You can move back to Glasgow,
get on with your lives.
I don't think my great
grandmother
- would approve.
- Ah,
so the bungalow was hers.
I take it she's no longer with
us?
Oh, no, she is.
She's buried in your back
garden.
Bee?
Tabitha.
Your great grandmother was
Mackay's maid.
You have no idea what you're
doing.
- Tell me.
- Get away from me!
What's the matter, Jenny?
It's too late.
Hey, hey, baby.
What you writing?
Right, do you remember
that time we went to Ullapool
and we kept missing everything
because we couldn't get out on
time?
The shops, the,
remember the ferry?
The whisky thing, the...
Well, I'm taking that idea,
right,
this couple who just can't seem
to do
- that they want to do...
- You're writing a play?
What if we don't sell this
place?
What if we move here
permanently?
Do it up, do the gardens,
everything, right?
You can keep teaching,
I can start writing.
Look, I know, I know it sounds
crazy.
But just think, if I can get
Jack's help,
his connections, then...
What are you doing?
What?
I'm thinking about us, about our
future.
I fucking hate teaching.
Callum, you can't stand it
here.
Yeah, but that's because I'm a
nobody.
I'm what, I'm a teacher on
sabbatical
trying to clean out his
grandmother in law's
shitty old bungalow.
It's like Damacles' sword
hanging over me.
Look, I've really got
a shot here with Jack.
- The guy's right there.
- No.
No, I don't want you going over
there.
You still haven't taken down
those sheds.
What the hell is wrong with
you?
I thought you wanted to move
back up here.
You're not a writer, Callum.
Get a grip.
Can't just suddenly do this in
the middle of us trying to...
Trying to what, Jenny?
At least I'm trying to make
something
of this awful situation.
Come on.
Come on, Alasdair, I know you're
in there.
Talk to me, talk to me!
What's the matter?
Is this where Mackay put you?
Where he starved you?
That's what you get
when you disrespect me.
I gave you everything and
you spat it back in my face!
Couldn't help yourself, could
you,
exposing your mother's shame!
Who's that?
Who's there?
Bee?
Don't come in.
Okay.
What's the matter?
Where have you been?
Why don't you want me to see
you?
You haven't missed
me.
Yes I have.
I came back to
help, but you don't want me.
Help with what?
Shit.
Hi, Jack.
Sorry, the ole' door was open.
So how's it all going?
Yeah, I know how that
feels.
The creative process, huh?
Oh, speaking of which, I was...
Eh, what are we drinking to?
You know why I bought
this place, Callum?
No.
You know what happens
when you tell people
that you own a castle?
No, what's that?
Sex and drugs.
Eh?
- I'll drink to that.
- Yeah.
So, what's with the papers?
Ah, it's just a play.
Play?
Whose play, your play?
Well, I mean, it's just
notes at the moment, but...
Well, then perform it.
Oh, no, no, no, no, it's not
finished.
Oh, you must.
A play is not for writing,
it's for performing.
Well, couldn't I just
tell you what it's about?
I don't wanna know what it's
about.
I want to experience it
live in the flesh, huh?
I wanna feel it like a cat
clawing up my clavicle,
searing my sinews, feasting
on my festering soul.
I want you to make love to my
loins with your words, Callum.
Rain death down upon my
dissident psyche.
Forget your notes, I want your
play
inside me.
Inside me the way that Jenny's
ancestors
are inside this place.
What?
You know, her great grandmother
thrown down the stairs,
used and abused.
Her great uncle left
to starve in the wall.
Please, Callum,
listen...
You lied to me, Jenny.
Please.
This is some heavy shit.
- You need counselling.
- Counselling?
I spent my entire
childhood being counselled
by everyone who had an opinion.
Exactly.
No wonder you can't look out the
window
without freaking out.
He's got no idea what he's
doing, digging up all this.
There's supposed to be
a curse on that castle,
a fricking curse.
Your great granny was
standing in this kitchen
making beef bridies
while her son starved to
death inside a fucking wall?
You wanted to find out if it's
all true,
if he's bringing it all back.
- Callum...
- Sweetheart,
you need help.
Callum, please.
He wants people to laugh at
my great grandmother's murder.
My granny, my Mum.
It gets a hold of you, it won't
let go.
Well, then, why did we move
here, then?
Because I can't bring
a child into this world
if there's still something
there.
Jenny.
Hello, what are you doing here?
I think we should have a talk.
Don't you?
Uh, have a seat, make yourself
at home.
Shouldn't be too hard.
What's on your mind, neighbour?
I need to know what you're
working on,
who it's about, what happens.
I'm afraid I can't
discuss that with you.
Will you excuse me?
We're out of coal.
Leave it.
I said we're out of coal.
Jenny.
- Callum.
- Go home.
This is between me and Jack.
Over my dead body it is.
Oh, please, I don't
want to cause any trouble.
Callum, would you be a darling
and go and fetch us some more
coal?
It's much more cheerier with a
fire.
We're not here for a soiree,
Jack.
Please!
Downstairs, I insist.
Might as well get cosy, yeah?
Bee?
So your great grandmother
was Mackay's maidservant,
the illicit mother of Alasdair
Mackay,
the devil's own tortured
servant of the night.
I suppose you don't want
me to make anything of it,
keep it in the wheelie bin.
What gives you the right to
come up here, dig up my past
and put it on display like
some gothic freak show?
I wasn't aware it was buried.
I'll tell you what I am
very interested to dig up
is why a young woman so
traumatised by her dreadful,
dreadful past would
choose to live next door
to the very place where her
family were so
affected?
It strikes me, if anybody's
digging anything up, it's you.
And what about Bee?
What does she make of all this?
There's your coal.
Let's go, Jenny.
I'm not finished.
Yes you are, let's go.
Callum, I'm not leaving.
Jenny, we're going.
Like hell we are.
Look, I don't know
what's going on here, okay,
but I don't like it, any of it.
Whatever happened to your
family here was awful.
All I know is that we need to
leave now.
What is it?
Oh, shit!
We need to go!
You wee devil.
Very good, Beleth.
You can come out now.
Nice place.
It's a little draughty.
I should write a piece on this.
Let me guess, feckless
playwright
buys Scottish castle to bolster
career.
I was thinking more tortured
artist
escapes ex-wife at castle from
hell.
Clearly I failed.
Oh, no.
You still look a little tortured
to me.
Are you gonna give me the grand
tour?
You shouldn't be here.
I'm working.
What are you working on?
- A story.
- Story.
Is it about me?
I haven't finished it yet.
You should finish it.
Get out.
Where is she?
You can't see her.
Why?
What have you done with her?
- What have I done with her?
- I'm Bee's mother.
Her mother?
Welcome home.
You call this a home?
Oh, no, no, no.
This is more than just a home.
You are full of shit, Jack
Travis.
Oh, Jack.
Shit.
You stay there, love.
What do you want, Jack?
She's, she's, she's dead.
What?
- She's dead.
- Who's dead?
- I told you,
stay in the room.
It's Beleth.
What, Bee's dead?
No.
What is it, Jack?
Kathryn, Kathryn...
Listen to me, Jack.
What the hell is going on here?
Kathryn, Kathryn.
- Who, who's dead?
- Kathryn!
She shouldn't even be here,
she should be in London.
I don't...
Where is she?
Where is she, Jack?
Jack, where is she now?
The stairs, the stairs,
the bottom of the stairs.
- We're coming over.
- I'm getting my coat.
Wait.
She's gone.
Doesn't make any sense.
Makes perfect sense.
Bee, Bee.
- Wait, hey...
- Let go of me.
Hey!
Where's Bee?
She's not here.
What do you mean, she's not
here?
Something is happening.
Damn right it is.
Something wonderful.
Where's Bee, Jack?
I'll tell you exactly what's
happening.
Someone's losing his frigging
mind.
It's not like that.
No?
Well, then where's your
ex wife's dead body?
Jack, where's Bee?
I don't know.
How long has she been missing?
Goodness sake, Jack, open your
eyes.
Look at what's happening to you.
You have to stop this.
I helped you finish
your play.
Everyone was scared.
Yes, they were.
How are you doing all of this?
Beleth?
No one will come, you
know.
Come where?
To the living play.
Why do you say that?
We need to start
again
so people will be scared for
real.
Why can't you come back,
huh, as you were?
We'll do it together.
We are doing this together.
Hi, girls.
Hi.
Where are you off to?
Seeing a friend.
- Sorry, who are you?
- Are you friends with Bee?
Um, depends what you mean by
friends.
She's in our class.
Have you heard from her?
We're not her frigging
secretary.
Bee's weird like that,
she'll just drop off the radar
for days
and then show up when she wants.
When did you last see her?
When we had a sleepover.
Did something happen?
No.
Come on.
Is Bee missing?
Just tell me what happened.
Come on, Katie.
Nice to meet you.
No, please.
Did something bad happen?
Something at the wall?
She screamed.
When she touched the wall, she
screamed.
You need to go home.
- What?
- Now.
You need to leave, go on!
- What the fuck?
- Let's just go.
Callum!
What do you want, Jack?
What do I want?
I want to be left alone
to do whatever the fuck I want.
You peasants
coming in here like you've
something important to say.
What do you want?
I want you to calm down and
listen to what I'm saying.
You being here is a problem for
me.
Callum, I thought we were
gonna work together.
You and me?
Look, we can't have all this
heavy shit
being paraded on our doorstep.
Jenny's fragile.
She needs to let go of all this.
It's not right for her to
carry that sort of pain.
Jack, there's no shame in it.
You can work on something else,
something people will
actually want to remember.
Jack, are you hearing what I'm
saying?
This has to end.
Jenny.
Jack!
Jack let me out of here now!
Get out of here.
You let me out
of here now!
Ah!
Everything we've
worked for.
I never wanted this.
You never wanted me.
What are you?
Tell me what you are!
You created me.
You are not my daughter!
Bee.
Jenny.
Oh.
Bee, wake up.
Bee, can you hear me?
Bee, Bee, oh, Bee!
Shh, you're okay.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org