A SHOCHIKU PRODUCTION
THE IDIOT
Produced by TAKASHI KOIDE
Developed by SOJIRO MOTOKI
Based on the Novel by
FYODOR M. DOSTO YEVSKY
Screenplay by EIJIRO HISAITA
and AKIRA KUROSAWA
Director of Photography
TOSHIO UBUKATA
Production Design by
TAKASHI MATSUYAMA
Music by
FUMIO HAYASAKA
Starring
SETSUKO HARA
MASAYUKI MORI
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
YOSHIKO KUGA
TAKASHI SHIMURA
CHIEKO HIGASHIYAMA
EIJIRO YANAGI, MINORU CHIAKI
NORIKO SENGOKU
KOKUTEN KODO
BOKUZEN HIDARI, EIKO MIYOSHI
CHIYOKO FUMIYA
MITSUYO AKASHI, DAISUKE INOUE
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
PART 1
LOVE AND AGONY
HOKKAIDO - DECEMBER
That was some scream.
Forgive me.
I was dreaming.
Dreaming?
Sounded like you
were being murdered.
I was...
about to be shot.
It's a recurring
nightmare of mine.
You see, I was convicted
as a war criminal
and sentenced to death.
Then why are you still alive?
My sentence was commuted
at the last minute.
They realized
they had the wrong man.
But I went crazy
from the shock.
I spent a long time
in a US military hospital.
In the south?
In Okinawa.
But I'm better now.
They put me on a boat
ten days ago.
What ails you?
Idiocy.
They call it
epileptic dementia.
I had so many fits
that I eventually became an idiot.
An idiot?
"Dostoyevsky wanted to portray
a genuinely good man.
It may seem ironic,
choosing a young idiot as his hero,
but in this world, goodness
and idiocy are often equated.
This story tells of the destruction
of a pure soul by a faithless world. "
Get up!
This man is sick!
That's all right.
Please, take your seat back.
Accept the favor, idiot!
I didn't mean it that way.
I say things like that a lot.
It's all right.
I don't mind.
Good.
Are you cold?
Yes, in fact, I am.
You're an odd one!
"Akama hadn't laughed in years.
He was the son of an old Sapporo family,
and his father's harsh discipline
had made him feel like a caged animal.
Oddly, he came to like Kameda,
who made him laugh heartily.
Akama told him about Taeko Nasu,
whom he'd met six months earlier.
One look at her had been enough
to release his pent-up passions.
He bought her a diamond ring
with money stolen from his father.
Enraged by this,
his father disowned him.
But now his father has died,
and Akama has come into his fortune.
He's returning home to Sapporo,
where Kameda is also headed
to see Mr. Ono,
his only relative in the world. "
Another snowstorm in Sapporo.
Come on, follow me.
That's her - Taeko Nasu.
What do you think?
Isn't she amazing?
Very pretty.
But -
But what?
When I look at her face,
I feel a pain in my chest.
Why?
She seems very unhappy.
Why are you crying?
I don't know. I was just looking
at her picture, and -
You really are a strange one!
I get a peculiar feeling
looking at you.
A tender feeling,
like I'm looking at a newborn lamb.
Well, I'm off.
The world's full of wolves.
Be careful.
Kameda wept upon seeing
Taeko Nasu's picture.
She was, however,
a woman of ill repute.
Rumor had it
that she'd been Tohata's
mistress since childhood.
Fearing now for his reputation,
he has offered a dowry
of 600,000 yen to marry her off.
Unbeknownst to Kameda,
her shadow now falls upon
his destination,
the Ono residence.
Dear, what do you plan
to do about Kameda?
Plan to do? Well...
he's coming all this way
in need of our help.
I'll try to find him work.
And Kayama has rooms for rent.
He can lodge there.
- Is that all?
- What do you mean?
You know,
your recent little tricks.
What's that supposed to mean?
I mean all your secrets
and funny business.
All those meetings with Tohata.
He may indeed
have a lot of influence,
but forcing his mistress
onto Kayama -
You don't understand.
It's in Kayama's best interest.
I'm glad I don't understand.
But any man who accepts
such a dirty deal isn't welcome here.
- But -
- I'll discuss it no further.
Right now I want to talk
about the idiot.
I don't like how you're taking
advantage of him.
"The army had reported
Kameda officially dead.
Kameda's father
had left him a large ranch,
which Ono sold through Kayama. "
"Kayama is now
about to marry Taeko Nasu
in exchange for the 600,000 yen.
He plays the scoundrel, but he's
really an unassertive coward,
as shown by the fact that he secretly
loves Ono's daughter Ayako. "
Good morning.
- Sleep well?
- Yes.
Am I intruding?
- Not at all.
I was just listening
to Kayama's views on life.
Taeko's birthday party is tomorrow.
Don't forget.
I know, sir.
That's good.
Mr. Tohata and I
were able to convince her
to give you
her answer at the party.
You'd better be there.
I understand.
Knock first!
Why? Discussing something
I shouldn't hear?
Mr. Kameda, lunch is ready.
"Ayako - straight-laced
and strong-willed, like her mother.
So straight-laced at times
that she turns mean. "
What would you say
if all this were yours?
- Mine?
- Would you be happy?
Yes, of course.
These cows may well be yours.
I'm afraid I don't understand.
What a beautiful path!
What's wrong?
Why do you look at me like that?
Somehow I just can't
believe you're ill.
I wish I weren't.
But I do behave oddly, don't I?
No, it's all right.
I don't mind.
People always laugh at me.
I can tell I'm odd,
but I'm not sure how.
Tell me, what are you like?
I want to know more about you.
What did you do
before the war?
- Well -
- You'd rather not say?
It's not that.
I remember the day
my life was spared,
but everything before that feels
like it happened to someone else.
Then tell me that story.
How did it feel when you
were facing certain death?
Everyone in the world
suddenly seemed so dear to me.
Everyone in the world?
Each and every person
I'd ever known.
Everyone I'd ever
passed on the street.
And not just people -
the puppy I'd thrown
a rock at as a child.
Why hadn't I been kinder?
To the puppy?
No, everyone!
I told myself
that if I were spared...
I would be kinder
and more considerate to everyone.
But I knew all was lost.
They were sure to execute me.
That thought alone...
was so unbearable
that it drove me mad.
Where on earth have you been?
Mr. Kayama's been waiting
to take you home.
Really, where did you go?
Why even ask?
She won't answer just to spite us.
Be careful.
She'll never admit it,
but she's extremely
proud of her looks.
That's why she's
so selfish and mean.
See that?
See how she glares at me?
Isn't her simmering rage becoming?
Yes, quite.
I felt the same way
when I saw Taeko Nasu.
She's also very beautiful.
Goodness!
Where did you see her?
I saw her portrait
in a photo studio near the station.
I must see it!
Say what you will.
I'm just curious.
I'd like to see it too.
I have no urge whatsoever.
I wonder.
But it's about time
I spoke to Mr. Kayama.
Would you call him?
He's in the study.
Mother!
I'm sorry not to send the girls,
but I have my reasons.
Madam sent for me?
I wonder why.
Any idea?
Not really.
I mentioned Taeko Nasu,
and then -
What?
You know her?
How?
You must have overheard us.
Did you tell them
what Mr. Ono said to me?
No, I just -
Why did you do that?
I only mentioned
her picture near the station.
Well, what's done is done.
Let's go.
Listen, I need you
to do me a big favor.
Give Miss Ayako
a letter for me.
Am I imposing?
No, but why can't you
do it yourself?
You're about to go see her.
I have my reasons.
I can't let anyone see me do it.
Besides, it's urgent.
Please.
Mr. Kayama,
Mother's in the parlor.
Mr. Kameda,
shall we go upstairs?
Mr. Kayama asked me
to give you this.
I know I often tend
to be too blunt.
Don't be offended.
I just can't abide dishonesty.
We've become like family,
so I'll speak to you
like a mother.
You're planning to marry soon,
aren't you?
No, I -
No.
No?
Are you certain about that?
Well, I -
So you won't come out
and say it.
I must say, such secrecy
about something so joyous
does make one wonder.
That's all I had to say.
Now if you'll excuse me.
I just got raked over the coals
thanks to you.
- But I -
- No excuses!
What was her reply
to my letter?
Mr. Kameda,
do you have a moment?
I'm taking you home, right?
I'll wait outside.
Please read this.
Isn't that Mr. Kayama's letter?
Yes. Now read it.
Read it to me aloud.
That's for being his messenger.
"Tomorrow my fate
will be decided.
If you still feel the friendship
for me that you once did,
simply say the word.
Tell me to call
the whole thing off,
and I will gladly do so. "
He's entering into
a sham of a marriage,
all for the sake of power
and 600,000 yen.
Now he wants me
to tell him to call it off.
He'll give up 600,000 yen
in return for my pledge of friendship.
If he'd resisted that enticement
from the outset,
I might have given him
my friendship.
But I won't!
Give him his letter back.
Tell him I won't
barter my friendship.
I won't barter my friendship.
That's my answer.
What did she say?
What's this?
Didn't you give it to her?
Yes, I did.
Then she asked me to read it.
You read it?
Then she said
to give it back to you.
She herself told you to read it?
Yes, though I didn't want to.
What an idiot!
She'd never ask you to do that.
But she did.
I have her answer too.
Well?
"I won't barter my friendship. "
That's what she said
to tell you.
"I won't barter my friendship. "
KAYAMA INN
You again!
Telling your tales here too.
Have you no shame?
- You're one to talk.
- Takako!
Apologize to Mr. Kameda.
You're the one acting strangely.
That's why I sent for him.
So he told you everything,
the little -
What are you saying?
He just came in this minute.
I'm just worried about
what tonight holds in store.
Who but Kameda
would blab about that?
It was me.
That's right.
Tell me, why -
- Why marry another man's mistress?
- No.
She's not my concern.
It's you I'm worried about.
I want to know your feelings.
Why marry like this?
That's easy.
He's sick of being poor.
- You hush!
I can't stand it anymore!
You're a worthless fool!
What?
I dare you to repeat that.
I will.
Any number of times.
You're a worthless fool,
and so is she.
If you bring that woman here,
I'll leave home.
I couldn't care less.
Don't think it ends here.
There's more:
I wrote her and told her
everything I just told you.
You bitch!
Takako, run!
What is it? You look like
you've just seen a ghost.
Go announce me.
Wait!
Who are you going
to announce?
What a strange man!
Taeko Nasu.
How do you know me?
I...
Never mind.
Just announce me.
I'll marry her,
no matter what anyone says!
It's worth it just to see
that look on your face!
Miss Taeko Nasu is here.
Your entryway is freezing.
I let myself in.
Why on earth
do you look so pale?
Introduce me.
My younger sister.
Miss Taeko Nasu.
My mother.
How do you do.
I'm glad you came.
Are you really?
How foolish of me.
I thought perhaps
a woman like me
wouldn't be welcome
in such a magnificent home.
I don't -
- Mother.
- Go make some tea.
Might I have a seat as well?
Please do.
Don't be a nuisance!
We have visitors!
My father.
Miss Taeko Nasu.
Jumpei Kayama...
a former soldier,
dishonorably discharged.
Fifty years old,
with nothing to show for it.
Allow me to introduce Mr. Kameda,
a very interesting fellow.
A relative of Mr. Ono's.
Forgive me.
I took you for a servant.
Not at all. I -
But how do you know me?
And why did you look
so surprised
when you saw me?
I felt...
as if I'd seen your eyes
somewhere before.
So it's true!
Which of you is my rival?
What are you doing here?
Who are all of you?
Him?
Who are you?
I'm Denkichi Akama,
and I'm rich as hell!
I can buy and sell the likes of you!
- Get out of here!
Are you really
going to marry him?
Now I remember you.
You gave me
a diamond ring once.
But why...
are you asking
these questions?
How does my marriage
to that man concern you?
I'll pay you 600,000 yen
to give her up.
What are you saying?
You must be drunk.
700,000!
No, 800,000!
You fool!
Leave or I'll call the police!
Damn it!
One million yen!
By tonight.
Have one million ready
by 9:00 tonight.
So suddenly my price
has shot up by 400,000 yen?
Insolent bastard!
Father!
He's made you look
even more foolish!
You shut up!
I will not! Not while we're being
disgraced like this!
Either kick her out
or I will!
Bitch!
That's enough.
Stay out of this!
Let me go!
Stupid brother!
It's all right.
You should be ashamed!
That man is a lamb!
It was nothing.
Nothing at all.
You're not
that kind of person.
That's not who you are.
What he said
about me is true.
Can you forgive me?
Good-bye, Mr. Kayama.
I'll see you tonight.
Please come along too,
Mr. Kameda.
What's the matter?
Why are you neglecting your guests?
You look pale.
Do you have a fever?
Why else would I sit
bundled up here by myself?
Why not rest a while?
There's something
I must tell you.
You're very kind,
but I prefer to keep drinking.
What's wrong, everyone?
Enjoy yourselves.
A Mr. Kameda has arrived.
Mr. Kameda.
He met Taeko at my place today.
I asked you to bring him.
Why didn't you?
Show him in.
Why him of all people?
You mean,
because he's an idiot?
I don't believe he is.
On the contrary...
he may be a good deal
more astute than either of you.
Especially at seeing
into another person's heart.
Now do you see?
How dare you!
I just -
Do you know how much
that vase was worth?
Let me ask you:
Didn't you give those vases to me?
Then let me do
with them as I wish.
I meant
to smash them anyway.
I won't bother
with introductions.
There's no one here
worthy of it.
What a thing to say!
Fortunately,
we've already met.
What's wrong?
Why are you staring like that?
Really...
what's the matter?
It just came to me.
I was sure I'd seen
eyes like yours before.
I just remembered where.
Eyes like mine?
How could I not remember?
What was the person like?
He and I faced
a firing squad together.
There were three posts.
We were to be shot
three at a time.
I was the fifth man
in the second row of prisoners.
I was to be
in the fourth group killed.
Just minutes before I was to die,
an order came down for a retrial.
I never dreamt
I would walk away alive.
And the man
with eyes like mine?
He was in the first group
to be shot.
He was barely 20 years old,
with the face of a boy.
He seemed as if in a trance,
tied there to that post.
Suddenly he began
to tremble.
He looked over at us,
his eyes filled with reproach.
They were the eyes of a man
who had suffered alone,
day and night,
for a very long time.
They seemed...
to be crying out,
"Why must I suffer like this?"
What torment
he must have endured!
His eyes seemed ready
to burst and spew blood.
I forgot that I too
was about to be shot.
I looked away.
At times...
your eyes are exactly like his.
And then?
What happened to him?
And then...
shots rang out.
I looked up.
There he was,
limp as a rag.
That's enough!
This is absurd!
This is supposed to be a birthday party!
Please be quiet.
Do you even care
that it's my birthday?
Mr. Kameda...
the fact is...
I've been asked
to marry Mr. Kayama.
I'm supposed to give him
my answer tonight.
Should I marry him or not?
What should I do?
- Taeko!
- This is outrageous!
I'll do whatever you say.
- Are you mad?
- This is serious!
Mr. Kameda,
please tell me.
Why are you asking him?
Who is he to you?
Don't you understand?
He trusted me
from the moment he met me.
That's why I trust him.
So tell me.
Please tell me.
Don't do it.
Don't marry him.
Then I won't.
Did you hear that,
Mr. Kayama?
That's my answer.
This is absurd!
What about the promise
you made just days ago?
Mr. Tohata,
what on earth is going on?
Oh, I see!
You're pleased about all this.
What?
It's obvious you're loath
to part with your treasure.
I look like a fool.
You?
I'm the one
who looks like a fool!
This is all your doing.
Friends shouldn't quarrel.
Mr. Ono, Mr. Kayama...
don't try to blame Mr. Tohata.
I have no intention
of going back to him.
Why that face?
You needn't pay anything
to be free of me.
You can put away
your 600,000 yen.
This house, and everything in it -
you can have it all back!
Taeko!
I'm leaving here tonight...
with nothing.
No, Taeko!
I was wrong.
I've been such a fool.
I've had enough.
I'm no longer...
your 14-year-old mistress.
Listen to me.
I swear to you.
I don't care anymore
what the world thinks.
I'll marry you.
Don't flatter yourself!
To think I'd ever marry you!
Who are you?
What is this?
One million yen.
So you kept your promise?
Thank you.
This man raised
a million yen to pay for me.
That's 400,000 more than you.
- Fool!
No, I'm tired of putting on airs!
As of tomorrow I'm penniless.
Who would take in
a penniless woman,
and another man's
castoff no less?
Right, Mr. Kayama?
Why ask me?
Isn't Mr. Kameda your confidant?
I...
I would take you in.
What did you just say?
I said I would take you in.
A woman like me?
The way I am?
Yes.
But what do you mean,
"A woman like me?"
I don't understand.
Why do you all laugh?
I guess I didn't phrase it well.
All I meant to say...
is that Miss Nasu
is very pure.
Stop it, you idiot!
How dare you mock me?
I really am sick.
My brain's gone bad.
I guess that's why
it didn't come out right.
But I said
what I honestly feel.
I don't care how much
people laugh at me.
I believe
you're a pure woman.
You just said you'd leave here
and give everything up.
That says it all.
That's enough for me.
And I'll let no one
speak ill of you.
So why feel ashamed?
Why sell yourself to him
for a million yen?
Butt out!
I won't remain silent.
You've suffered alone
for so long...
that it feels wrong
if you're not in pain.
You are ill.
You need a kind nurse.
I'll nurse you back to health.
She's accustomed to luxury.
How will you support her?
You're penniless yourself.
I'll find work somehow.
Listen to him!
What, shoveling snow?
For that you'd make
about 300 yen.
Not even enough
to buy her cosmetics.
That's enough!
Stop ridiculing him.
Thank you.
No one's ever said
anything like that to me before.
Miss Taeko...
I...
Somehow, I'll -
When I first saw your picture...
you seemed
to be calling to me.
You see...
I've been waiting
for somebody like you.
Ever since I began
this awful life as a kept woman,
I've been waiting.
I hoped and prayed...
imagining someone like you.
Hoping...
that a good, honest,
kind man would appear.
"Taeko, it's not your fault.
I still respect you. "
How I longed
to hear those words!
But instead it was
always just him.
He'd do lewd and shameful
things to me and then leave.
I can't take it anymore.
I'd rather die in the street...
than go on living like this.
Yet...
I'm afraid...
the life you envision for us...
is a fairy tale.
Everyone,
I have an announcement.
Actually,
it's more of a confession.
In truth...
I'm an utterly despicable man.
Until this moment,
I've hidden the fact
that Mr. Kameda possesses
a considerable fortune.
As his relative,
I thought it was in his best interest.
Anyway...
I wish to announce that Mr. Kameda
is the owner of a 125-acre farm.
Get back!
You really feel
that way about her?
Don't be ridiculous.
What?
So you mean you'll -
Isn't it obvious?
I'm going with you.
Taeko!
A man like him?
Get lost!
I can't...
I can't ruin the life
of an innocent child like you.
Out of the way!
Hey, don't forget this -
the million yen.
I worked hard
to scrape it together.
Everyone stay back!
I give it to Mr. Kayama.
Pull it out with your bare hands
and it's yours!
It's burning!
A million yen!
I wrapped it with my own hands!
Be quiet!
Let me go!
Mr. Kayama,
don't just stand there.
Hurry or it'll all burn.
What's the matter?
Don't you want it now?
Please have mercy!
It's all burning!
You little worm!
Take a good look.
That's how we do things!
Mr. Kayama, drop the act...
or you'll regret it later.
Pull it out, man!
What's a little pride?
Hurry!
It's all burning!
It'll burn up! Hurry!
It's safe.
A few thousand yen
got burned, that's all.
Move!
Listen, everybody.
This is all for Mr. Kayama.
He didn't pull it out.
He would have let it burn.
It's his by right.
Is that clear?
And now,
farewell to you all.
Out of the way!
Farewell, Mr. Kameda.
Come on, men!
Time to drink!
Kameda, don't go after her!
She's a fallen woman!
You can't save her!
Kameda!
FEBRUARY
Ayako,
don't play with your food.
And why are you all so quiet?
You've all been acting
so strange lately.
It's the weather.
Weeks without sun.
Everybody gets depressed.
It's not the weather, that much I know.
It's that man.
I really misjudged him.
Why give him the ranch if he's going
to spend his money on that hussy?
But -
And what bothers me
the most is how you did it.
Wasn't there
a more straightforward way?
Why bring that Karube in
as an agent?
And you, acting so secretively,
as if you were the guilty one!
And Kameda could have at least
stopped by to thank you.
Perhaps he's an idiot after all.
What's so funny?
It's just -
That again?
That's all you seem to say.
It's just that Ayako -
She's up to something again.
Some fine young ladies you are.
Out with it.
What's going on?
Mr. Kameda sent her
a strange letter.
A letter? When?
Kayama's brother gave it to her
last week at the skating rink.
Little Kaoru? Not surprising,
given his older brother.
But Kameda's in Tokyo.
How is that possible?
It was enclosed
in a package to Kayama.
What was in the letter?
"I have no idea
why I'm writing to you like this.
But I simply cannot
suppress the hope
that perhaps
you remember me fondly.
For reasons I don't understand,
you're very important to me,
extremely important.
I have nothing else to write
about myself, nor any desire to do so.
I wish you every happiness. "
What's so funny?
You're laughing at the letter -
do you know why?
Because there's not a single lie in it.
It's so honest that it's funny.
Not laughing now, are you?
Well, well.
You lost that one, didn't you?
But why did he send it?
Have you heard
any more gossip about our idiot?
It seems he and that roughneck Akama
are both still chasing Taeko.
Taeko, being who she is,
swings like a pendulum
from one to the other.
She agreed to marry Akama
but then ran away
with Kameda.
Things are bound to end badly.
Did you forget something?
No, but I felt
I was being watched.
You mean
murder or something?
Akama's not above it.
Stop that.
It's too morbid to think about.
Come in.
Don't bother
taking off your shoes.
Watch your step here.
What's wrong with you?
Stop staring at me like that.
Sit down.
Akama, I want you
to tell me the truth.
Was that you at the station?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I glimpsed a pair of eyes
in the crowd exactly like yours.
I wonder who it was.
Maybe I was just
imagining things.
That happens to me a lot.
What a dark room!
It's an old house.
I could tell from a block away
that this was your house.
How?
I just knew
your house would be like this.
It really is dark.
There's something
dark and gloomy about you too.
Will you two live here
after you marry?
Of course.
This is my home.
Is the wedding soon?
You know I can't decide
a thing like that on my own.
Akama, please don't hide
anything from me.
I have no intention
of standing in your way.
She's back in Sapporo too,
isn't she?
You've come to an agreement,
haven't you?
What if we have?
Is that what you came
to find out?
No.
But I honestly feel it's best
for you two not to marry.
I've said so many times.
It would mean ruin
for her and for you.
But there's nothing
I can do to stop you.
You understand, don't you?
I simply feel sorry for her.
Everything she does
worries me.
I can't just sit by and watch.
We discussed this in Tokyo,
didn't we?
I simply want her
to be happy, that's all.
Why are you
glaring at me like that?
I'll be going now.
Good-bye.
Stay.
It's been a while.
The minute you leave,
I know I'll start hating you again.
You made me boil for a month
after we parted in Tokyo.
I wanted to poison you.
It's true.
But ten minutes in your presence
and my anger evaporates...
and amazingly,
I like you as much as ever.
You're a strange one.
We're opposites
in so many ways.
Have a drink.
Now listen.
You love her
because you feel sorry for her.
But I hate her
as much as I love her!
Sometimes I think
it'd be easier if she were dead.
She hates me too,
with all her might!
Once I beat her black and blue
for the way she looks down on me.
You didn't!
Yes, I did!
I sat outside her door for two days
without eating or drinking to apologize.
I terrified the maid at the inn.
She stopped coming to the room.
Taeko finally got fed up
and came out.
Know what she said?
"What would you do
if I never forgave you?"
I told her over and over
that I would die.
Then she said,
"You'll probably kill me first. "
When I saw her here in Sapporo
about a week ago, she said,
"I've made up my mind.
I'm an outcast anyway,
so I'll do as you say.
But I want to be free
just a little longer...
until I've had
my fill of freedom. "
What do you think?
I don't understand it.
Are you sure?
Want me to spell it out?
She's in love
with another man,
and that man is you!
It's the hand of fate!
She can never marry you.
Why? Because she doesn't
want to ruin you!
So she'll ruin me and drag me
down to hell with her!
What a thing to say!
You're just imagining things.
It's simply jealousy.
Stop that!
I shouldn't have come
if my being here makes you
think these thoughts.
Something told me
not to come,
but I wanted us
to part on good terms.
I wanted our memories of Sapporo
to be pleasant ones.
You use that
for cutting paper?
Yes.
But it's not
a paper knife, is it?
It's a butcher's knife.
But there's no law
against cutting paper with it.
I suppose not.
But...
it looks brand-new.
You saying I can't
afford a new knife?
What got into me?
When my head
starts to get heavy,
I say and do things
without even realizing it.
It's been getting worse lately.
Maybe it's a sign
of an approaching fit.
Well, please excuse me.
Be well.
It's not safe.
I'll go with you.
What's that?
My mother. She prays
to the Buddha every day.
And you?
Do you ever pray?
I mean,
do you believe in a god?
Not really.
I was made
to pray as a child.
That's how my mother is.
I always had to carry an amulet.
I still do, in my wallet.
I carry a sort of charm too.
It's just a plain stone.
A stone?
It's nothing special,
but it has great meaning for me.
I told you, right?
About my death sentence?
How the shock of being
pardoned drove me insane?
Just then I went into a trance
and picked up this stone.
It's still precious to me.
You have it now?
Show it to me.
Can I keep it?
What for?
I don't know.
I'd just like to have it.
I'll trade you my amulet for it.
You want to swap charms?
I remember doing that
with friends as a boy.
Let's have tea with Mother.
Mother, this is Mr. Kameda,
a very close friend.
Make us some tea.
Tea!
Relax.
She's oblivious to everything -
even what a useless bum I am.
Right, Mother?
She seems to like you.
She'll share the cake offering with you.
Eat it.
It'll make her happy.
Well...
We don't need to shake hands.
We've already exchanged charms.
All right, take her!
It's the only way!
I'm giving her to you!
Don't forget me!
What was it I saw
that shone so?
END OF PART 1
PART 2
LOVE AND LOATHING
The juvenile delinquent!
So you don't like
being called that?
How about postman?
Messenger boy? Errand boy?
Cat got your tongue?
It shows you know it's wrong
to deliver strange letters to young ladies.
But you were quite tactful
with today's delivery.
Anyway, stop gaping
and tell me:
Where's Mr. Kameda hospitalized?
Or is he asleep inside?
He's come to already.
People can recover that easily?
Disappointed?
Nice try, but you won't
get even that way.
But I was a fool,
rushing to get here.
Then go home.
That's enough.
I'll do as I please.
Mr. Kameda, you're really
quite an ingrate.
Not so loud.
He's not well.
I know that.
That's why I'm letting him off easy.
Didn't you go too far
about the ranch?
Sending this man
to our house
like some kind
of debt collector!
What did you do,
Mr. Karube?
Well, you see,
you have a right
to what's yours.
A right?
Just what did you do?
Well, I never!
You really don't know?
May I ask who's paying
all your expenses?
This may sound
quite forward of me,
but Mr. Ono said I owned
the rights to a large ranch.
Mr. Karube said he'd lend me money
with the ranch as collateral.
This is outrageous!
He said he was your agent
and forced my husband to pay.
Just like my husband,
to be fooled by such a man!
You can't run away!
I'll be filing a formal complaint!
Please, don't be rash.
I intended all along
to settle accounts fairly.
Bilk this poor innocent of one penny
and you'll settle them from a jail cell.
Step outside, please.
I have something
to discuss with Mr. Kameda.
You really are something.
No, I can't say any more.
One look at you
and the words melt away.
I'm not mocking you.
In fact, it's your -
forgive me -
it's your dimwittedness
that's almost mocking. I mean -
Just what do I mean?
What got me going like this?
Ah, that's right.
It's time I asked after you.
How are you feeling?
Much better.
Still, please be careful.
You're quite pale.
Are you still on your own?
Married yet?
No.
What are you grinning about?
Of course
I was being sarcastic.
Anyway, I'm here for a reason.
I must ask you something.
What is it?
I read your letter to Ayako.
What was the meaning of that?
It was such a fine day
when I wrote it.
I didn't ask
about the weather!
I know, but on such
a bright, sunny day,
a man burns with hope.
What kind of hope?
For Ayako?
Are you in love with her?
No.
Are you sure?
I think so.
See?
You're not sure at all.
But I wonder
how she feels about you.
She has more disdain
for you than praise.
She calls you
an invalid and an idiot.
But don't be offended.
She really takes after me -
willful with a touch of craziness.
If she likes someone,
she'll call him names and tease him.
But don't get
your hopes up just yet.
It's a constant worry
having grown-up daughters.
Did you hear
about Mr. Kayama?
No.
What about him?
He has "hopes"
regarding Ayako as well.
He regained her trust
after that incident with the money.
Giving it back to Taeko
was a real masterstroke.
But be that as it may -
Oh, yes, I'd better give him
a talking-to as well.
Take good care of yourself.
By the way, I'd rather
you didn't come visit for a while.
Especially not on a nice day.
You get my drift?
Yes.
Ayako already
forbade me to visit.
What? When?
She wrote back to me
while I was in Tokyo.
That postman again!
Postman?
Never mind.
What did she write?
"There's no hope at all.
I have no wish
to ever see you again. "
That was the gist of it.
Knowing her, it could mean there's hope
and that she wants to see you.
I'll feel her out
and get to the bottom of this!
Leaving already, Mrs. Ono?
Is your family well?
Won't you stay for tea?
It's so cold.
What did Mrs. Ono
say to you in the hallway?
I think I can guess.
You went completely red in the face.
Then don't ask.
Why are you acting like this?
Still holding a grudge?
I'm on your side,
especially in this matter.
What matter?
Still playing dumb?
She warned you about Ayako, right?
It makes me so mad.
Does she think we're beneath her?
I'm merely their employee.
You don't really mean that.
So don't be like this.
Pull yourself together.
Ayako's just shy.
That's why she acts so crazy.
It's just a smoke screen.
- Is that from Kameda's room?
- Yes.
Kaoru's putting on his costume
for the ice carnival.
Kameda seems
in a good mood.
Be careful.
Mrs. Ono gave him
a talking-to as well.
And then she rushed out.
Something's definitely going on.
- They're all crazy.
- Mother!
Who are you looking for?
Don't worry. The invalid
won't dare come out in this cold.
- Who's that fool?
- He's a clown.
It's me, the postman!
I hope he falls!
Be careful!
Laugh all you want.
You'll pay later.
You too, Ayako.
You ridicule me no end.
What were you two
whispering about?
Spit it out!
What did the postman tell you?
Good evening.
I looked all over.
I thought you'd be here.
Good evening.
Kaoru just told me
you were here.
Let's go over there.
My feet are frozen
from standing still.
You little liar!
It's hideous!
What were they thinking?
I'm going.
Enough of this nonsense!
I knew it!
Why do you stare like that?
Can't you greet a person?
Let's go over there.
Mother, go on without me.
Mr. Kayama will see me home.
What are you doing here?
Don't be too smug.
You have no right.
Have you forgotten what you
were willing to do for 600,000 yen?
Was that her?
I want to ask you something.
Be here tomorrow at noon.
Come along.
How dare she insult us!
Noriko, come on!
Tough luck, huh?
You have no business
being here.
Aren't you angry at me
after what I did?
We traded charms.
Of course I trust you.
Well, I'm no good.
Do you know Taeko
wants you to marry Ayako?
But a lot of good
that does me!
She wants you to be happy.
That means
she loves you after all!
What? You fell asleep?
You actually fell asleep?
Oh, it's you.
I must have dozed off.
Didn't someone else
try to wake me?
I thought
another woman was here.
I must have dreamt it.
Yes, it was a dream.
I see.
You mean her, don't you?
What did you dream
about her?
No, I don't want to know!
But why did you fall asleep?
Really!
Look at that!
Doesn't it look silly?
It seemed
so impressive last night.
Why on earth
did I come here?
You made me promise
to meet you here.
I have no use for men
who fall asleep like that.
I didn't get
any sleep last night.
Mr. Kayama attempted suicide.
- Wasn't he just pretending?
- You may be right.
In that case,
I'll go easy on you.
I'll get to the point.
Do you know why
I asked to meet you here?
Because I can't stand it
when people make fun of you.
You're a bit -
I'll be frank.
At times your illness
makes you seem comical.
But in wisdom,
the most important thing,
you're far ahead
of everyone else.
Wisdom comes in two kinds:
Important and unimportant.
But nobody realizes that.
No, actually Mother does.
And I do too,
but we're different.
I've waited a long time
for a chance to tell you this.
Remember that letter
you sent me?
Ever since then -
no, even before that -
But why did you chase
after that woman?
I'll bet you even
came back for her!
I detest you!
I love Mr. Kayama.
- That's a lie.
- No, it's true!
Ask this bench.
We often meet here.
Another lie.
So what if it is?
Anyway, he's completely changed.
To prove it, he cut off his finger
right before my eyes.
Which hand?
What's the difference?
He cut it off!
I saw his hands last night.
They looked just fine.
Tell me the truth.
You're crazy about Taeko,
aren't you?
Yes, but not
in the way you think.
How would you know
what I think?
Let me rephrase that.
My feelings for her
are a mystery to me,
so I assumed
you wouldn't understand either.
What would you do
if your closest friend,
as close as a sibling,
were thrown in a cage
and brutally beaten?
You'd be miserable.
You'd wish to be beaten
instead, right?
Whenever I see her,
that's how I feel.
Perhaps you can't
understand her pain.
But I do.
No, you only know
that she was a kept woman...
that it began when she was only a child,
and that it traumatized her.
But there's more
to her unhappiness than that.
If you take a piece of candy
from a sensitive child,
she'll throw a tantrum
and stomp on the candy she has left.
That's how she is.
It drives me mad
to think how things might be
if she weren't like that.
She thinks her happiness
will always be tainted by that wound,
so she crushes whatever
happiness comes her way.
- I can't take it anymore!
- What do you mean?
Don't you know?
She wrote to me three times.
Wrote to you?
Here's one of her letters.
She insists I marry you.
She cajoles, entices,
and even pleads with me.
Last night too.
Mr. Kayama got
in the way between us,
and look how she behaved!
I've never seen
anyone so presumptuous!
Try to forgive her.
As I said before -
No, I can't think as you do.
It's all here in her letter.
She feigns a stupid sentimentality,
saying she wants to see you happy.
Don't say that!
Either that or she's jealous -
or even worse!
She's not uniting us,
she's dividing us!
- You can't believe that.
- I certainly do!
You certainly what?
Ayako asked me
to meet her there.
I got there at noon
and then fell asleep.
You what?
I fell asleep while waiting.
Well, I never!
Just how do you feel
about Ayako?
Feel about her?
Do you like her, or what?
I like her a lot.
Then how you could
fall asleep is beyond me.
Fine.
Don't bother to explain.
But assure me of one thing.
Did anything happen
that might make a mother worry?
I don't think so.
Then you can meet again.
But not outside - she catches cold easily.
Come visit her
at our home if you wish -
but come in
through the front door!
You really are a mystery.
You suddenly show up...
during a blizzard
to pay a visit.
Nothing you do
ever fails to surprise.
You know how, in late March,
the clouds suddenly part after a blizzard?
Blue skies,
then a sudden crack of thunder.
That's exactly how you are.
I can't stand it!
You sat with her like this
when you went away.
And you talked about me,
didn't you?
Leave right now!
And never come back!
I'm like a bride-to-be
sealed up
and on display in a bottle.
Then it's straight
from bottle to altar.
I can't stand it!
Let's take a trip together!
Why do you come here
every day?
Don't you realize
everyone's laughing at you?
And I'm sick of seeing
your face every day.
I sometimes say
terrible things to you, don't I?
Are you going
to hold it against me...
later on?
Another letter from her!
It's shameful!
She says she'll marry
when we do.
What is it?
You look pale.
That upsets you, doesn't it?
Don't worry.
I'd never marry you, no matter what!
Why are you all laughing
at Mr. Kameda?
What's so funny about him
bringing me carnations?
- No one's laughing.
- Liar!
You deliberately
set them in front of me
and then smirked
at Mr. Kayama.
We always put flowers
in the center.
Calm down.
Don't get upset over nothing.
It's not nothing to me.
Mr. Kameda is more noble
than anyone here.
He has a better nature...
and a purer heart.
Yet you all
make fun of him!
And of me too.
Are you crying?
No, certainly not.
But why is it so funny
that he brought me carnations?
Well, they're red!
It's absurd!
Why?
You don't know?
Red carnations mean -
Right, Mr. Kayama?
I'll ask Mr. Kayama.
Answer me clearly.
What makes red carnations so funny?
I guess... it's because
red carnations signify love.
I didn't know that.
I just thought -
Just a moment.
Even if he brought them
knowing full well
what they meant,
it wouldn't seem funny to me.
I'd be delighted
and accept them gratefully.
Ayako!
What's it matter anyway?
That language of flowers is foreign.
It doesn't apply in Japan.
But what if it did?
He just got through saying
he didn't know.
Isn't that right?
- Yes.
But it's true that I love her.
Well, that could mean a lot of things.
Surely you're not proposing to her!
I...
I am.
This is -
Right, Satoko?
I won't allow it.
I simply won't.
I'd like to speak
with him in private.
We certainly didn't expect this.
How did this come about?
Father, Mother would like
to see you.
Wait here and think it over,
all right?
Look at her.
The poor child!
But -
We have no choice
but to let her follow her heart.
But of all people!
I know,
but deep in my heart,
I feel she's made
the right choice.
No, don't look.
You mustn't see
my face right now.
But what an expression.
What do you mean?
I see your reflection
in the window.
I think I know
why you look so sad.
You mustn't say it!
But it needs to be said.
There's someone
standing between us.
Don't say it!
Please get up.
Are you happy?
That's all I need to know.
What did she say?
I understand.
I'm so glad.
Then this will be
the last time we meet.
Farewell.
We're leaving tomorrow.
We'll probably
never meet again.
Why didn't you
answer her question?
Are you happy or not?
I see.
Of course you can't answer.
We just had an unexpected guest -
Miss Ayako.
No, not for you.
You get your hopes up
so easily.
Last night you seemed pleased
about their engagement.
She's here to see Kameda?
You need to ask?
Of course she is.
What a slap in the face!
They just went out
together in the storm.
Are you afraid
to take me to her?
No, but still I'm worried.
Don't worry.
I just want to see for myself.
I want to understand her
the way you do.
No, just listen.
Last night I thought and thought,
and it finally hit me.
If I talk to her,
it might clear everything up.
I may even come to like her.
- Is she inside?
- Yes.
But I -
Frightened of a mere girl?
Yes, I am.
I'm afraid to even look at her.
She's everything
I ever dreamed of being.
She possesses...
everything I've ever lost.
She represents...
an ideal for me.
That's why...
I wrote to her.
I want her...
to have the kind of life
I dreamed of.
But -
But if you meet her,
you may not like her.
Please, let's go back.
I'm afraid.
What's wrong?
Why that look?
You're pale too.
This is important for us.
I won't be impetuous
like I usually am.
I assume you're fully aware...
of why I asked to see you.
No, I'm afraid I'm not.
Yes, you are.
What would I possibly gain
by pretending?
Very well.
Never mind that.
But there seems to be
a misunderstanding.
I didn't come here
to quarrel with you...
but I'm also not the sort
to let things pass unnoticed.
I came to give you
a reply to your letters.
But first there's something
I'd like to ask.
Do you have any idea...
what sort of person
Mr. Kameda is?
I certainly do.
I daresay I know
far better than you.
That's a lie!
You couldn't possibly know.
Why not?
Because you only ever
think of yourself.
Drunk on your own misery,
you don't see
the grief you cause others.
If you really
understood Mr. Kameda,
you wouldn't subject him
to such ridicule.
I don't recall ever
subjecting him to ridicule.
Then why did you
walk out on him?
He's a simple man.
You deceived and mistreated him.
Ayako!
Look at him.
Even now
he's trying to defend you.
I've never met a man
with a heart so big and so pure.
That's why I love him
with all my soul.
Is that all
you came to say?
No, there's still
the most important thing:
My reply
to your obnoxious letters.
I'll be frank.
You have no right
to meddle in our affairs.
Stop coming between us!
Stop playing the martyr
at our expense!
You act as if you're
Violetta from La Traviata!
You mustn't say that!
You were right.
How could I have been
such a fool?
For some reason I imagined
this jealous little princess
to be some kind of angel.
Listen to me, young lady.
You don't even know yourself
why you came here, do you?
Shall I tell you why?
You wanted to see
what it is you're afraid of.
What would I be afraid of?
Me, of course.
You're terrified
that he might love me more.
That's why you're here.
You're wrong.
It's pity he feels for you,
not love.
It amounts to the same thing.
But I know I have no right
to accept his love.
That's why I -
No, enough of this!
Take your precious man and go!
I can't bear to look at you.
But know that you're the one
causing him all this suffering!
Now go! Take him away!
Get out of here!
Now!
No, I've changed my mind.
We'll fight for him.
Are you ready?
I'll command him
to leave you...
and he'll abandon you
and stay with me forever.
He'll marry me...
and you'll go home alone
and in tears.
Is that what you want?
Is it?
Mr. Kameda,
which of us will you choose?
No, I'll never
let you go again.
Say you'll marry me!
Please, don't do this!
Are you ready?
If he refuses to take my hand
and say he's leaving you,
then you win.
In that case, you can take him away.
I have no need of him.
Now then:
Which of us will it be?
How did it ever come to this?
Please, please...
you mustn't blame her.
She's so...
deeply unhappy.
Are you going after her?
Are you?
I'll take care of things here.
You go after Ayako.
Ayako hasn't come home!
You took her to see that woman
and didn't escort her home
in this blizzard!
Please hurry!
Ayako came to our house
with a raging fever.
I ran here because
the phone wasn't working.
We'll be right there!
Listen here:
It's all over.
I've had enough of you.
AKAMA RESIDENCE
Come with me.
I have to talk to you.
Is she at your place?
Yes.
Was that you peeking out at me?
Has she been there all this time?
I told you:
Don't walk so close to me.
Remember:
You never saw me here.
It's very cold.
Won't you light the stove?
No, I can't.
Why not?
I had to see you,
no matter what.
Really?
So I was right.
I got that feeling somehow,
so I came looking for you.
You've been on my mind a lot.
I thought I'd bring you here
so we could talk through the night.
Is she asleep in there?
That's right.
Want to look?
Listen -
No, never mind.
Go in.
It's so dark here.
You'll see enough.
You're trembling like a leaf.
Careful you don't have
another fit.
Did you... do that?
Yes.
What do you intend
to do now?
I don't get it.
Why are you trembling like that?
Anyway, let's spend
the night here.
I'm hot.
It's hot, isn't it?
What?
I thought you were cold.
Listen! Do you hear
someone in the hall?
I don't hear anything.
You see?
She's sleeping in there.
She's not going anywhere.
She's all ours now.
We won't let some worthless fool
take her, will we?
Let's take turns keeping watch.
She has a beautiful body!
Take a look in the morning.
I spent all day by her side.
I've never seen
such a beautiful woman.
But I'm worried
she may start to smell.
The stove was lit earlier.
You smell anything?
I don't think so.
I wish we had
flowers to offer.
Mother always has some
on the family altar,
but she'd notice
if any were missing.
Shall I go buy some?
Let's bury her
in lots of different flowers.
No, that would be too sad.
Oh, right!
There's something I wanted to ask.
How did you kill her?
Did you use that knife?
Yes, the butcher's knife.
Wait a minute.
There are other things
I want to ask.
Lots of things.
Tell me everything.
I went rushing off, right?
Is that when you did it?
Right after that.
The knife was on the desk.
But something puzzles me.
It went in three inches -
no, even deeper -
right around here...
but hardly any blood came out.
You know why?
I can explain that.
It's called internal bleeding.
Listen!
You hear that?
Yes!
Footsteps!
You hear that?
Someone's outside.
I hear it.
Someone's walking around.
That's right.
Amazing!
Look at that cloud!
It's like a rainbow.
Look how strangely it shines!
It's coming this way!
It's coming!
It's racing toward us.
And she's riding on it!
She's laughing!
Mother's there too.
They're here!
Hurry, get on!
Someone come quickly!
You hear that thunder?
Even the weather's gone crazy.
I hate having
to visit the sick.
Ayako, do something for him.
He's terrified.
I told him not to come.
And he's in middle school, no less.
What could be so frightening
about that idiot?
Kaoru, come with me.
Poor thing.
I feel so sorry for him.
No matter what anyone says,
he was a fine person.
He was too good
for this world.
Even that worthless Karube came,
flowers in hand.
He actually had
tears in his eyes.
I don't want to talk about it.
I promised you...
I'd keep an eye on him
and tell you what he was doing.
But it was too -
Was it that awful?
All I know
is that I'll remember
what a good man he was.
If only we could all
love as he did...
without hatred.
What a fool I've been.
I was the idiot.
THE END
Translation by KERIM YASAR
for SUBTEXT SUBTITLING