They then looked like a womanizer.
They did not like.
The week I left, things got worse.
My parents insulted me, something for nothing normal about them.
And it all ended one afternoon, very bad.
You leave me at age 19 and not me ...
I talk to my parents for 15 years.
Whatever ... That's the story.
Recently my parents looked for me on the Internet.
They demanded to know their grandchildren.
Spend a week with them.
I researched my parents and have a help page.
People love them.
Ironically, advise people, that's what I heard.
Whatever, I told the boys and said they wanted to see them.
I told them I did not want them to be ...
and said they would go anyway.
Are brats what can I say?
And my 15 year old daughter, wants to make a documentary about this.
Wait, wait, go back, huh ...
Describes the events of the day you left ...
Farm your parents, at age 19.
I did not choose to tell you something.
If they want to tell, they are entitled okay?
I want to do this for you.
Hey, they're good people.
Just ask them.
What has already finished my part? I have yet to help them pack.
I am chatting with two girls separately.
Clarifies that the word "separate".
Not going to be that we believe are twins.
Explain that you are chatting.
- Communicating, nothing more. - No, they are on the waiting list.
You're 13, how they are waiting lists?
I saw him in the shower, he does have to wait.
And you do not have boobs!
Stop and the two!
And I need to chat.
It's a week, your phone will not work there.
You will return home on Saturday.
Are you holding the camera right?
- On one side girl okay? - According.
Our mother, Loretta Jamison ...
She is dating an eligible, attractive and disheveled man.
Called Miguel Diego Torres.
He loves her.
We decided to give a boost to this union, to give them time.
They are going away.
A cruise on the Royal Caribbean.
The typical beach cruiser.
We visit our grandparents,
to which we have ever seen.
We do not know what their character or their tastes.
Si.
And we do not even know how they are.
They could ... you to like crafts.
You might think that boy bands are cute.
¿Tickets?
DOCG Masonville, Pennsylvania.
Our grandparents receive us.
Are You a prodigy of the cinema?
Do you know? I used to be a good actor.
Oh no, my camera is blinking.
Here I am, slandered, accused and perplexed.
Pierced my soul ...
the launch of infamy.
Unfortunately, I'll have to turn off the camera.
Since my father left us, my brother ...
It is always worrying with germs.
The psychologist who saw him for months,
He said it was his way of controlling things.
♪ Girl, I'm sorry again again
♪ I'm like Iron Man and Batman, a hero again
♪ think I'm under, but the other month, I grew a foot again
♪ I think very good for me, but it's really a joke
♪ Look, it does not bother me
♪ Because I'm not as sensitive as I look
♪ And finally end up with me, you'll be in my bed
♪ I will not be expendable
♪ With very spicy messages, you write
♪ A frappuchinno take on Starbucks
♪ And this philosophy based on science, you see
♪ Mr. Simm, my pediatrician, recently confirmed it for me
♪ notified, I'm entering puberty
How ♪ oh!
Strikes, Go.
Maybe I could rap in your documentary.
Sure, because that just winning documentary Oscars.
With misogynist songs.
Here our mother grew up.
When he left, he thought it went with the man of her dreams.
MASONVILLE, PENNSYLVANIA
MONDAY MORNING
- Hello. - Hello.
Becca right?
- According. - Hello.
Look around.
This is Mary Vela Jamison.
My, my grandmother.
It is a great cook and we have the same eyes.
And this is Frederick Jamison Spencer.
My, my grandfather.
He is a farmer now, but also makes voluntary work.
How do you like your new Tyler grandparents?
They are fine.
They not even know who the One Direction.
Have you made your grandmother those pretzels?
Yes it is.
Thank you.
Are we There Yet!
Tyler Look, Mom swing.
A camera, tell us what he told us mom.
I used to wait here on the swing, came to his friends.
This is the perfect film image to start the film.
Come!
Wait! Wait, do not touch it.
Let him move only natural.
We are entering the house where he grew mom.
Look! Look, this is the clock that told us.
Do you play any sport?
I do not like sports.
Before Yes.
And what do you do?
Why do you wear the pants down so?
Rapping.
It is a form of modern poetry.
Das un tema.
And he likes to improvise rhymes on the subject.
Su nombre artístico
es "T. Diamond Stylus"...
Come on, Grandma, tell whatever.
Can it be food? I like food.
Yes, of course!
How about...
pineapple upside down cake?
Sure, why not, right.
Good.
The I have, okay.
The girls ♪ happy to believe I'm so sweet
He ♪ Like a Hershey, the girl looked at me
♪ It's called Andy
♪ And some broads before the stop hallucinating
♪ There's something you have to understand about me
♪ I always rhyme without stopping because if
♪ And I was not surprised, confused, even I had fun
♪ When a rare Hawaiian girl said
♪ You remind me of a cake pineapple upside down
♪ Oh
It was awesome.
Mom's room.
It is not a big thing.
I ask the big bed.
No, that is not worth.
No, no, no, I took it first. I took first.
No, no, no.
How Rock-paper-scissors?
According.
Rock-paper-scissors.
Again.
Sleep well over there!
Children are good guys.
It will be a great week.
By the way, there is mold in the basement,
we do not want you getting sick right?
I do not have a bar.
Not even one.
Solo, still unpacking.
Do not! Do not look at the camera.
That's.
This is so nice.
Stop looking at the camera!
Unpack, as you would normally.
If I were not here, okay? I know, I know natural.
So naturally?
What an idiot you are!
These are the people in the life of the grandparents.
We must toast them a bit.
Not much, just a hint.
And where are they now?
Out in the henhouse.
How are you? Do not answer that, I do not care.
They will treat you well?
Have not you said something bad about me? No answer me!
This is like a divorce agreement.
We are one week every 15 years, and we have to be civilized.
Mom? We have already talked about this.
We made a decision.
You go, we're having great.
Yes, you should go. According?
So you will not be so grumpy when you return.
Here Jacques Cousteau wants ...
we go to buy swimsuits.
We set sail from the port in a few hours.
- Hi miguel. - Good Morning.
I do not believe it's going to do it!
The employee of a Wal-Mart,
you are traveling in the world's largest cruise ship.
I hate spoiled brats.
We will hate you!
We are looking for visual attention.
Things that enrich decision.
Things we do imagine, that lies beyond the frame.
Record only what happens to you, as a party involved.
And we discuss the staging morning.
So now, I'm like now co-director.
Secondary camera operator, is your official title.
This is the first camera, mom ...
found in the damaged container useful things.
It tries to be formal, as in the classical moments that are ...
Hello grandfather!
Grandfather!
What's in the shed, Becca?
According.
I decided to say names of female pop singers,
curse instead of saying, from now on.
Why?
I think that sounds better.
For example, if I stick a finger, I say ay Shakira!
Oh, you're weird!
Is everything alright?
Yes, we are very good grandfather.
He had not seen her grandmother so happy in years.
Becca, T. Diamond Stylus, we are old.
Here we go to bed at 21:30 p. M: Yes?
See you in the morning.
- ¿21:30 p. m.?
- Las 21:30 p. m.
- God! - The 9:30 p.m.
This will be fun!
No WiFi and half past nine.
I want my cookies, I was right about toast nuts.
Well, go have some.
Passed 21:30 pm I do not want to wake them.
Do not make noise, are greater, you would not hear anything.
It has long wanted to spend some time with Grandma.
Seriously, I feel like mourn.
Can you teach me all these cooking tips?
Are you aware that that was my intention?
Cursilonas hate movies, seem torturous.
That smells so good grandmother!
I think it looks good.
I decided to use the soundtrack favorite musical mom.
It's so pompous, it will be like his presence in the film.
The counterpoint, will be more dramatic.
It is an ironic soundtrack.
Look at me when you discuss, you're like Miss Porte, the Gymnastics.
Oh and ...
CONSCIOUS what good is this?
Ah, well.
It is a gift for the girls.
I can not sleep.
Grandma's cookies need.
I will turn my personal addiction,
in a positive cinematic moment.
Mom...
I will rebuild your steps when you running away ...
Room to steal cookies to the grandmother.
¿Tyler?
Tyler, wake up!
T. Diamond. The grandmother is sick.
TUESDAY MORNING
And that's the camera.
Then you can upload videos to the Internet.
I have 4 videos and rapping.
One of them has 347 views.
Both are very talented.
Do you know who Tyler the Creator?
No.
Well I, I sound a bit like him.
People say.
Ven Becca cariño, come.
Grandfather?
You need me?
Your grandmother is right.
Last night I had a little stomach flu.
A virus such that last 24 hrs.
I knew it would be something.
She is not well, Becca.
Sometimes it gets sick.
Yes of course.
¡Tyler!
The grandfather has said it may take us into town this afternoon ...
for us to record some sites you would mom.
¿Tyler?
You can play hide below.
There are lots and visual tension.
Mom's place for hide and seek.
You better hide, my ethnic confused friend.
One...
Of ...
Three ...
Four ...
And five!
Ready or not, here I come!
I see you, little fool!
I have to use a strategy.
It is faster, but I'm a lot smarter than him.
Here I go.
I just spent it.
¿Becca?
I'm coming for you Tyler. I'm coming for you!
¿Tyler?
I'll catch!
I'll catch Becca!
I'm making chicken pie.
What the hell was that?
Can I help you?
Hi, I'm Dr. Sam.
Working at the hospital where your grandparents volunteers collaborate.
You must be Becca.
Are you making a movie?
I used to be an actor in my time.
Life is just a passing shadow, a poor player that struts ...
- And consume your time ... - You wanted to talk to my grandparents?
Yes. Are they here?
No, they have gone out for a walk, I think. They just leave.
Okay, well, tell them to go to see them.
They were supposed to come from volunteers a few days ago.
I tried to call them, just wanted to make sure they are okay.
I think his work as volunteers stresses them a little,
but they will not admit it.
They are fine!
I am glad to hear.
Tell them there's a lot of excitement in the hospital.
I can not wait to tell, I know you love gossip.
I will tell you, nice to meet you.
24:15 Saturday.
Tyler Jamison, better known by the girls as T. Diamond Stylus.
Investigate there in the shed.
It is an isolated farmhouse, with people hanging.
Are there dead bodies?
There will be dead!
I go into the shed.
Here smells like ass.
I am approaching the suspect lots.
Oh, shit!
Oh, damn it!
¡Ay, Sarah McLachlan!
Tyler.
What the hell grandmother?
Your grandfather has incontinence.
Hides his "accidents" in the shed.
And then I think the field burning.
It is a virile man who is ashamed.
You must be disappointed with your grandparents!
I feel that ruined things!
Really we tried.
I'll make bread pudding.
We are fine?
Yes, if I'm right, Grandma.
Good.
My mom is a character in the classic narrative.
He says things like "things do not go well for me!"
And then makes pass.
You need the elixir or all of your relationships fail.
¿Becca?
Grandfather, we often play a game of pointing a building ...
and we must say who lives there, and what they do in secret.
Becca, with the commissioner.
A police officer named Jerry, works there.
But he never come to work, or answer the phone.
Because, what you really like to be is a dancer.
Okay, it's my turn.
That big brick building back there,
It is a factory of slippers.
And it works a woman named Sally.
That's the Maple Shed hospital, actually.
Yeah, Mom told us to work as volunteers.
Yes, every Tuesday and Thursday.
They are good people, but they have no one to care for them.
I'll find my pass Maple Shed and make them a visit.
SECUNDARIA MASONVILLE
Join us on a journey into the past Loretta Young Jamison.
This was the Secondary Loretta Young.
Loretta Young and her friends used to stay close to this sign ...
Now we'll go to the back.
At a glimpse, the room, the young rebel Loretta,
through a window.
Mom grandfather was a good student?
We have to go, such is watching us.
- We do not, no, grandfather watches. - Fuck, it has stopped.
- Grandfather? - Pretend you're not watching.
What are you doing? Grandfather for!
Hey, stop following me!
- No, no, stop. - Stop following me!
I'm not following man!
- Stop following me! - Grandfather!
- Grandfather? You get hurt. - I'll split the ...
- Quítateme me! - Hey!
- But what is your problem? - Tyler.
Grandpa does not know you.
Oh man!
I'm sick.
I'm fine, I ...
I'm sorry.
That was insane! It is as strong as a wrestler.
This increased.
Confused, do not panic!
Most people become paranoid and is a ...
field type, spends his days chopping wood.
Hey would you not talk about it?
What is that?
Okay, we believe that there is someone outside the door.
It's 10:47 p.m.
Becca opens the door.
No way.
Okay, you still recording this.
Come on, let's see what's out there.
No, something is wrong.
I'll open the door Becca.
- I'll open the door and Becca. - I do not think you should.
There I go, I will open the door.
Open it. Why do you keep talking about it?
¡Only ciérrala, only ciérrala!
Jesus Becca, I'm blind.
Wednesday morning
Grandfather?
I'll tell you the truth, I have been diagnosed with the disorder.
Apparently, many older people suffer.
Why vomits it?
Okay...
Sometimes he puts into his head that has eaten something.
And ... that is inside it.
And trying to get out.
It's called Evening syndrome, is a type of dementia.
It happens after dark.
Is it true?
It's like when someone talks in his sleep, so they explained to me at least.
Better you get as standard ...
not to leave your room later ...
21:30 pm What you Agree?
We agree?
Yeah, yeah, okay.
Sorry for this.
I guess you're not happy now.
Nothing happens grandfather, I'm fine, just we'll be here until Saturday.
You're going, you're going somewhere?
If, to take the train to the costume party.
Grandpa do I create that you're confusing?
Oh man!
Well, that old pair of confused proved your grandparents!
Okay, nothing happens.
- Do not worry. - Do not.
- All right. According? - Yeah, okay.
Nothing happens.
Cecil B. DeMille good morning.
He was a great director.
I've made cheese biscuits, honey.
Already he was preparing the old, to the costume party again?
Yes it is.
He's crazy.
I'm going to do something barn, slow one minute.
Step something with your computer.
I dropped some dough on top, try cleaning with a solvent.
I'm sorry.
It is rare during the day.
- And more rarita overnight. - I tell you, nothing happens.
Search the Internet for the definition Evening Syndrome.
Sure you do not understand almost nothing, is not language rapper.
It is a neurological reaction to the sun and moon.
It is literally a chemical reaction.
Evening syndrome describes the disorientation, agitation ...
or general deterioration of mental deterioration ...
own old age at dusk or dark.
It is very common among older people.
The old people are afraid for no reason.
And what about the computer?
Only computer crashed camera.
Here's something else.
The clean with a cleanser and now through the camera can not see anything.
Is not that a little weird?
Erred.
When you accept you are older, it will not seem so strange.
We are on deck, Miguel is a contest of hairy chests.
They are smearing oil.
It's strange not to see them.
I think I can clean.
Tyler, why are you so quiet?
Grandparents are a little strange.
How rare? ¿Becca, have rubbed off on Tyler?
No.
Guys?
Grandfather in diapers and stored in a shed.
And the grandmother wanders naked ...
and grandfather believes strangers haunt you.
I knew this would happen, Tyler age.
I have discussed it with him.
Older people sometimes have ...
problems with their bodies, sometimes.
They are not aware of what they do and become paranoid.
Becca what extent the look weird?
They have never been bad for a second.
The grandmother chased us crawling under the house.
We played hide and seek.
They played hide and seek under the house loved me!
- Oh Carrie Underwood. - Yes, can withstand a couple of more days.
My parents were rare in young people.
My mother was a hippie, used to take ...
the sun naked in the garden, without telling anyone.
I'm already half blind.
I cringed, are just weird people love.
What level would be the problem?
One.
You see.
I miss you guys!
I think it will start the contest hairy chests,
maduronas hear all applauding.
I have to go, I wish I could see their faces clearly.
Hello Darling.
Grandma can I ask you about Mom?
Do you think you could talk a minute, during an interview?
Would you care to get inside the oven to clean it?
¿Pe ... Sorry?
I am big, I do not get back.
The kitchen must be clean.
The oven is turned off.
Yes of course. Yes of course.
Slip deeper.
In all.
Okay, I'll be out in your film.
If you could be any animal what would you choose?
Is there a right answer?
No, these questions are for you to relax.
Un oso Grizzly.
I think you're ready.
Mom told me that you and Grandpa were very much in love.
Where did you meet Grandpa?
In a garden.
And what did you think of him?
He was very handsome.
It has a very strong personality.
This is great.
Then we go back to that.
Now I want to talk about something else.
I know it was long ago,
But what happened the day that Mom left?
She will not tell me.
Did you do anything?
Grandma? Grandma!
Grandma, do not answer that question.
No more questions about Loretta Jamison.
- Maybe I could ask you ... - I do not want to go out in your film!
Okay, Wednesday night, stay 3 nights.
T. Diamond Stylus, will discover exactly is going on.
What are you doing?
I'll leave the camera here tonight, okay?
It is as if we were living with the werewolf.
You can not record it.
A un lado.
Look, I know you do not understand because the brain ...
It has not been fully developed like.
- But you can not do this! - Why?
Because I have my film principles.
No, no one gives a shit about your film principles.
According? We're not in the 18th century.
Have you seen a Reality?
That housewives of Houston,
It has as millions of viewers.
If one of them does not participate in the scene, we can not burn!
It is unethical. With all due respect to whoever had the idea ...
Reality of the housewives of Houston.
You think you pretty cool right?
I hope things will not put more rare.
Because I'm on the edge.
Teaches the clock. I teach it.
This is what I was talking grandfather.
- The werewolf is real. - Wait!
It is Vespertino Syndrome.
We are participating in this. And it is not...
Reality no housewives on Houston.
Wait, if you want to open the door, open it, but only a moment.
- Is it normal to do that? - It's like when someone talks in his sleep.
You used to talk sleep up to 7 years.
Dad came to calm down.
Thursday morning
Hey Becca ...
Who I am?
¿T.? ¿T.?
¿T.?
There is a family of foxes, they're going to lose.
Now come on!
Just stop!
Does the grandmother is looking into the well?
Come, let's go.
I do not know.
The staging.
Do you know? You're not as dumb as they seem ...
reflect school performance test.
I forgot I had something for you.
When you think of Dad, now, in California, you still like him?
I do not know, they are things that happen.
But dad is hilarious.
It's fun, he sent us that funny card with that fat.
Do you remember that?
What do you mean by "these things happen"?
People are going ...
because they find something they like better.
And it does not make you feel bad?
No.
You're not being honest.
You can believe whatever you want, but that's what I feel.
Convince me!
I'm with the Titans, the children's football team, was third down.
It's almost the end and we are winning.
If they stop, probably we win the game.
Give me the context. How old were you?
I was 8 years.
According. I am the link above.
And that means I have to tackling the contrary ...
if he tries to pass the ball to people online.
So run, hits the ball.
Wait, what am I supposed to understand these terms?
Do these sentences are supposed to mean something to me?
You listen.
And run and is very large ...
and exceeds the line and I'm the only one who can taclearle.
Only I have to tackle him, I put my hands ...
and as I tackle him, but ...
I stood there.
I froze and listened to all screaming.
Dougherty coach, dad, my teammates.
He runs and runs with the ball.
And the other team already is celebrating and standing there.
At the same place.
He came the coach for me.
Dad patted me the man and went to the car.
And he said that he was angry or anything.
Do you think dad left us without saying anything ...
why not another player tacleaste 8 years ...
5 years ago?
Well, That sounds pretty stupid.
Why are we here?
She was looking at something.
So what have you found?
It's just water.
So just I read these in order?
If you could be any animal, what would you be?
- I feel like a moron Becca. - Shut!
It would be a dolphin.
It is an intuitive and intelligent creature.
That follows poetry and strength in their movements.
How can you like the pizza delivery?
With all that face full of acne?
Please answer the question.
He is friendly.
He has kind eyes.
Why did not you look in the mirror?
According what's all that?
Except when editing. Whenever you view yourself.
You never look in the mirror.
You comb your hair back to the mirror.
And I saw you when you brush your teeth.
Look down all the time.
You wear your sweater backwards you know that?
Is not that you have not looked in the mirror this morning?
I am right?
Not feeling well right?
Are you changing the focal length?
No, I do not even know what that is.
Do you do zoom?
No.
Will you admit that you do not look at yourself ...
Or will you keep lying?
When do you think I started doing it?
You know when.
That's not true idiot.
You think worthless.
Admit it.
He gave me a card when he left.
A card.
The videos that have small ...
I thought to use them in the film.
But I refuse to put pictures with my dad in them.
Mean forgive him.
Grandma?
Becca, this blind.
I know I'm right.
Something is happening here.
Perhaps there is something in the basement!
They do not want to go down there! I was being altered.
Speaks in English.
They could be hiding something down there.
They said mold, so do not want to go down.
And let it okay?
Let me just let the camera placed.
Hi, I'm Stacey Are Mr. and Mrs. Jamison?
No, just out, we are just my brother and me here.
Mr. and Mrs. Jamison were volunteers in midow Group.
I was in a rehabilitation program there.
They used to sit by my bed when I was wrong.
Sometimes all night.
Well, I have come to bring a cake of blackberries.
They had to stop by there on Saturday.
But they never appeared.
I know that Mrs. Jamison was not feeling well,
so I wanted to come to see how it was.
Have you heard all the gossip in Maple Shed?
I think not.
Stacey quiet, is natural, I'm shooting everyone.
Solo sé natural.
Well never mind.
Grandfather?
Now we're even.
I've been making music assembly.
But I need more shots of everyday life of the grandparents.
So I'll follow them Thursday afternoon.
Do you hear that? He is laughing watching TV.
Perhaps for the same programs as mother.
Grandma?
Grandma are you okay?
Good afternoon.
I heard that you laughed.
I have a dark attack.
Grandma! Grandma!
Grandma! Grandma! For! For Grandma!
What's wrong with Grandma?
You have to laugh, to lock up the darkness in a cave.
Grandfather?
Grandfather? I think Grandma ...
I was just cleaning.
What is that?
Did you want something?
I was just cleaning, seriously.
I think, I think the grandmother is not feeling well.
Thanks Becca, I'll go see it.
Tonight we put the camera.
How about?
- Well girls! - That's right, I'm bad, I'm bad.
It looks like this much better without us.
I LOVE! - We do so mom has its own life.
¡Tonto!
MIGUEL MOM + - Now we really perfect people.
Here we go, from the beginning. Here we go.
SEE YOU SOON!
Good evening!
All good?
We are fine.
¿Safe?
They're both a little strange.
We are great, really. Thanks for asking.
- According. - Good evening!
Good evening.
- What I am going to do? - What's up?
There were no tissues in the bathroom ...
I had to touch the toilet seat.
- And now I have something in my hand! - Here, let me ...
It does not look, but I can feel it.
- Tyler, Tyler. - It's disgusting, it is not removed.
- Do not remove. - Wait, let me look.
I can feel it. There are scarves Becca!
Tyler had handkerchiefs under the sink.
Where? Than?
- Peace man. - Too late, not be removed.
Rubbing can not be removed.
It's okay, okay.
- I still feel. - It is already going, look.
It is taking quite definitely.
- Safe? - It is done!
- You see? - Yes.
Next time look good right?
- It is done. - I did not know it was there.
¿Becca?
Stay in bed.
Friday morning
Mom comes home this afternoon.
We will leave here today.
Stay away from them. If I do not tell you.
Pack your bags.
You still have to give your mom elixir.
Becca what is the "elixir"?
Pretend we're playing.
Everything is alright?
We are playing.
Do you want me to do the interview?
Than? What are you doing?
We said no acercáramos Becca.
Are you going to do an interview with him?
Mom told me you worked in the coal industry long.
Work in a factory.
I know.
He worked nights.
He saw a white creature hanging around.
A white creature?
If, he haunted by the factory at night.
I just saw her.
I told the others, but no one believed me.
His yellow eyes.
Then they fired me.
And everyone stopped talking.
Mom had told me no.
She does not know, then he steps that was.
Grandfather, sad look.
Well, it's just ...
just because your trip soon.
I know that everything comes to an end.
Why do not you ask mom if you can come visit?
Are you still angry?
You can not overcome it, because they believe still angry with her.
The white creature that makes me the willies.
No doubt it is a principle of schizophrenia.
Both are very bad.
Brilliant!
Grandpa has schizophrenia and grandmother ...
Michael Myers becomes when the sun sets.
Es Stacey.
Why did not they come?
Okay, stop ...
Why you are angry?
We will be saying they need to get help.
I do not...
Come back.
I need to show you something.
Good.
I've already cleaned.
No he visto marcharse a Stacey.
And you?
Grandma says it's okay.
Thanks for making it, we'll soon grandmother.
Me da pena que se termine.
It is the last time I can ask you questions.
It's like the grand finale of my film and like you said, you're the star.
Tell me anything you want to tell.
I know a story about the water.
Brilliant!
There is a pond ...
with little creatures inside.
The creatures are from another planet, but no one notices.
These creatures spit in the water all day.
Their saliva let you sleep, but not kill.
When people are immersed in the pond ...
They fall into a deep sleep.
A truly beautiful dream.
Creatures from another planet have so many people in the pond bottom.
The stored.
They plan to take them one day to his planet called Synmorfitelia.
It's just a made-up story.
No es real.
Wow, that's an incredible story!
And the creatures have antennas, but are invisible antennae.
Can we talk to Mom?
You do not want to see her?
No.
Never.
The day he left, he had to do something ...
Okay, okay, let's pretend ...
we are telling a different story.
And history ... is a young ...
he believes in love with an older man.
And they decide to escape together.
The parents of the girl warned him that he will not run.
And do not consent to leave.
But then one day, they have a terrible fight and it is gone forever.
Parents do not know this story ...
But the sorely missed.
And he suffers ... much.
And then the worst happens.
The man breaks your heart and the girl is gone forever.
And leaving two small children.
And grandma, in this story,
What do you hope happens to the girl?
In the story is she so sad?
Sometimes this inconsolable, but try to be happy.
Takes medication and goes to therapy for 4 years,
but still a little sad.
I do not like this story.
Grandmother what do you think the parents of this ...
history should do, if they saw the girl again?
Grandmother, imagine that you are in this story and the girl was your daughter.
And he left.
What would you say when finally come back to see?
I would say...
I forgive you, little girl.
That is the elixir.
What are you doing?
This is how children play right?
Hey, Mom already be in the house, let's talk ...
for it in Skype, while they walk walking behind.
According.
It will be the outcome.
Hey guys did you see my videos? I know I look like an apple.
The trip was great.
Miguel and I fight this morning.
He wanted pancakes for breakfast and told him that I was gaining weight.
Can you believe it? Things never turn me.
- Mom? - Yes?
Mom, come looking for us right now.
Than? What happened?
Mom, get in the car and go now.
You know what it take to self Rebecca?
Mom, trust me, grandparents something strange happens.
I tell you, you must come to pick us up tonight.
Becca, you're scaring me, I have my heart in my throat.
We're fine, but come now.
Where are you now?
They are outside in the henhouse.
They can not see you.
- Becca? - They do strange things Mom, we've recorded.
Becca, yo...
Yes, I kept not tell something was Becca, right?
Becca, yo.
Grandma walks at night with a knife.
And the grandfather had a rifle in his mouth.
Tyler...
I think he wanted to kill himself.
Becca, Tyler, baby, I want you to listen carefully.
Becca, Tyler, solo escúchenme.
We listen.
These are not your grandparents.
What are you talking about Mom?
Where are the grandparents?
Have you been with these people all the time?
In Masonville Police Department.
¡Come on, come on!
What do guys?
Then we return cielitos.
This is the Police Department of Masonville County.
Our official Jerry came out, please leave a message ...
Police did not answer, damn it, everything falls.
Okay, I'll keep calling from the car, I promise.
You and your brother out of there.
Go to a neighbor's house.
- Just calm down. - I'm coming.
We are at home with ...
I have a fantastic idea for when we get to pick.
We must play a board game!
Families play board games.
It's our last night together.
Becca, can help me clean right?
You can record with your camera.
- According. - Yes.
We could go and record some shots of the house at night.
Okay, it sounds good sister.
Could you wipe the oven Becca?
Metete all in.
¿Becca?
And it has done before.
We should shoot something out.
Do this first.
I will be quick.
This will only take a second.
Grandma? Grandma?
- I clean those. - Grandmother, please open the door.
It's okay.
- Please open it! - It is done.
It was not for the fuss.
Let's make it ...
a perfect family night.
His grandfather is very competitive with the games.
I will warn you.
- Can we move that here. - We will use that table.
T. Diamond Stylus and I are going to record an interview last out ...
and return immediately.
We can sit there.
Think how will the teams.
- Come on, come on, hurry. - I take your coat, I'm coming.
Well, opens.
What is that?
And are the teams, young against old.
Stop throwing all dice at once.
We will lose the game because of you.
- No, it goes. - No need to count the points.
I am a teacher Yahtzee.
Did not everyone in the cafeteria called the "Master Yahtzee"?
What cafeteria?
If you want to win in the Yahtzee, listen to me.
You are no master of Yahtzee, that it would take 10 years.
You see! He is using a strategy,
approved by Milton Bradley himself.
I do not know what I do.
The game maker Hasbro's grandfather.
That's a lie.
Before the manufactured Milton Bradley.
Becca does matter!
Finally!
Me I'm having so much fun!
Me, I'm running out of battery, I now turn.
Keep playing with them T.
You keep playing.
I'll be right back.
¿Becca?
Katy Perry.
What time is grandma?
It's getting late.
¡Yahtzee!
¡Becca!
I'm going down to the basement.
I think my grandparents are here.
Grandfather?
Grandma? Are you down here?
The night is not going as I wanted.
They spend nine.
I have to take your grandmother to your room, you wait here.
Grandma?
Grandfather?
Hospital psiquiátrico de Maple Shed.
What if we just play the three?
My name is Becca Jamison, if you find this place ...
My name is Mitchell.
They kept telling us they were fantastic.
They were coming to visit. They would be a family.
That was a bad thing to do.
They knew that Claire threw their children into the pond suitcases.
He deserved to be a grandmother, at least this week.
Claire's children are in Synmorfitelia.
And you're going to meet them.
Help!
The only way to reach Synmorfitelia from here, by the well.
For!
It has not been a perfect week?
I promised it would be.
The white creature with yellow eyes is real.
We are waiting. I've seen on the field.
He laughed at us!
Tyler are murderers!
¡Becca!
Go away fool, run!
We're all going to die today ... Becca.
No.
To you, I think you've been bewitched.
Help!
Nunca me has simpatizado.
Claire.
Do you want me to tell a story?
I have to take the train to go to a costume party.
It is a company party.
Not today!
Already knew.
You have problems with germs, right?
¡No!
¡No, no!
They are blind! They are blind!
I see the truth, I'm a visionary.
I see the sad face ...
and deformed.
From this world.
We can save us all tonight.
Your magic spell can be broken.
¡Becca!
¿Has estado vigilándome?
¡Corre Tyler! ¡Corre!
Support running!
Block him! Block him!
Block him!
As Stop it! As Stop it!
¡Tyler!
¡No!
Are there any other hidden crazy idiot out there?
Come on out! Come on out!
Becca, come!
Children!
- Mom! - OMG!
I'm already here! I'm already here!
I'm already here.
Everybody is here?
I'm already here!
Come on, hurry.
The ambulance! Hurry, hurry, this way.
Mom, seriously, you know you do not have to.
I want to do this for you.
I liked to sing.
My mother said she was not listening.
But, I was behind the input clock.
With a kitchen towel, covering her mouth,
to hide his smile.
I thought he sang better than Olivia Newton John.
Olivia Newton John, era como su Elvis.
My father was a gentleman.
We used to walk together and just talked.
As a child, I woke up early,
working on a project.
My father believed he was destined for great things.
Well, it was before that day.
The day I left, it was horrible.
My parents insulted me.
I went to the door and my mother, I stood in front.
I hit my mother.
And then my dad hit me.
3 And we were paralyzed and then I left.
They tried to contact me soon after,
but never answer your calls.
I know that I forgive querías Becca.
But there was no need affection.
I was there when he wanted to.
Please.
Do not hold grudges never anyone Becc.
Do you hear me?
♪ Happy birthday to you!
- Puff Daddy! - Okay, okay.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY DAD
- Good! - Yes.
My brother insisted to include this part.
♪ If I have 13, I do not live in the neighborhood
♪ I not take razor and I'm not allowed Mobile dinner
♪ But I'm young and I can do 18 sit-ups, to be honest
♪ My sister tried to make a movie
About ♪ old, who were out of favor
♪ And do not turn out well
♪ She cried and vomited in the face received
♪ stew Her hair was full, but washed
♪ And it Herbal Essences shampoo washed
♪ And this learned T. Diamond visiting old
♪ adult diapers have many names
♪ sizes are small and large
♪ And all they are equal
♪ They meet all its functions, and keep everything under control right?
♪ Here the truth, causing a murderer, that was pretty crazy
♪ And I can not me!
♪ The pain over it, because one day I'll be famous
♪ As 50 Cent, I get a shot
♪ And I ate a diaper on his face, just over half an hour
♪ I thought I would end
♪ For I know that he was buried
♪ And someone passed over with the mower
♪ But that did not happen, I left me a little crazy
♪ Fui loco como Mel Gibson,
al final de Lethal Weapon
♪ I do not lie, now I'm sane for 3 weeks
♪ Because the diaper, I have been fatal
♪ I had to use two pads to clean my face
♪ And finally, I do not want to look bad
♪ But seriously, no shit tastes like chicken
♪ ¡Oh Shawna Tain, putas!
The Visit (2015) A translation of TaMaBin
Español neutro EuroGroup-sub