USRCS employees are advised to avoid
prolonged physical contact
with Bad Batch inmates.
This includes eye contact.
Bad Batch 5035 to 5040,
step into the room.
USRCS employees are advised to limit
eye contact with Bad Batch inmates
- to no longer than 10 seconds.
- All Bad Batch,
once you are tagged,
go to the left side of the room
and get your rations.
Single-file line, please.
USRCS employees are never to inquire
- details regarding fittings.
- Come on, folks.
Let's keep 'em moving.
Bad Batch Inmate 5040, Arlen Mae Johnson?
Take a seat right there, miss.
I need your right ear, please.
USRCS employees are reminded
to clearly differentiate
between personal view statements
and views, statements, positions made
on behalf of the agency or association.
Bad Batch 5039, you can move out.
USRCS employees are advised
to avoid prolonged physical contact
with Bad Batch inmates.
All right 5040, you can move out.
Step through.
Stand back from the gate.
You wanna radio it in?
It's hotter than the devil's a-hole out here.
Whoo! Get me back to that AC.
Help me! Help me!
No.
No. No!
Help, somebody!
Hey!
Help! I just want to go home!
Please, somebody!
Oh, my God! Please!
Huh? Goddamn.
Come on.
Be right there.
Okay, come on in.
Is it ready?
Tore her ass up.
Homegirl got fucked up!
Fuck, homes.
She stink, man.
Right.
I'm surprised she's alive, homes.
I can't find my fuckin' shoes.
Where are my shoes?
Hey, y'all seen my shoes?
It's all rusted out.
Doesn't even fuckin' work.
If you forget everything else but not this,
you have nothing to worry about.
It's the one thing...
Keep walkin', motherfucker. Keep walkin'.
There's one thing you must never forget.
Never forget.
Never, never, never,
never, never, never, never,
never, never forget this one thing.
If you remember everything else,
if you forget this one thing...
Whoo!
If you remember everything else
and you forget this one thing,
you will... you will have
done nothing in your life!
Nothing! Nothing!
This is the one thing, the one thing
you must never forget!
Give me some fucking noodles!
One dollar!
- Demon!
- One dollar!
She's a goddamn... she's a goddamn demon!
You no pay, no noodle!
No noodle for you, no pay!
Thank you very much. Huh?
- Hey, what's the thing?
- Shut up, motherfucker!
The thing?
The thing.
How should I know?
Find out for yourself.
You find out for yourself.
No one is gonna tell you.
You have to figure it out for yourself.
You have to figure it out.
Forget everything else but this one thing.
You have nothing to worry about.
Just one thing.
Must never forget.
All right, get up! Get up!
I can't do it again.
Please don't do this! Please!
Please! Please, I'm begging you!
Please don't do this!
I can't do this again! I can't do it!
Please don't do this! I can't do it again!
I can't do it. Please. Oh, God, please.
Please don't make me!
Please just let me go! Please!
I don't want any... please don't do this!
Please, please, please, I'm begging you!
I'm begging you! Please don't do this!
Oh, God! No, please! Please!
Please, I can't! No, no, no.
So sick of this shit.
Sick and tired of this shit.
There. Push, push.
Where do y'all come from?
You come from Comfort?
Look, I ain't got no problem.
No problem with you.
You're a Bridge person.
We're just out here
looking for plates, that's all.
That's right.
Looking for plates.
Honey, stay back.
Does your kid eat people, too?
I'm just trying to live out here,
same as you.
Ain't easy for me neither.
Look, we the same, we are.
No, we ain't.
We ain't the same.
We both Bad Batch, right?
We ain't the fuckin' same!
Do you hear me?
Please.
Just let us go.
Yeah, I did that.
Begged.
Pleaded.
Just like you're doing.
Tell me what you want.
I'll do it.
So, tell me what you want me to do
- and I'll do it.
- Shut up.
Just tell me what you want...
There's fuckin' nothing you can do.
You kind of stink, kid.
You want me to take your socks off?
My name's Arlen.
What's your name?
Look, no one cares about you now.
I could have just left you
out there in the desert.
Is that where you wanna be?
Hmm?
Now, you like this bunny, don't you?
Do you wanna keep him?
Then, you got to do exactly what I say.
That dead woman over there.
There was... a kid was with her.
Did you see this kid?
Did you see her?
You better start talking, old man.
What you want?
Keep it steady.
Nice straight line.
Let me see.
That's good.
A little bit more down here.
Yeah, baby.
Come on, baby! Do that move!
Move it down.
Dang, baby!
People of Comfort, good evening!
Give us The Dream!
Make some noise for the one and only!
The Dream!
Come on, Dream! Change my life!
He looked at me! He looked at me!
- We love you!
- I love you, too.
Heal my life with The Dream!
I've been wanting to dream all my life!
Come on now, Dream!
I love you, Dream!
I've got a question.
Why are we out here?
Just what are we doing in the middle
of the goddamn desert tonight?
Jimmy! Jimmy!
That's right. That's right.
You want that music only Jimmy can make.
Let me tell you something about Jimmy.
You know why Jimmy's here?
- Why?
- Jimmy!
- He's Bad Batch.
Yeah, yeah!
Bad Batch, fucker!
Nonfunctioning member of society.
That's what they told him.
That's right.
All of us here, we weren't good enough.
Smart enough.
- Yeah!
- Young enough.
- Healthy enough.
- You're right!
Wealthy enough.
Sane enough.
Freaks.
Parasites.
Bad Batch! Motherfucking Bad Batch!
This here is the Bad Batch.
Bad Batch, bitches!
We ain't good. We're bad.
Yeah, yeah, that's right, Bad Batch!
Yeah, Bad Batch.
That's right.
We're bad, baby!
Now, there's only one rule
here, and it's this.
It's time to wake up.
It's time to find... The Dream.
The Dream!
All glory to The Dream!
We're a Bad Batch, motherfuckers!
Bad Batch, motherfuckers!
Yeah!
Yee-haw!
- Yeah.
- What's wrong with that?
Is this your rabbit?
Where is she?
She was just right here?
That kid.
She was right here a second ago.
She's got to be here somewhere.
Where did that kid go?
I lost her.
That kid. I hope she's okay.
What did I do? She's got to be here.
I know she's got to be here.
She's got to be here somewhere.
What did I do? What did I do?
Where did that kid go?
Hey, you guys seen a little girl?
Hey, you seen a kid?
What am I gonna do now?
I hate this place.
What is this place?
This place.
Here's what you do.
Okay, here's what you do.
Go somewhere. Go far away.
You go far away.
Somewhere. Leave Comfort.
Leave Comfort.
Just go for a walk.
Somewhere. Anywhere.
Wow.
It's so big.
So big.
Wow.
It's so big.
Wow! It's so big.
It's pretty, so pretty.
Is that what it always looks like?
Doesn't always look like that.
Wow.
Thought it was pretty at first, but...
now, I'm not so sure.
I don't even really know what it is.
Do you?
You're big.
Strange, isn't it?
Here we are
in the darkest corner of this Earth,
and we're afraid of our own kind.
Hmm.
You know where you are?
You are a long way from Comfort.
And without this, you go nowhere.
Did you see a kid look like that?
Did you see her?
No.
I'm going to take you to Comfort,
and you will go inside
and find her for me.
Listen to me good.
I don't care about nothing or nobody
except that little girl.
And I'm going to kill you
if you don't find her for me.
Comprende?
Mm.
Vámonos!
I'm thirsty.
This make you more thirsty.
We got guns at the wall.
They'll shoot if they see you.
Mm.
So what?
That's your kid?
What if I can't find her?
You will find her.
Trade you for that leg.
I'm being friendly, dude.
I can just keep it all for myself.
It's up to you.
Wait!
No!
Mm!
Fuck.
Mm-hmm.
No.
No, no, no, no! No!
Let me go!
Aah!
Vámonos!
Would you turn around, please?
What's your deal?
How come you're in the Bad Batch?
Gang related?
Drug related?
Illegal.
No papers.
You a Mexican?
Cubano, from Havana.
I heard of Cuba.
That's in the tropics, right?
Near Hawaii?
Here is Cuba.
I am born here, in Havana.
I come with a boat to America when I'm 16.
To Miami.
Miami.
What did you do there?
Like, what did you do in Miami?
A lot of thing.
I make tattoos, construction.
I do this, that.
No big deal.
I got this one when I was 13.
And this.
See this one?
It's from the first boy I ever loved.
He was a musician.
We both got matching ones at the same time.
And this one, 5040.
What's your number?
Come on.
What's the big deal?
Just show me your number.
Your kind, you're evil.
That's what you are.
Evil.
You don't see things how they are.
You only see things how you are.
I don't care.
I hate you.
Get it?
I hate all of y'all.
No problema para mí.
It's okay.
Doesn't change nothing for me.
Doesn't change nothing for you.
Ohh.
Ohh!
Come on. Come with me.
Come on.
Let's go, man.
I'm getting the fuck out of here.
Come on. Hurry the fuck up.
Let's go now.
Open up.
Close it up.
- What's up, man?
- Hey, what's going on?
What's your number, fool?
5828.
Been out in the desert two days, man.
I need some food.
Are you guys gonna help me out or what?
What's up with the white girl, man?
Found her ass out there
with one of them Bridge people.
All right, kick back, homey.
- Thanks, man.
- Welcome to Comfort ese.
Yeah, welcome to Comfort.
Excuse me.
Have you seen this kid?
No.
You seen this kid?
Excuse me, sir.
Have you seen this kid anywhere?
Uh-uh.
No?
Can you look out for her, please?
Oh, he ain't ever gonna be wasted.
Hey, have you guys seen a little girl?
I ain't seen shit, man.
I wish they'd stop making pennies.
I hate pennies.
I hate 'em!
Hey!
- I keep losing things.
- Hey.
Don't wanna be a loser. I wanna be a finder.
Finder finds things. Loser loses them.
Yeah. I need to find a kid.
A little girl.
Yeah.
- She's about this tall.
- Yeah.
- You've seen her?
- Where?
- Hey, you wanna play with my puzzle?
You wanna play?
No, I'm not gonna play with your puzzle.
- Thank you.
- I'll call you later.
Yeah, baby!
Woo!
It's happening!
Yeah.
Yeah, baby.
Take a good look there.
That's the economy of Comfort
sitting right in front of you.
Right beautiful.
See, you can catch more flies with honey.
But who wants flies?
Remind me your name again,
Sweetheart.
It's Arlen.
Let me ask you a question, Arlen.
When you shit here in Comfort,
your shit goes away.
That accurate?
I guess.
You shit.
It leaves.
You know why it leaves?
Um...
because the toilet takes it someplace?
Yes, it does.
Takes it where it takes it...
because of me.
'Cause I hate the idea
that my sons and daughters
would have to stew in their own shit.
Cows stand in their shit.
They stand in their shit...
'cause they're cows.
Pigs stand in their shit...
'cause they're pigs.
Some misbehaving humans been making
hamburgers out of my sons and daughters.
We are not cows.
We don't stand in our shit.
Reason we don't...
is because I won't let that happen.
I got each and every toilet in Comfort
taking that shit from all your little asses
and sending it down the pipes
till it reaches a place
where no one thinks about it
and no one smells it.
Ain't that nice of me?
But you don't like it here,
do you?
No, I just...
Costs a lot to be here.
Cost you an arm and a leg.
Where would you rather be?
It's all right.
You know what I see when I look at you?
A sailboat out in the sea...
with no wind.
What is it you want, Arlen?
If you could have one thing,
anything,
what would it be?
- Anything?
- Anything at all.
A time machine.
Why?
So I could go back.
Fix things.
Make it better.
All the things you've done
have put you right here,
on this couch,
in this room, with me.
Close your eyes.
Close them.
What do you really want?
I wanna be the solution for something.
You know what this is?
It's a tomato.
First,
it was a seed.
You take care of a garden,
and it takes care of you back.
You feed it,
it feeds you.
Few things in this world operate like that,
fair and square.
It just needs a place to grow.
It grows and grows.
Then it comes out
and it's part of the world.
Because you know what The Dream really is?
It's life.
Life is The Dream.
The only dream.
I want The Dream.
What dream is that?
This one here.
Like they have.
Make up a room for our guest.
Is everything okay?
Hey. I'm sorry.
I guess I'm just a bit nervous.
That's okay.
Can you come in for a second?
Yeah, of course.
Is this really necessary?
Come here, kid.
We're going.
Bring her down!
You wanna see it all over your fucking walls?
Come here.
Promise me something.
Take care of this rabbit.
Come on.
Yeah.
When we're out and clear
of the wall, I'll let her go.
Come here.
Let's go, kid.
I'm real disappointed in you, Arlen.
Real disappointed.
Once we're out, I'll let her go.
I swear.
Yo, check this shit out right here, homes.
- Open it, Nacho.
- Open the gate, homes.
Open it!
Come on.
Bye, guerita.
Don't come back, you crazy bitch.
Get in the front.
Come on.
Miel.
You good? Okay?
Hey.
Wait.
What are you doing right now?
Do you wanna hang out or something?
You are very confused, no?
Not really.
What you think I am, gringa?
What if all these things that happened
to us happened to us so the next things
that gonna happen to us can happen to us?
You brought back my kid.
You done now.
You can go.
Go back to Comfort.
I'm not going back there.
In this place is only death for you.
Is like that.
Well, I like it here.
What do you like?
Where is here?
Look around.
Is nothing.
I want spaghetti because
the other man gave me spaghetti.
I want spaghetti.
I'm hungry. I want spaghetti!
I want spaghetti!