-
: Thank you
for making my Sonic your Sonic.
My name is McKayla.
How can I help you tonight?
I need a Footlong Cheese Coney
with mustard and onions,
large Tots
and a large Cherry Limeade.
:
We're on the road showing
real people the stain-fighting
power of OxiClean.
: Thank you, Lord, for
this and many other blessings.
Please keep a watchful eye
over Ally.
In Jesus' name. Amen.
: Do you
know how annoying that is?
Not to mention you could
blow out your eye that way.
-MAN: Where you from?
-BILL: Stillwater.
Who's the last drilling company
you worked for?
-ITA.
-Why'd you quit?
Operator dropped the rig.
We stacked.
I got laid off six months ago.
What are you doing now?
I work construction.
But it's been slow
since the rig's been down.
I've been doing cleanup
after that tornado by Shawnee.
Getting after it.
Hey, Sharon.
Let me finish this page.
One more page.
Thank you for this food and for
all that is good in this world.
Keep Allison
in your watchful eye.
-Amen.
You get hired out yet?
Had an interview this morning.
Got a call from your mother
a few days ago.
She moved to Tampa.
She ask for money or some shit?
No.
She asked about you.
You should call her sometime.
I got enough
I'm dealing with here.
Did you pick up
my car registration?
Yeah.
I got it at home.
Spent all morning
waiting for it.
Got it online.
Everything's online.
Can't get a real human being
if you try.
Didn't stop them
from charging me $23.
I'll pay it.
That's not what I meant.
I know.
SHARON:
There's a bag of things
by the front door
for you to take.
And an envelope of photos
in on her desk.
Those are important.
WOMAN:
Okay, you have two stopovers,
the first in Atlanta,
the second in Frankfurt.
-You're at gate 22.
-Thank you.
I just need
your signature please.
-You are with us for two weeks?
-Yes, ma'am.
Thanks.
Here's your key. Room 156.
Thank you, ma'am.
Welcome back, Mr. Baker.
Hey.
-
Oh, pardon.
Merci.
-
Hey. Hey.
Y'all mind keeping it down?
I'm trying to sleep.
-The music.
-Hein?
-
-No-no English.
-No speak English.
-
Yeah, all right.
Hey, good night.
-
-Bonjour.
-Baker.
:
Salim, neuf.
Moussa, dix.
Baker, onze.
Merci.
-Hey, baby girl.
- Hey, Dad.
You look good.
:
Thanks.
How was the flight?
Okay.
You doing all right?
-I'm okay, yeah.
-Good.
Good.
You got some laundry for me?
Yeah. Some.
I'll get it done.
They gave us
two more visiting days.
The next one's, uh, Friday,
2:00 p.m.
How's Gram?
She's good.
Still got the oxygen tank.
Still got plenty of opinions.
Miss her.
She bought you
everything you wanted.
Uh, we got you a extra pair
of socks
and, uh, good new pair
of sneakers.
Thanks.
Uh, Gram said that she was
giving you some photos for me.
Ah, shit. I forgot them.
Oh, just bring them next time.
No, I mean I forgot them
at home in Stillwater.
Sorry.
Doesn't matter.
I got you, uh, a Cowboys
sweatshirt at the airport.
They're gonna be good
this year.
They got this big ol' tight end
out of Guthrie.
Takes about three guys
to bring him down.
He gonna go pro for sure.
Cool.
You still working
at the library?
No, I quit.
Um, Dad, I need you
to do something.
I need you
to get that to Leparq,
make sure she reads it.
-Okay?
-Wh-What is it?
It's-it's a letter.
Just give it to her.
-Yeah, yeah. -The-the address
is on the envelope, okay?
Yeah, okay.
But are you good?
Dad, please.
I'll do it today.
I'll make sure she reads it.
Okay.
Mind if we pray a bit?
Yeah, sure, Dad.
Thank you, Lord,
for bringing us together
on this blessed day and
thank you for keeping
a watchful eye on Allison.
Mr. Baker.
I'm sorry you had to wait,
but Maître Leparq
is not coming back
to the office today.
I'll come back tomorrow, then.
Thank you, ma'am.
Mr. Baker,
she's in court all week.
Why don't you give me
your letter
and I will make sure
she gets it.
Can't do that.
Thank you, ma'am.
-As you wish.
-
-Bonjour.
-Hey.
You locked out?
Quoi?
Key. You got a key?
Ah, euh, non.
:
Come on, let's go get it.
Come on.
I'm gonna get you a new key.
GIRL:
Bell?
BILL:
Bill.
Beal?
Closer.
What's your name?
-Hmm?
-You.
Maya.
Maya. Ah, that's nice.
CÇ'est quoi?
It's a tattoo.
-Hmm?
Oh, it's a eagle.
-Eagle?
-Eagle.
Bald eagle. America.
Yeah, and I got a skull
with a knife going through it.
-Merci.
-BILL: Thank you, ma'am.
-MAN: Merci.
-Thank you.
-
Afternoon. I'm looking for, uh,
for that person, Maître Leparq.
Ms. Leparq?
-Mr. Baker?
-Yes, ma'am.
I just need a few minutes
of your time.
Letter from my daughter.
LEPARQ:
I'm sorry, Mr. Baker,
but I cannot honor
your daughter's request.
Why's that?
Mr. Baker, a judge
will not reopen this case
based on hearsay.
This is not possible.
Okay.
We have exhausted
every possible legal action.
This letter tells me
that your daughter
has not accepted her sentence.
And she must.
Do you understand?
Yes, ma'am.
I must go.
I have a full day.
Can I get that letter back?
As you wish.
-Thank you.
-Mr. Baker,
there's a time for hope and
there's a time for acceptance.
The last thing you want to give
your daughter is false hope.
That could make her situation
very dire.
Do you understand?
Yes, ma'am.
Hello.
Hey.
Uh, thank you for helping
my daughter Maya yesterday.
I was a little bit late
coming back.
It's, uh, you know,
we're between apartments,
and we don't have electricity
at our new place.
So...
Sorry, I...
I don't speak English.
Oh, yes.
The balcony. Yeah.
Um, well, my-my English
came back to me.
Uh, I'm-I'm sorry
for the loud noise.
It's because of
my girlfriend Nedjma.
She's a bad influence on me.
I'm, uh, Virginie.
I'm Bill.
Hello, Bill.
You're in Marseille
for vacation?
Uh, visiting my daughter.
It's cool.
Well, hopefully we're only here
for one or two more days,
but if you need anything,
you know, we're next door.
Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you. Bye, Bill.
VIRGINIE:
"Dear Maître Leparq,
"I'm writing to you
because I was contacted by
"Dr. Patrick Okonedo,
"uh, chief of
the outreach program
"I was involved in
at university.
"Patrick was approached
by a student
"who met a guy named Akim
at a party.
"She was told he had
stabbed a girl years ago
"and got away with it.
It must be the same Akim
who killed Lina."
You're the father of the girl,
the-the American student?
Yes, ma'am.
Um...
"H-His DNA must be compared
"to the unknown DNA
found on the crime scene.
"I, uh, I beg you
to investigate,
"to talk to Mr. Okonedo
and to the student.
"I am innocent of this crime,
"and I have no one else
to assist me.
"My grandmother can no longer
make the trips to Marseille,
"and you know my father.
"I cannot trust him with this.
"He's not capable.
"Please do not abandon me
in this horrible place.
"I have lost five years
of my life,
"and I still have four to go.
Sincerely, Allison Baker."
I'm sorry.
Appreciate your help.
Please don't say anything
to anybody about this.
Oui, bien sûr.
Mr. Baker. Please, this way.
So, how can I help you?
Well, I want to see Mrs. Leparq
about the case.
Maître Leparq
is not available today.
There's a new lead.
This guy...
was talking at a party
about the murder.
-Mr. Baker... -So somebody
needs to talk to this teacher,
this guy, Patrick Okonedo.
We need to hear
what he has to say.
Mr. Baker, Maître Leparq was
very clear with you yesterday.
She cannot pursue this case.
But if you wish to pursue
a further investigation,
we can recommend this.
It's a list of private
detectives you can engage.
No, I don't want,
I don't want a detective.
We have worked with
the people on this list,
and they're all very capable.
I don't care how capable
they are. I don't want...
-I'm circling the names that
you can... -Stop circling that.
-My daughter's in fucking jail.
-
I don't need some fucking list.
Euh, ça va?
Oui, oui, ça va, oui.
Merci.
As you want.
Fuck this.
Merci, Sybille.
-Hey. Mm.
-Hi.
-You good?
-Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
Let you out a bit late today.
They shouldn't do that.
You know they're gonna
call you back in on time.
It's okay.
It happens sometimes.
-I did your laundry.
-Thanks.
Um, did you give
my letter to Leparq?
Yeah, of course.
And what'd she say?
Well, uh, she told me
what you wrote about Akim
-and the girl at the party.
-And what'd she say?
Well, she said, you know,
she works on
a lot of these cases...
Dad.
Is she gonna
investigate it or not?
Just tell me.
Yeah, she's gonna look into it.
Really?
She said that?
She said
she's gonna look into it?
That's right.
I told her how strongly
you felt about it.
Does she need me
to do anything?
No. She said she just needs
some time, and, uh...
She did say, uh, she didn't
want to make any promises.
She-she didn't want
to give you any false hope
-or nothing like that.
-No, no, no, no, no.
But that's-that's still great.
Akim exists.
He killed Lina.
I know.
-I know that.
-
You have no idea how many times
I-I wrote and then rewrote
that letter.
:
Oh, my God.
Well, it worked.
:
Yeah.
Maybe God answered our prayers.
Thank you, Dad.
Thank you so much.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Bill Baker.
Called about a list.
One moment please.
BILL: I don't know
how much you remember
about the case, but
Allison came here for college,
and that's where
she met this girl, Lina.
Allison and Lina were...
together,
and one night
they got in a big fight,
and Allison went to a bar.
That's where she met
this Akim guy.
And they had some drinks.
He stole her purse, and...
when Allison got home,
she found Lina dead
and called the police.
And they never could find
this Akim.
He's the one who killed Lina.
What do you think?
Mm-hmm.
You speak English, right?
English?
Yes. I am.
:
Fuck.
Give me back the letter.
:
Mr. Baker.
Please.
My office.
I was in service
at the time of this case.
In the police.
Have you talked
to this Okonedo?
-The professor.
-No, sir.
I see why your lawyer
doesn't want to help.
Some kid at a party
hears gossip about a murder.
Maybe she remembers
this famous case.
Why now? It was five years ago.
That's... that's how long my
kid's been in jail, five years.
Does she know we are meeting?
Your kid.
No, sir.
Are you rich, Mr. Baker?
This is a DNA case.
It means two steps.
First, I look for
the young man.
That will not be easy.
People will talk.
He will try to disappear.
Then, if I find this Akim,
I have to get
a sample of his DNA
and use my connections
in the police to test it
against the DNA
from the crime scene.
How much?
$12,000?
Euros.
Thank you for your time.
Mr. Baker.
Do you believe
your daughter is innocent?
I know she is.
Then maybe it's not so much
to see her go free.
-Excuse me, ma'am.
-Yes?
-Ask you a question, please?
-Yes, of course.
I'm just too much of a dumbass
to figure this out on my own.
I don't speak French.
Uh, how can I help you?
I'm looking for a guy,
uh, who works here.
-Oui?
-Sorry to interrupt.
Do you speak English?
I do.
Looking for Patrick Okonedo.
-Have a seat please.
That's all right.
I'll wait outside.
No, no, please. Join the party.
It's impressive, huh?
It's the kind of office
a PhD will get you.
Mint tea.
I want to talk to the girl
you told Allison about
from the party.
Yes. I assumed as much.
To be honest, I've always felt
guilty about what happened.
I should've warned Allison.
Warned her? About what?
Well, I knew Allison and Lina
were sleeping together,
but I had no idea
Lina had moved in with her.
I try to not be cynical about
these type of relationships--
poor girl from the ghetto,
rich American student--
but then I end up
being guilty of naivete.
Allison grew up poor.
She isn't rich.
Educated.
There is a lot of resentments
towards the cultural elite.
But I'm sure
you're aware of that.
What about the girl
from the party?
-My student?
-Yeah.
Her name is Souad.
She's from
the outreach program,
the same one Lina and Allison
were involved with
when they met.
And she heard some guy
talking about Lina's murder?
This is what she told me.
Could I talk to her?
She'll talk to you, yes.
I'll give you her phone number.
Souad doesn't speak English
very well.
You will need someone
to translate.
Oh, could you do that for me?
No, I'd rather not.
I'm still running
the outreach program.
I cannot be associated with you.
Or your daughter,
after what happened.
Whatever my personal opinion
may be.
My daughter's innocent.
I wish you good luck.
-
BILL: Hey, Patricia,
afraid I need some help again.
I'm supposed to attend a
very special birthday tomorrow,
and I lost the address.
:
Bonjour?
BILL:
Hi. It's Bill Baker.
Pardon?
-Bill, from the hotel.
-Ah, Bill.
Yeah, I was stopping by.
Sorry to...
-Uh, last floor.
-All right.
Hi, Bill.
Hey, Maya.
I got something for you.
It's a robot.
-Hi.
-Hi. Sorry to intrude.
No, it's okay. Come in.
Um, I have some friends over.
Oh.
How did you find us?
Oh, the lady at reception
gave me your address
'cause there's this girl
I need to call,
but she don't speak English,
and it's kind of personal.
Ah, you want me to make the
call for you. Is that right?
Yes, ma'am, but I'll come back
another time.
No, it's fine.
Uh, just come in.
Just let me grab my phone.
Come.
-Hey.
VIRGINIE:
Bill, this is, uh,
the crème de la crme
of the Marseille theater scene.
VIRGINIE:
Ouais.
Uh, we're doing
this, uh, mask exercise.
-All right.
-Yeah.
Excuse the mess.
This is going to be my office,
but we're still moving in.
Have a seat.
So, who am I calling?
Um...
the girl from the letter.
-Ah, it's about the case?
-Yes, ma'am.
I want to meet with her.
Is the lawyer not helping you?
Uh, doing it myself for now.
Oh. Wow.
Okay. Um...
-Oui.
-Um...
What a great deal,
I got this place
through this friend of mine.
I fell in love with this view,
but, uh, has a few defects.
Probably just
a circuit breaker.
I could look at it if you want.
-Yeah. You know how to do that?
-Yes, ma'am.
Well, that would be great.
Souad? Souad?
Oui, bonjour. Souad?
Bonjour.
...Bill Baker.
Bill Baker...
Oh, non.
Let me see. Let me see.
Hey
-Cool.
Sexy lady...
-
I didn't know it did that.
That-that goes on easy.
Hold on. There you go.
Looks good.
VIRGINIE:
Merci beaucoup.
Au revoir.
Okay. She agrees to see you
tomorrow at 6:00.
All right.
Um, she was nice.
Bit shy.
So how are you gonna talk to
her if you don't speak French?
Well, that's a fair question.
I'll figure it out.
Okay.
Well, I could come
and translate if you need.
You sure?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, Maya has art class,
so if you come here at 5:30,
then we take my car.
Appreciate it.
Uh, you show me
where that fuse box is,
I'll work on
that breaker for you.
No, it's okay.
You don't have to do that.
Oh, non, non.
Just give me that damn thing.
I-- Come on.
MAYA:
Bill!
Bye, Bill!
Bye.
VIRGINIE: I have to confess,
uh, I went online and I read
about Allison's case.
It was a big story at the time.
I mean, the-the press
was ferocious, no?
Y-You say "f-ferocious"?
-Yes, ma'am, we say that.
-Yeah?
-Putain.
Dumbass.
Yeah, people--
they don't know how to drive
in this fucking town.
It's a crazy place, Marseille.
But I still prefer it to Paris.
You know, people actually
talk to each other here.
And plus, it's cheaper.
And why did Allison
come here for school?
I'm curious.
-Don't know.
-No?
Yeah, she was going
to Oklahoma State.
She just called me up
one day, said,
"I'm going to France," to here.
She's independent.
Yes, ma'am. Always been.
Are you close?
Well, you read her letter.
And where is her mother?
She passed.
Killed herself.
Allison was raised
by her grandmother mostly.
I wasn't around much.
Where were you?
Working oil rigs and...
being a fuckup when I wasn't.
It's not easy
being a single parent.
I often work at night, and
Maya, she gets really upset.
-What do you do?
-I'm an actress.
-Oh, on TV?
-No.
Theater.
Do you go to theater?
No, ma'am.
-Never?
-No, ma'am.
Okay.
BILL: Uh, thank y'all
for talking to me.
So, this guy that she met
at the party, Akim--
uh, anything she could
tell us about him?
She said he was quiet and nice.
Nice?
And then he told her friend
he'd stabbed a girl
and that the police
never caught him.
-So...
-BILL: Okay.
Does she know where he lives?
BILL:
-AÀ Kalliste.
-Kalliste?
VIRGINIE: She says he lives
in a different project.
It's called Kalliste.
-BILL: What's she saying?
-Nothing helpful.
I-I'm, uh... le père.
Uh, Allison.
That's my little girl.
Allison is my... ma fille.
You understand?
She doesn't want to help.
Can she tell me anything?
Wh-What does this guy
look like?
-Where they going?
-They're leaving.
Uh, no, no, no. Hold on,
hold on, hold on, hold on.
Wait, no, no. Hold on.
Just wait. No, no.
-All right, all right.
-Wouah, wouah, wouah! Wouah!
Souad. Hey, Souad! Souad!
Bill, Bill, let them go, okay?
She's afraid.
Afraid of what?
I'm talking to her.
Yeah, but that's not
how it works here.
Well, you tell me
how it works then,
'cause nobody here's
doing shit for me.
VIRGINIE:
I do shit for you, okay?
We should go. Now.
Okay?
-Yeah, all right.
-All right?
VIRGINIE:
That's it. Kalliste.
That's where she says
Akim lives.
Well, can we go look around?
No. Not at this time.
It's not safe for us.
'Cause we're white?
'Cause we're not from there.
And there's a lot of dealing.
Well, I got to do something.
No one will talk to you,
trust me.
Bill, what if there's no Akim?
There is.
Okay, but they never
found this person
during the investigation.
My daughter's not a liar.
No, I didn't say she was.
It's just that everything
I read about the case...
So you're some kind
of expert now?
No, I'm not.
The press was against us.
All they cared about was
Allison was sleeping
with some Arab girl.
Bunch of...
fake news scumbags.
That's why you punched
that English reporter?
I was drinking then.
ALLISON: Hey, did you
tell Gram about Leparq?
No.
No, I didn't want to get her
hopes up until we know more.
She's getting on,
your grandmother.
Oh, I had a meeting
with the judge yesterday.
Oh, yeah? About what?
Well, I have my parole review
coming up
in about three months.
And, uh, it's the thing
where I get out of here
one day a month.
Yeah, okay.
-So what'd he say?
-She. She said.
Uh, you know, as long as
my behavior remained good,
shouldn't be a problem.
I felt like saying,
"Fuck parole.
My lawyer's working on getting
me out of here for good."
No, we don't know that yet,
Ally.
-You got to keep...
-I know, I know, I know, Dad.
I-I didn't say that.
But I wanted to.
And... somebody from
Leparq's office was there.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. I never met her,
but I asked her
how the investigation was going.
What'd she tell you?
She said she didn't know
anything about it,
but she also said
she just started working there.
Leparq's probably
taking care of it herself.
It's a big case.
:
Yeah.
I told her I wanted
to talk to Leparq.
She should be
keeping us informed.
-You know what I mean?
-I'll talk to her.
Okay. Well...
I'll see you in a couple days.
Uh, Dad, do you think that
you could stay in Marseille
a little longer?
Just in case
something comes up.
Yeah, I could do that.
I'll check in on work
and stuff.
I-I can have Gram wire you
some money if you need.
No, no, don't do that.
I-I'll figure it out.
Thanks, Dad.
Bye.
Uh, Max.
Salut.
-D'accord.
-Ay.
Now, once the oil company
has a lease--
Give it here, M.
Come on.
Once that oil company
has that lease,
they hire a drilling company.
That's who I work for.
And then we get there,
we rig up
and we put
all that shit together.
Once we have that rig up,
we start making hole.
That's what a roughneck does.
We make hole.
All right, test it.
Go on, flush it.
Get it.
-Flush.
-Ah, flush.
-Yeah.
-D'accord.
-Flush.
-
-CÇa va?
-Hell yeah, ça va!
-
VIRGINIE:
Bill, come.
Come here.
Come and see this.
Nedjma is a technical genius.
I'm not a genius.
I'm just younger.
-Okay...
-These are online or some shit?
These are all from
Instagram accounts
of Souad and her bitchy friend.
And these photos
are all from the party.
How'd y'all get them?
I set up
a false Instagram account,
followed Souad and her lovely
friend whose name is Samira,
and then geotagged the party
Souad was at
when she saw this guy.
So there's a chance
Akim is in one of these photos.
VIRGINIE:
...Arab and light skin.
Yeah, uh, light skin,
yeah, and tall.
So we're going
to print them up,
and then you can show them
to Allison.
-No, I'm not gonna do that.
-Why?
If Akim is there, she'll know.
I don't care.
I'm not gonna do that.
I'm not gonna do it to her.
I got to protect her.
I don't understand.
Wh-why you're being
so stubborn about Allison?
What we should do
is go back to Souad
now we got those pictures.
Well, we stole these photos
from Instagram,
so I'm not sure
this is a good idea.
-Well...
-NEDJMA: Can I say something?
Ouais, vas-y.
Did anyone else in Marseille
see this Akim guy
or just Allison?
Bar owner.
Where they met.
He was at the trial.
-He didn't do shit, but...
-VIRGINIE: Okay.
Uh, what's it called, the bar?
What's the name?
I don't remember
the name of it.
-It was near her apartment.
-Yeah. Okay.
-Mm.
Okay.
Bill, did you vote for Trump?
No.
Ah. Voilà.
-I didn't vote.
-VIRGINIE: What?
-Why didn't you vote?
-Got a record.
I was arrested.
They don't let you vote
when that happens.
VIRGINIE:
It's there, around that corner.
Your friend, uh, Nedjma...
she mad at you for helping me?
Don't worry about Nedjma;
she's generally hostile.
You know, she's very protective
with me,
but she's a good friend.
She helps me with Maya.
BILL:
Where's Maya's father?
VIRGINIE: Corsica, running
a nightclub on the beach.
He was a... a fling.
-That's how you say?
-Fling, yeah.
Yeah.
Does he visit?
He used to, but it's better
when he doesn't.
What?
BILL:
That's where Allison lived.
Twenty-one.
That's where it happened?
Yeah.
-Bonjour.
He's the new owner.
He wasn't there
when the crime happened.
Does he know where we could
find the old owner?
Yes, I know.
He's right there.
Drinking my profits.
Euhm...
He recognize anybody?
BILL:
What's he saying?
Putain.
Okay. CÇ'est bon.Let's go.
What'd he say?
Nothing. He's useless.
Hey.
Hey!
Hey! What happened?
I'm sorry. I just, uh-- I can't
talk to that guy anymore.
He was just saying
some horrible things.
Like what?
Like he just wants to put
an Arab kid in jail, you know?
He doesn't care which one.
That's it?
What do you mean, "That's it"?
He's a racist.
Okay, he's a racist.
We still got to talk to him.
No. I don't talk to him, no.
Well, he might know something.
No, he doesn't know something!
Bill, we're not gonna send
an innocent boy to jail.
My daughter is innocent.
Quoi? Oh, putain.Can't believe
this conversation.
Well, then y-you live
in some fancy-ass world, honey,
'cause I work with guys
like that all the time.
No, but it doesn't matter, okay?
It's not right.
I'm not saying it's ri...
I'm trying to get
my little girl out of jail.
That's all I give a fuck about.
And you sound
very American right now.
Good. I am.
Yeah, and you're also
a stranger here.
You don't understand shit.
You know what?
Mr. Baker, one moment please.
You have a message.
:
She said you need more money
because Leparq
reopened the case?
BILL:
I'm dealing with it, Sharon.
-Dealing with what?
-Nothing.
I mean, Allison told me
to give her a letter.
I did, and now Leparq's
looking into it.
Well, i-is she looking
for Akim again?
I'm-I'm-- I told you
I'm dealing with it, Sharon.
-Who is gonna pay for this?
-Nobody's talking about money.
Okay?
Bill, have you been drinking?
No.
Listen, Sharon, I'm her father.
Oh, my God, Bill.
You're supposed to visit
and come home.
Don't mess with this.
Y-You're gonna need
to trust me on this.
That's it.
I'm gonna call Leparq.
No, don't do that, Sharon.
-Sharon!
-
Dad, what is going on?
I talked to Gram, she said that
you're acting really weird.
All right, I just need you
to trust me, all right?
I need you to look
at these pictures.
ALLISON:
Dad?
Dad...
are you drinking?
What? No, never.
Are you using?
Ally, I'm done with that shit.
You know that.
Now, come on,
look at these pictures.
Wh-What the fuck are these?!
Where's Leparq?!
-Wh-Why isn't she here?!
-Just look at the photos
and tell me if you see Akim!
I think he's in there.
Please, baby.
Please.
-No, I don't see him.
-Okay, all right. There's more.
There's more.
Holy shit.
You see him? Which one?
That's him.
That's him. That's Akim.
You're sure?
That's the guy from that night?
Daddy, that's him.
Kalliste?
Yeah. Uh, oui.In there.
Just drive on in.
Thank you.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Ma'am, you seen that guy before?
Akim?
-Non. Non.
-He lives, he lives here. No?
Ma'am, have you
seen him before? Akim?
Excuse me, sir.
-You seen that guy before?
-Non.
BILL: How about you?
Have you seen this guy before?
WOMAN:
Nan.
-Looking for him. Akim.
-No.
You know him? Akim?
Non.
Excuse me.
Y'all know this guy?
Him? Akim?
BILL:
You ever seen that guy?
Akim?
Non, non. Non, non, non.
-This guy?
-
No?
Hey. You know that guy?
-Right there? Akim?
-
You know him?
-This guy, Akim, he lives here?
-
Yeah.
How about... Akim?
-Non, non.
-
MAN:
Bye-bye, cowboy.
-
You speak English?
Hey, you know this guy?
This-- His name's Akim.
He li-- he lives here.
Akim?
-The guy lives here.
I-I speak English.
You suck my dick.
MAN:
Allez!
-Ici.
-Merci.
Hi.
They asked me
if I knew anybody.
Are you okay?
I saw him.
I saw Akim.
In Kalliste.
Did you tell the police?
That was my chance.
What the fuck did you do?
I was trying to help.
Tell me exactly
what you did, Dad.
Dad.
She wouldn't do it, Ally.
Leparq wouldn't
look into the case.
:
Oh, my God.
You fucking lied.
About all of it.
Of course you did.
I found him, Ally.
I found Akim.
And why didn't you
call the police?
Why?!
You let him get away!
-He's fucking gone now!
-
He's fucking gone!
I feel so stupid.
You've always lied to me,
my entire life, always!
I hate myself
for ever trusting you!
-Ally, listen to me.
-No!
No! No.
You are done
fucking up my life.
Do you get that?
Do you?
Stay the fuck away from me.
MAN:
Bill! Bill!
-Hey, guys.
-
Hé, Bill.
-Yeah, I got it.
the TV screen
just like a loaded gun
I'm six feet underground...
-Hé, Bill.
-How we doing?
How was school today? Good?
-You get it done?
-
All right, come on. Let's go.
-Yeah, I got it.
-Here. I got you that.
-
Maya, you got to eat
the whole thing.
I see what you're doing,
but you got to eat
the bread part, too.
Oh, you gonna
pawn it off on me?
All right.
Bill.
Uh... un marteau.
Oui. Très bien. Marteau.
-Hammer.
Uh... ciseau...
Uh... ciseausomething.
-Ciseau à bois.
That's a shitload of words
for "chisel."
-Chisel.
-Come on in. Get the light.
-Lumière.
-
Maya, supper.
Maya.
That bald guy's
gonna lose his shirt.
-Oh, non.
-
Yeah, that's how they do it.
Cut to commercial
before the big reveal.
Come on, let's eat.
-Come on.
-
You do your homework?
-Homework?
-Ah, non.
Well, appreciate the honesty.
Yeah, I used to
hate school, too.
Hated everything about it.
Dropped out of high school,
worked a rig like my daddy,
started making hole.
That what you gonna do?
You gonna make hole?
-Oui,I make hole.
-: No shit.
You got to start out a worm,
you know.
That's the lowest of the low.
A worm.
Non, pas unworm.
Je veux travailler
sur le derrick,like you.
You going right to the derrick?
You got to have the want-to.
You got the want-to?
Ben, oui.
Hey.
-Thank you, Lord, for this and
other blessings. -
-Please look after Ally.
-
Keep a close eye on her.
We ask this in Jesus' name.
Amen.
-Dig in.
-VIRGINIE: Bonsoir.
-Bonsoir, maman.
-Hey.
-BILL: Hey.
-There's a burger up there
if you want it. -Thanks. Ah.
For me?
Yes, ma'am.
-That's rent.
-Thank you.
Would you please
get me the ketchup?
MAYA:
Non.
-Mais oui.
-BILL: Thank you.
Bill, she has to do
her homework.
I know. Hundred percent.
Do your homework.
-Yeah?
-Mm.
Merci.
When I see what you guys eat, I
understand why you pray before.
-How was play practice?
-Rehearsal.
Uh, it was shit.
We do a lot of stage writing,
so it's messy,
and, uh, the-the director--
he's young and provincial.
What's stage writing?
We don't know what we're doing,
so we make it up instead.
Cool.
Cool Raoul.
Drops back,
scrambles to the middle.
Down inside the ten,
so the clock is running,
-clock is running.
BILL:
Back to bed.
I look with you?
No way.
Bed.
You're gonna get me in trouble.
My tablet.
Yeah, I'm using it.
Bed, now.
SPORTSCASTER: ...fourth
quarter. Well, why not?
-
Hello?
Yeah, this is him.
LEPARQ:
It's a one-day leave.
She goes out in the morning,
comes back to the prison
at night.
Then if it goes well,
she'll get another day
the following month.
The idea is for inmates
to acclimate
to the outside world again.
Understand?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
The judge requires a chaperone,
someone who is
going to vouch for her.
Did she ask for me?
No.
But you are the only option.
Okay.
A-Allison hasn't talked to me
for more than four months.
I am aware.
:
Mr. Baker,
do not take any initiative
this time.
Understand?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
Huh?
Color she love.
Oh, her favorite color?
Ah, oui,"favorite."
Yeah, not sure.
Hey, Maya?
No.
I thought it was pretty.
Bill! Bill!
Ah, soccer, no.
Allison likes Oklahoma State.
She likes real football.
This is football,
favorite foot.
No, these guys
are a bunch of babies.
Bunch of crybabies.
All right, all right, don't
get all wound up. How much?
Maman.
Euh, non.
Merci, Bill.
-All right.
-VIRGINIE: Merci, Bill.
-Oui.
-Bonjour, Maya.
Bonjour.
Hi. You must be Bill.
Yes, sir. Hi.
Good to meet you.
Uh, Virginie told me
you-you are from Oklahoma.
That's so cool.
Okay.
Renaud is
a rising star director.
That's me.
Oh, you're the one
who does the stage writing?
Yeah. You know about
stage writing?
Great.
Y-You know, man, I really love
working like this.
It's real, you know?
Stage writing? It's truth.
It's from life.
Virginie been telling me
about it, right?
Yeah. Merci, Bill.
Um, would you help me
move the table?
-'Cause dinner is...
-Yeah, I got it.
Merci, Bill.
RENAUD: Seriously, for me,
it makes total sense.
People should be able
to carry guns.
You know, but they got freedom.
It's basic freedom.
-I would love to have a gun.
-
I'm sure you have a gun.
-Don't you, Bill?
-Yes, sir, I do.
-Yes!
-No, you do not.
Why wouldn't I?
I got two of them.
I got a shotgun and a Glock.
-Oh, non, putain. C'est pas
vrai.-Two guns! It's perfect!
Non, non. Arrête, arrte.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's-it's his...
-His-his... his culture.
-: Culture.
Culture is
such a broad concept, huh?
I'm gonna call it
a night, y'all.
Come on, Bill. It's early.
-I'll put Maya to bed.
-Oh, I can do it.
-I got it.
-Okay.
You're my favorite.
Favorite what?
Favorite American.
Sweet dreams, little girl.
VIRGINIE: You know
it's Sunday morning, right?
BILL:
Where's your friend?
Oh, he left early this morning.
Mm.
We had a bit too much to drink.
Ain't no shit.
I was thinking, uh, I'd like
to bring Allison by the house.
Won't it be too much for her?
I'd like her to see
where I live.
If you're okay with it.
Why wouldn't I be?
Not everybody is.
-Hey.
This your van?
From work.
What work?
Construction.
I told you about it
in my letters.
You didn't get them?
I did.
I didn't read them.
-You want to get going?
-Yeah.
Merci.
Life is brutal.
Can I drive?
by brothers
ALLISON: I haven't heard
this song in a while.
BILL:
Special playlist for today.
How old is that thing?
It still works.
foggy feeling when I'm...
So you never went home?
Nope.
How come?
to keep believing
beats your hope in the ground
it's really coming down
I'm...
-
Are you sure we can park here?
What are they gonna do?
Arrest me?
O.M.
You really are a local now.
Maya sold me on it.
That's her favorite team.
Does this kid have a father?
He's not around.
Lives on a beach or some shit.
Groovy.
So is this woman
your girlfriend?
It's not like that.
I just live with them.
Like roommates.
What does she do?
She's sort of an actress.
Sort of an actress?
She a stripper?
No.
She just don't do
TV acting or anything.
She does theater.
Theater.
Have you seen her act?
What am I gonna do
in a fucking theater?
Yeah.
You know what's messed-up?
I never had a chance
to mourn her.
Lina.
It was so intense
when we first met.
She was so funny.
And cool and beautiful.
Then she moved in,
and everything got fucked-up.
She started sleeping
with other people.
Like it didn't matter.
Like she was just using me.
Or something.
:
And I felt so humiliated.
But, you know, the really
fucked-up thing is...
...I just want to see her.
I just want to be with her.
So much.
VIRGINIE:
Oui.
Ouais.
-
-Bonjour. -Bonjour.
-BILL: This is Allison.
Thanks, Dad.
I think she knew that.
:
I'm Virginie.
I'm Allison.
-Enchantée.
-Come. Come in.
-Merci.
Maya? Maya?
BILL:
Get out here.
Wait. Attends.
Ouais.
MAYA:
Oui.
Ouais.
:
Hey, y'all.
-Ah, watch out. It's hot.
It's hot. -Ow, that's...
-Yeah. Well, then take this.
-I got it.
I got it. I got it. I got it.
Let's pray.
Thank you, Lord, for this
and many other blessings.
Thank you for this special day
with Ally.
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
Maya?
Dig in.
-There you go.
-Merci.
Thank you.
So you two
really aren't having sex?
Allison Baker.
What?
You're so French now,
I-I thought it was okay
to talk about sex
at the dinner table.
Sorry.
Is it okay?
The food.
It's honestly
the best meal I've had
in a really long time.
Good.
And, no, we don't have sex.
Jesus.
VIRGINIE:
Oui.
So where did you
have lunch today?
-Pizza.
-Pizza?
-Chez Sauveur.
It's my favorite place. -Oh.
-It's so good.
And, uh, I'm curious, why did
you come to Marseille to study?
It was far away.
And completely different.
And the pizza.
-I like it, too.
BILL:
Uh, oh, no.
He's a fuckup.
Always has been.
It's more beautiful
on this side of the wall.
I like them.
Virginie and Maya.
It's good what you have.
I'm just trying to do it right.
I'm happy for you, Dad.
-WOMAN: Bonsoir.
-Bonsoir.
:
Hey.
How are you doing?
Pretty good.
Yeah?
The day was nice?
Flew by.
Merci.
Pourquoi?
Everything, I guess.
Oh. Bonne nuit.
Good night.
Hello?
Excuse me.
I'm Bill Baker, father of
Allison Baker, from Baumettes.
What happened to her?
What does that mean?
Fuck off me.
: I don't leave you,
you don't leave me.
I don't leave you,
Is she okay?
She's stable.
Hey, Bill.
BILL:
I talked to Sharon again,
told her you was back in here.
And work's been going good.
Uh... good group of guys.
16, 17,
18, 16...
Ah, Bill.
What, did I mess it up?
Oui,you messed it up.
"Love at first sight.
I was trapped by
how you looked at me."
Lumière.
Light.
Casquette.
Cap.
-Glasses.
Lunettes.
Merci,hand.
VIRGINIE:
Mathilde...
Ah. Merci.
VIRGINIE:
So, what did you think?
What'd I think?
Yeah. Of the play.
What did you think?
Oh, it was good, yeah.
Yeah? What was good?
Well...
I don't fucking know.
I don't know shit about plays.
-Plus, it's all in French.
-Oh, come on, Bill. One thing.
Uh, no one stands
like real people.
: What?
-It just looks weird.
Look, it's great, I'm sure.
I don't-- D-Don't-don't ask me.
-I'm a dumbass.
-No, you're not.
And, no, it's not great, no.
Ah, merci.
Cheers.
I will say, you were...
really good.
Best thing up there.
So, I got exciting news.
I got the part.
-On the TV show?
-Mm-hmm.
-Yeah, and I said I'd do it.
-No shit.
-That's great.
-Yeah.
But...
it's more money,
but it's also more hours,
so that means I'll have to pay
for a babysitter
and I'll be away more
from Maya.
Well, I could help
with Maya, too.
No, you help enough, you know?
You got a job. You're busy.
I don't care. I want to.
Why?
-Why?
-Mm.
I like spending time with her.
And with me, too?
Yeah.
And you, too.
How much do you enjoy it?
A lot.
I would say a lot.
This would be
a serious change for us.
Guess it would.
You guess?
Well, I mean, I know.
Oh.
And you know... what?
-Ah, for fuck's sake.
-
:
Do you have cash?
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, how much is it?
Sixty.
No shit?
-Hey.
-: Hey.
This is your music.
-Yeah.
I-It's a bit sad, no?
Maybe I...
-Ah, hell no.
-Huh?
-No, it's beautiful.
-Yeah?
Yeah, you can dance to it.
Really?
No, no, no. Come here.
-Come here.
I'll show you.
-You show me?
-Yeah, I'll show you.
by my side
This is Sammi Smith.
morning light
through the night...
Oh, we got eyes on us.
Ben...
Non.
Oui.
Viens.
BILL:
Hey.
-Ready for it?
-Mm-hmm.
out of sight...
-Hey.
-Huh?
-I need to ask you something.
-What?
Do you really own a gun?
-Oh.
-
-Two guns.
-Hey, Maya.
-MAYA: Hmm?
Want to hand me my casque?
My casque.My helmet.
My hard hat.
-Oh.
-Will you get it for me?
Yes, ma'am.
Ouais!
-
BILL:
Here we go.
Whoa!
BILL:
Oh.
-Wow.
-
Damn, the place is heating up.
-Quoi?
-A lot of fans.
Going nuts.
Someone should tell them
they're winning.
-All right, let's go.
Pardon, pardon, pardon.
Bill.
Oh, I think I see
a friend from work.
Want to see if it's him.
Okay, let's go get the van.
-MAYA: Is it your friend?
-No, that wasn't him.
-Hey.
-VIRGINIE: Hey.
-How's it going?
-Uh, good. Game just ended.
Be home soon.
-Okay, take your time.
-CÇ'est maman?
-It's your night.
-Okay.
Uh, see you in a bit.
Wouah!
Go back to sleep.
Go on.
We're going home.
CÇa va.
Nice to see you again.
You're late.
Oh.
Excusez-moi.
What can I do for you,
Mr. Baker?
That DNA test we talked about--
I want to get it done.
First I will need, uh,
the DNA sample.
Can I ask you how you got this?
Can you do it or not?
Yes, I can.
But I am an ex-cop,
so let me tell you,
it will be a serious mistake
to commit a crime
to prove your daughter innocent.
It will not get her out of jail.
And it will send you in.
-Do you understand?
-How fast can you do it?
It's hard to say.
A week at least,
but it will cost you.
BILL:
Here's 3,000 now.
I'll give you another 3,000
when you get it done,
but it's got to be quicker
than a week.
Even if it matches,
I still have to find this guy.
No, you don't.
You know where he is?
He could still disappear
before the results come back.
He won't.
Call me when you get it done.
Come on.
-
BILL:
Maya?
Hey, Maya?
-Hey.
-VIRGINIE: Hey.
-
-This is quite a greeting.
-You seen Maya?
-I was in the shower.
-Yeah.
She's playing soccer
in the courtyard.
I'm sorry I'm late.
-Oh, that's all right.
-It...
Don't you want to ask me
about my first day at work?
Uh, yeah, yeah. How'd it go?
-
-Bill?
-Hmm?
Who is the man in the cave?
In the cave?
With the tools.
I saw him.
Um, I'm gonna need your help.
Okay?
'Cause it's a secret.
You can't tell anyone.
Even your mom.
Okay?
He's a bad man.
He'll be gone soon.
It's gonna be our secret.
Okay?
That's my girl.
:
Shit.
ALLISON: I learned
something new actually.
It's helped me a lot.
It's something called
the "Mektub."
A nurse told me about it.
It's about acceptance.
Acceptance of what?
Your fate.
It's helping me
to stop struggling so much.
Stop questioning everything.
You just embrace your fate
and learn to live in peace
with it.
It's a Muslim idea.
It's about...
letting go of all of that...
...shame...
...and guilt
that pushes you down
and keeps you down
and makes you feel
so powerless.
And that's how I felt
for a really long time.
Powerless and forgotten.
And...
that makes living really hard.
You know what I mean?
But you're innocent.
So we got to keep fighting.
It doesn't matter
that I'm innocent, Dad.
It's not about justice.
It's about finding peace.
I don't know
what you're saying,
but you're wasting your breath.
We're gonna wait for that DNA,
and then we'll know.
She ask me. She pay me.
You want more water?
Allison, she say,
"Go. You put Lina out."
-That's enough, now.
-"Money for you."
That's enough, now.
She tell me take it.
She gave me collier.
"You take it.
-Money after."
-Here.
Drink that.
Go on.
Un collier.
"You take it for you."
Collier.Gold.
Like this. Like this.
The necklace?
I-I don't want that.
No!
She gave me.
She say,
"Go. You put Lina out.
Necklace now. Money after."
You're not even making sense.
Time to shut the fuck up.
S-Stillwater!
What'd you say?
The collier.
He say "Stillwater."
Gold.
She say...
"Do it. Make her go.
Make her go out."
Hey.
-Hey.
-Where were you?
I walked back from
the, uh, Baumettes.
We have to go and see Isabelle.
We'll be late
if we don't leave now.
Do, uh... do I have to go?
Yes, of course.
I told her you were coming.
Hurry up, please. Maya...
MAYA:
Oui, maman.
VIRGINIE:
So, Isabelle is
a sort of like godmother
for us.
Maya really loves her.
Well, you'll see.
This is really
the other side of Marseille.
MAYA:
Marraine!
ISABELLE:
Ah.
: I don't
know what you're talking about.
BILL: The gold necklace
I gave her the day she left.
Said "Stillwater" on it.
Yeah, I remember it.
What about it?
D-Do you remember, was
she wearing it at the trial?
Did she still have it on?
What are you getting into,
Bill?
Wh-When we went to get
her stuff, did you see it?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't remember. Why?
I'll talk to you later, Sharon.
Bye.
VIRGINIE:
CÇa va?
Yeah. Yeah, ça va.
Uh, talking to Sharon.
-Is she okay?
-Yeah, yeah, she's fine.
Are you?
What do you mean?
You just seem distrait.
I am. Sorry.
I'm happy you're here.
Me, too.
You, too?
Y-You're-you're happy
you're here?
-I am.
Really.
Me, too.
I like you, Bill Baker.
Okay, come.
-BILL: Mr. Dirosa,
it's Bill Baker.
Uh, really need that result.
Uh, it's kind of urgent.
DIROSA:
Bonjour, madame.
Bonjour.
Bonne journée.
Au revoir.
You know, I used to fight
a lot at school
when I was a kid, too.
But that's not good. Fight? No.
You sure you don't want this?
The man in the cave,
you will kill?
What? No.
Of course not.
I would never, ever do anything
to hurt you or your mother.
Never.
Because I love both of you.
So much.
I do.
You just have to trust me.
Okay?
Okay.
Mr. Baker, a word please.
Police.
Can I see your I.D. please?
Your I.D., Mr. Baker.
Thank you.
Take off your cap.
Okay. Thank you.
So, Mr. Baker, my colleagues
are gonna take
the little girl inside.
Okay?
-No, Bill. -Okay, all right,
all right, all right.
It's okay. It's all right.
-You go with her.
-No.
Tout va bien. Tout va bien.
It's all right.
You're all right.
CAPTAIN:
So, Mr. Baker, look at me.
Do you have a basement here?
Yes or no?
Yes, sir.
Okay. Give me the keys please.
CAPTAIN:
Please.
Stop.
Do you have the key?
Mr. Baker.
He's got it.
CAPTAIN:
Let's go upstairs.
DETECTIVE:
Sit.
Viens.
:
Vas-y, chérie.
Oui.
-Oui.
-Ah.
Oui.
Ah.
-Non?
-Non.
-Oui.
-Mm.
Okay.
Virginie, I didn't mean to...
How did you find him?
Pure chance.
The soccer game.
With Maya?
Did you ask her to lie?
Did you?
I never meant
to involve you or Maya.
-I know...
-You...
You have to leave now.
Okay. You pack your things,
you leave.
May I come in?
Maya?
You don't want to talk to me?
All right.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I love you.
VIRGINIE:
Bill.
MAYA:
Non.
Mr. Baker,
I've come with some
extraordinary news.
The judge in your daughter's
case called me this morning.
New evidence has surfaced.
Apparently, a retired cop
came up with a DNA match
on the unknown sample.
It also matched
a sample the police collected
on a burglary case
four years ago,
after the trial.
Did they catch him?
No, not yet.
But all we need to prove
is sufficient doubt.
So even if they can't
find the suspect,
there's a real chance
they will release Allison.
In fact, the judge
has already agreed
to reopen the investigation,
which is almost unheard of.
I think this could only happen
in Marseille.
Thank you for coming
to tell me, ma'am.
Mr. Baker, this is
the best possible outcome
for your family.
Do you understand?
I do.
Thank you, ma'am.
-MAN: Go, Pokes!
I told you we were gonna
bring our girl home,
and that's exactly what we did.
Welcome home, Allison.
Welcome back to Oklahoma.
Welcome back to America!
-
You're being antisocial?
You all right?
The day you left for Marseille,
Sharon and I drove you
to the airport, and...
when we got there,
I was embarrassed I didn't have
a present or nothing,
so I went to the gift shop.
I thought I'd get you a book
or a key chain or something.
Then I saw this necklace.
I thought it'd be like a little
piece of home to take with you.
It was gold.
Said "Stillwater" on it.
:
I didn't want it to happen.
He told me that
he would just help me
get her out of the apartment,
that's all.
I didn't want her to die.
I loved her.
I know you did.
You think I'm a monster?
You're my daughter.
I... I could never think that.
Dad, what is wrong with us?
I don't know, baby girl.
I don't know.
:
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Me, too.
from my hair
and let it fall
against your skin
on the wall...
Morning.
Hey.
Couldn't sleep.
Went for a walk, and...
ended up here.
I'm glad you did.
You miss them?
I do.
Can you go back?
No, I can't.
But it was good.
That don't change.
:
I'm sorry.
Life is brutal.
Everything looks the same here.
Nothing's changed.
Don't you think?
No, Ally, I don't.
It all looks different to me.
I don't hardly
recognize it anymore.